<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FreeXml>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Neujahr</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>You shall be careful therefore to do as the Lord your God has commanded you. You shall not turn aside to the right hand or to the left. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 5,32</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>By this my Father is glorified, that you bear much fruit and so prove to be my disciples. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 15,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Spirit of the Lord God is upon me, because the Lord has anointed me to bring good news to the poor; he has sent me to bind up the brokenhearted, to proclaim liberty to the captives, and the opening of the prison to those who are bound; to grant to those who mourn in Zion— to give them a beautiful headdress instead of ashes, the oil of gladness instead of mourning, the garment of praise instead of a faint spirit; that they may be called oaks of righteousness, the planting of the Lord, that he may be glorified. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 61,1.3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Come to me, all who labor and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 11,28</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Return, O my soul, to your rest; for the Lord has dealt bountifully with you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 116,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And my God will supply every need of yours according to his riches in glory in Christ Jesus. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>It was not because you were more in number than any other people that the Lord set his love on you and chose you, for you were the fewest of all peoples,  but it is because the Lord loves you and is keeping the oath that he swore to your fathers, that the Lord has brought you out with a mighty hand and redeemed you from the house of slavery, from the hand of Pharaoh king of Egypt. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 7,7-8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>God chose what is low and despised in the world, even things that are not, to bring to nothing things that are, so that no human being might boast in the presence of God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 1,28-29</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>On the day I called, you answered me; my strength of soul you increased.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 138,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And after you have suffered a little while, the God of all grace, who has called you to his eternal glory in Christ, will himself restore, confirm, strengthen, and establish you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 5,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Epiphanias (Erscheinungsfest)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Behold, the Lord God comes with might, and his arm rules for him; behold, his reward is with him, and his recompense before him. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 40,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>because of the tender mercy of our God, whereby the sunrise shall visit us from on high to give light to those who sit in darkness and in the shadow of death, to guide our feet into the way of peace.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,78-79</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>1. Sonntag nach Epiphanias</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>I will raise up for them a prophet like you from among their brothers. And I will put my words in his mouth, and he shall speak to them all that I command him. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 18,18</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Philip found Nathanael and said to him, “We have found him of whom Moses in the Law and also the prophets wrote, Jesus of Nazareth, the son of Joseph.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 1,45</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>When his breath departs, he returns to the earth; on that very day his plans perish. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 146,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And which of you by being anxious can add a single hour to his span of life? </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,27</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>From your lofty abode you water the mountains; the earth is satisfied with the fruit of your work. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 104,13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Yet he did not leave himself without witness, for he did good by giving you rains from heaven and fruitful seasons, satisfying your hearts with food and gladness.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 14,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You will say in that day: “I will give thanks to you, O Lord, for though you were angry with me, your anger turned away, that you might comfort me. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 12,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For God has not destined us for wrath, but to obtain salvation through our Lord Jesus Christ, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Surely he has borne our griefs and carried our sorrows; yet we esteemed him stricken, smitten by God, and afflicted. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 53,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For our sake he made him to be sin who knew no sin, so that in him we might become the righteousness of God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 5,21</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>He will swallow up death forever; and the Lord God will wipe away tears from all faces, and the reproach of his people he will take away from all the earth, for the Lord has spoken. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 25,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Rejoice in hope, be patient in tribulation, be constant in prayer. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For as the heavens are higher than the earth, so are my ways higher than your ways and my thoughts than your thoughts. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 55,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For now we see in a mirror dimly, but then face to face. Now I know in part; then I shall know fully, even as I have been fully known. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 13,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>2. Sonntag nach Epiphanias</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>The keeper of the prison paid no attention to anything that was in Joseph’s charge, because the Lord was with him. And whatever he did, the Lord made it succeed. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 39,23</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Not that we are sufficient in ourselves to claim anything as coming from us, but our sufficiency is from God, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 3,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Only fear the Lord and serve him faithfully with all your heart. For consider what great things he has done for you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 12,24</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And his mercy is for those who fear him from generation to generation. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,50</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“And you shall not covet your neighbor’s wife. And you shall not desire your neighbor’s house, his field, or his male servant, or his female servant, his ox, or his donkey, or anything that is your neighbor’s.’  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 5,21</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And he said to them, “Take care, and be on your guard against all covetousness, for one’s life does not consist in the abundance of his possessions.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 12,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“They shall be mine, says the Lord of hosts, in the day when I make up my treasured possession, and I will spare them as a man spares his son who serves him. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Malachi 3,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But to all who did receive him, who believed in his name, he gave the right to become children of God, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 1,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>the one who by his strength established the mountains, being girded with might; </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 65,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And he came and preached peace to you who were far off and peace to those who were near. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You, O Lord, will keep them; you will guard us from this generation forever.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 12,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>that you may be blameless and innocent, children of God without blemish in the midst of a crooked and twisted generation, among whom you shine as lights in the world, holding fast to the word of life, so that in the day of Christ I may be proud that I did not run in vain or labor in vain. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,15-16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And God said, “Let there be light,” and there was light. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 1,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For God, who said, “Let light shine out of darkness,” has shone in our hearts to give the light of the knowledge of the glory of God in the face of Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 4,6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Letzter Sonntag nach Epiphanias</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>I bow down toward your holy temple and give thanks to your name for your steadfast love and your faithfulness, for you have exalted above all things your name and your word. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 138,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>I made known to them your name, and I will continue to make it known, that the love with which you have loved me may be in them, and I in them.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 17,26</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Yet for your sake we are killed all the day long; we are regarded as sheep to be slaughtered. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 44,22</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“And to the angel of the church in Smyrna write: ‘The words of the first and the last, who died and came to life. “I know your tribulation and your poverty (but you are rich) and the slander of those who say that they are Jews and are not, but are a synagogue of Satan. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 2,8-9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And Samuel grew, and the Lord was with him and let none of his words fall to the ground. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 3,19</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For not only has the word of the Lord sounded forth from you in Macedonia and Achaia, but your faith in God has gone forth everywhere, so that we need not say anything. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 1,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Everyone utters lies to his neighbor; with flattering lips and a double heart they speak. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 12,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>At the same time, pray also for us, that God may open to us a door for the word, to declare the mystery of Christ, on account of which I am in prison— </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 4,3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Do not withhold good from those to whom it is due, when it is in your power to do it. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 3,27</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But if anyone has the world’s goods and sees his brother in need, yet closes his heart against him, how does God’s love abide in him? </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 3,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>you whom I took from the ends of the earth, and called from its farthest corners, saying to you, “You are my servant, I have chosen you and not cast you off”; </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 41,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For the gifts and the calling of God are irrevocable. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 11,29</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Surely goodness and mercy shall follow me all the days of my life, and I shall dwell in the house of the Lord forever. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 23,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Truly, truly, I say to you, whoever hears my word and believes him who sent me has eternal life. He does not come into judgment, but has passed from death to life. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 5,24</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Septuagesimae (70 Tage vor Ostern)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Wait for the Lord; be strong, and let your heart take courage; wait for the Lord! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 27,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Behold, we consider those blessed who remained steadfast. You have heard of the steadfastness of Job, and you have seen the purpose of the Lord, how the Lord is compassionate and merciful. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 5,11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And I will give them one heart, and a new spirit I will put within them. I will remove the heart of stone from their flesh and give them a heart of flesh, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 11,19</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Therefore, if anyone is in Christ, he is a new creation. The old has passed away; behold, the new has come. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 5,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>God shall bless us; let all the ends of the earth fear him!</Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 67,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>may have strength to comprehend with all the saints what is the breadth and length and height and depth, and to know the love of Christ that surpasses knowledge, that you may be filled with all the fullness of God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 3,18-19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-01-3100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Then Moses and the people of Israel sang this song to the Lord, saying, “I will sing to the Lord, for he has triumphed gloriously; the horse and his rider he has thrown into the sea. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 15,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>See what kind of love the Father has given to us, that we should be called children of God; and so we are. The reason why the world does not know us is that it did not know him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 3,1</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>They did not thirst when he led them through the deserts; he made water flow for them from the rock; he split the rock and the water gushed out. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 48,21</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>The Spirit and the Bride say, “Come.” And let the one who hears say, “Come.” And let the one who is thirsty come; let the one who desires take the water of life without price. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 22,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Will any teach God knowledge, seeing that he judges those who are on high? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Job 21,22</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Likewise, you who are younger, be subject to the elders. Clothe yourselves, all of you, with humility toward one another, for “God opposes the proud but gives grace to the humble.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 5,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>They feast on the abundance of your house, and you give them drink from the river of your delights. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 36,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Therefore do not throw away your confidence, which has a great reward. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 10,35</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Sexagesimae (60 Tage vor Ostern)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Comfort, comfort my people, says your God. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 40,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For the Son of Man came to seek and to save the lost.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 19,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>This Book of the Law shall not depart from your mouth, but you shall meditate on it day and night, so that you may be careful to do according to all that is written in it. For then you will make your way prosperous, and then you will have good success. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Joshua 1,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But he said, “Blessed rather are those who hear the word of God and keep it!” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 11,28</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Turn my eyes from looking at worthless things; and give me life in your ways. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 119,37</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Do not be led away by diverse and strange teachings, for it is good for the heart to be strengthened by grace, not by foods, which have not benefited those devoted to them. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And he was afraid and said, “How awesome is this place! This is none other than the house of God, and this is the gate of heaven.”  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 28,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And the Word became flesh and dwelt among us, and we have seen his glory, glory as of the only Son from the Father, full of grace and truth. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 1,14</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>They shall no more be a prey to the nations, nor shall the beasts of the land devour them. They shall dwell securely, and none shall make them afraid. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 34,28</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So then, there remains a Sabbath rest for the people of God,  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 4,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Salvation belongs to the Lord; your blessing be on your people!</Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 3,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>who saved us and called us to a holy calling, not because of our works but because of his own purpose and grace, which he gave us in Christ Jesus before the ages began, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 1,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>He makes peace in your borders; he fills you with the finest of the wheat. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 147,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And let the peace of Christ rule in your hearts, to which indeed you were called in one body. And be thankful. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 3,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Estomihi (Sei mir ein starker Fels! Psalm 31,3)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Ah, you who hide deep from the Lord your counsel, whose deeds are in the dark, and who say, “Who sees us? Who knows us?” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 29,15</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Then Pilate said to him, “So you are a king?” Jesus answered, “You say that I am a king. For this purpose I was born and for this purpose I have come into the world—to bear witness to the truth. Everyone who is of the truth listens to my voice.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 18,37</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>he makes his messengers winds, his ministers a flaming fire. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 104,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And suddenly there came from heaven a sound like a mighty rushing wind, and it filled the entire house where they were sitting. And divided tongues as of fire appeared to them and rested on each one of them. And they were all filled with the Holy Spirit and began to speak in other tongues as the Spirit gave them utterance. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 2,2-4</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The fear of the Lord is the beginning of knowledge; fools despise wisdom and instruction. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 1,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And so, from the day we heard, we have not ceased to pray for you, asking that you may be filled with the knowledge of his will in all spiritual wisdom and understanding, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>But this command I gave them: ‘Obey my voice, and I will be your God, and you shall be my people. And walk in all the way that I command you, that it may be well with you.’ </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 7,23</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So Jesus said to the Jews who had believed him, “If you abide in my word, you are truly my disciples, and you will know the truth, and the truth will set you free.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 8,31-32</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I know, my God, that you test the heart and have pleasure in uprightness. In the uprightness of my heart I have freely offered all these things, and now I have seen your people, who are present here, offering freely and joyously to you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 29,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Rather, speaking the truth in love, we are to grow up in every way into him who is the head, into Christ, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 4,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>and call upon me in the day of trouble; I will deliver you, and you shall glorify me.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 50,15</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Let us then with confidence draw near to the throne of grace, that we may receive mercy and find grace to help in time of need. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 4,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Awake, O harp and lyre! I will awake the dawn!  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 108,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Is anyone among you suffering? Let him pray. Is anyone cheerful? Let him sing praise. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 5,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Invokavit (Er ruft mich an, darum will ich ihn erhören. Psalm 91,15)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>On that day it shall be said to Jerusalem: “Fear not, O Zion; let not your hands grow weak. The Lord your God is in your midst, a mighty one who will save; he will rejoice over you with gladness; he will quiet you by his love; he will exult over you with loud singing. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Zephaniah 3,16-17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Therefore lift your drooping hands and strengthen your weak knees, and make straight paths for your feet, so that what is lame may not be put out of joint but rather be healed. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 12,12-13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And if it is evil in your eyes to serve the Lord, choose this day whom you will serve, whether the gods your fathers served in the region beyond the River, or the gods of the Amorites in whose land you dwell. But as for me and my house, we will serve the Lord.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Joshua 24,15</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>This is how one should regard us, as servants of Christ and stewards of the mysteries of God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 4,1</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>He has caused his wondrous works to be remembered; the Lord is gracious and merciful. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 111,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>The cup of blessing that we bless, is it not a participation in the blood of Christ? The bread that we break, is it not a participation in the body of Christ? </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 10,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For you shall not go out in haste, and you shall not go in flight, for the Lord will go before you, and the God of Israel will be your rear guard. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 52,12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Therefore we must pay much closer attention to what we have heard, lest we drift away from it.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 2,1</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>God is not man, that he should lie, or a son of man, that he should change his mind. Has he said, and will he not do it? Or has he spoken, and will he not fulfill it? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Numbers 23,19</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Jesus immediately reached out his hand and took hold of him, saying to him, “O you of little faith, why did you doubt?” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 14,31</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The angel of the Lord encamps around those who fear him, and delivers them. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 34,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“Blessed are those who mourn, for they shall be comforted. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,4</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>O Jerusalem, wash your heart from evil, that you may be saved. How long shall your wicked thoughts lodge within you? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 4,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Therefore put away all filthiness and rampant wickedness and receive with meekness the implanted word, which is able to save your souls. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 1,21</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Reminiszere (Gedenke, HERR, an deine Barmherzigkeit! Psalm 25,6)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Blessed are the people who know the festal shout, who walk, O Lord, in the light of your face, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 89,15</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“Blessed are those who are persecuted for righteousness’ sake, for theirs is the kingdom of heaven. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Both we and our fathers have sinned; we have committed iniquity; we have done wickedness. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 106,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>How precious to me are your thoughts, O God! How vast is the sum of them! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 139,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>for whenever our heart condemns us, God is greater than our heart, and he knows everything.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 3,20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-02-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And Samuel said to the people, “Do not be afraid; you have done all this evil. Yet do not turn aside from following the Lord, but serve the Lord with all your heart. And do not turn aside after empty things that cannot profit or deliver, for they are empty. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 12,20-21</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Therefore do not be foolish, but understand what the will of the Lord is. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Who is the man who fears the Lord? Him will he instruct in the way that he should choose. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 25,12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For to this you have been called, because Christ also suffered for you, leaving you an example, so that you might follow in his steps. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,21</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>he reveals deep and hidden things; he knows what is in the darkness, and the light dwells with him. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Daniel 2,22</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>I have come into the world as light, so that whoever believes in me may not remain in darkness. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 12,46</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And as he spoke to me, the Spirit entered into me and set me on my feet, and I heard him speaking to me. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 2,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>The woman said to him, “I know that Messiah is coming (he who is called Christ). When he comes, he will tell us all things.” Jesus said to her, “I who speak to you am he.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 4,25-26</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Okuli (Meine Augen sehen stets auf den HERRN. Psalm 25,15)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>For my father and my mother have forsaken me, but the Lord will take me in. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 27,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>We are afflicted in every way, but not crushed; perplexed, but not driven to despair; persecuted, but not forsaken; struck down, but not destroyed; </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 4,8-9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>All these things my hand has made, and so all these things came to be, declares the Lord. But this is the one to whom I will look: he who is humble and contrite in spirit and trembles at my word. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 66,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>When he saw the crowds, he had compassion for them, because they were harassed and helpless, like sheep without a shepherd. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 9,36</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Do not say, “I will repay evil”; wait for the Lord, and he will deliver you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 20,22</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>See that no one repays anyone evil for evil, but always seek to do good to one another and to everyone. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Behold, I will bring them from the north country and gather them from the farthest parts of the earth, among them the blind and the lame, the pregnant woman and she who is in labor, together; a great company, they shall return here. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Jesus said to them, “My food is to do the will of him who sent me and to accomplish his work. Do you not say, ‘There are yet four months, then comes the harvest’? Look, I tell you, lift up your eyes, and see that the fields are white for harvest. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 4,34-35</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>How precious is your steadfast love, O God! The children of mankind take refuge in the shadow of your wings. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 36,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Look at the birds of the air: they neither sow nor reap nor gather into barns, and yet your heavenly Father feeds them. Are you not of more value than they? </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,26</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>O Lord, do not your eyes look for truth? You have struck them down, but they felt no anguish; you have consumed them, but they refused to take correction. They have made their faces harder than rock; they have refused to repent. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 5,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>The apostles said to the Lord, “Increase our faith!” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 17,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>He was oppressed, and he was afflicted, yet he opened not his mouth; like a lamb that is led to the slaughter, and like a sheep that before its shearers is silent, so he opened not his mouth. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 53,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Truly, truly, I say to you, unless a grain of wheat falls into the earth and dies, it remains alone; but if it dies, it bears much fruit. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 12,24</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Lätare (Freuet euch mit Jerusalem! Jesaja 66,10)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Now therefore, O our God, listen to the prayer of your servant and to his pleas for mercy, and for your own sake, O Lord, make your face to shine upon your sanctuary, which is desolate. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Daniel 9,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“Fear not, little flock, for it is your Father’s good pleasure to give you the kingdom. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 12,32</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>He put a new song in my mouth, a song of praise to our God. Many will see and fear, and put their trust in the Lord. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 40,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“Truly, truly, I say to you, an hour is coming, and is now here, when the dead will hear the voice of the Son of God, and those who hear will live. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 5,25</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Better is a dinner of herbs where love is than a fattened ox and hatred with it. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 15,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>If I speak in the tongues of men and of angels, but have not love, I am a noisy gong or a clanging cymbal.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 13,1</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For still the vision awaits its appointed time; it hastens to the end—it will not lie. If it seems slow, wait for it; it will surely come; it will not delay. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Habbakuk 2,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>The Lord is not slow to fulfill his promise as some count slowness, but is patient toward you, not wishing that any should perish, but that all should reach repentance. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Peter 3,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>the fear of the Lord is clean, enduring forever; the rules of the Lord are true, and righteous altogether. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 19,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>If you keep my commandments, you will abide in my love, just as I have kept my Father’s commandments and abide in his love. These things I have spoken to you, that my joy may be in you, and that your joy may be full. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 15,10-11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For the Lord your God has blessed you in all the work of your hands. He knows your going through this great wilderness. These forty years the Lord your God has been with you. You have lacked nothing.”’ </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 2,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Again Jesus spoke to them, saying, “I am the light of the world. Whoever follows me will not walk in darkness, but will have the light of life.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 8,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>O Lord, you have brought up my soul from Sheol; you restored me to life from among those who go down to the pit. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 30,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>In the days of his flesh, Jesus offered up prayers and supplications, with loud cries and tears, to him who was able to save him from death, and he was heard because of his reverence. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 5,7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Judika (Gott, schaffe mir Recht! Psalm 43,1)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Let me hear what God the Lord will speak, for he will speak peace to his people, to his saints; but let them not turn back to folly. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 85,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For the law was given through Moses; grace and truth came through Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 1,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Are there any among the false gods of the nations that can bring rain? Or can the heavens give showers? Are you not he, O Lord our God? We set our hope on you, for you do all these things. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 14,22</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And this is the confidence that we have toward him, that if we ask anything according to his will he hears us. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 5,14</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Break forth together into singing, you waste places of Jerusalem, for the Lord has comforted his people; he has redeemed Jerusalem. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 52,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For by grace you have been saved through faith. And this is not your own doing; it is the gift of God, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>By the sweat of your face you shall eat bread, till you return to the ground, for out of it you were taken; for you are dust, and to dust you shall return.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 3,19</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For as in Adam all die, so also in Christ shall all be made alive. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 15,22</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord God has opened my ear, and I was not rebellious; I turned not backward. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 50,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>If anyone serves me, he must follow me; and where I am, there will my servant be also. If anyone serves me, the Father will honor him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 12,26</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>the fear of the Lord is clean, enduring forever; the rules of the Lord are true, and righteous altogether. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 19,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>It is the Spirit who gives life; the flesh is no help at all. The words that I have spoken to you are spirit and life. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 6,63</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For the eyes of the Lord run to and fro throughout the whole earth, to give strong support to those whose heart is blameless toward him. You have done foolishly in this, for from now on you will have wars.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 16,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And behold, a woman of the city, who was a sinner, when she learned that he was reclining at table in the Pharisee’s house, brought an alabaster flask of ointment, and standing behind him at his feet, weeping, she began to wet his feet with her tears and wiped them with the hair of her head and kissed his feet and anointed them with the ointment. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 7,37-38</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Palmsonntag</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Who can utter the mighty deeds of the Lord, or declare all his praise?  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 106,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>The next day the large crowd that had come to the feast heard that Jesus was coming to Jerusalem. So they took branches of palm trees and went out to meet him, crying out, “Hosanna! Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord, even the King of Israel!” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 12,12-13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Sing to the Lord, bless his name; tell of his salvation from day to day. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 96,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And when they had sung a hymn, they went out to the Mount of Olives. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Mark 14,26</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For great is his steadfast love toward us, and the faithfulness of the Lord endures forever. Praise the Lord! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 117,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>He who did not spare his own Son but gave him up for us all, how will he not also with him graciously give us all things? </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,32</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>In righteousness you shall be established; you shall be far from oppression, for you shall not fear; and from terror, for it shall not come near you.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 54,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Peace I leave with you; my peace I give to you. Not as the world gives do I give to you. Let not your hearts be troubled, neither let them be afraid. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 14,27</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Gründonnerstag</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Behold, all souls are mine; the soul of the father as well as the soul of the son is mine: the soul who sins shall die. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 18,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>In my Father’s house are many rooms. If it were not so, would I have told you that I go to prepare a place for you? </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 14,2</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Karfreitag</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Then Moses stretched out his hand over the sea, and the Lord drove the sea back by a strong east wind all night and made the sea dry land, and the waters were divided. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 14,21</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For I am sure that neither death nor life, nor angels nor rulers, nor things present nor things to come, nor powers,  nor height nor depth, nor anything else in all creation, will be able to separate us from the love of God in Christ Jesus our Lord.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,38-39</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-03-3100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Therefore the Lord waits to be gracious to you, and therefore he exalts himself to show mercy to you. For the Lord is a God of justice; blessed are all those who wait for him. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 30,18</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>He is not here, but has risen. Remember how he told you, while he was still in Galilee, that the Son of Man must be delivered into the hands of sinful men and be crucified and on the third day rise.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 24,6-7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Osterfest</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>And all these blessings shall come upon you and overtake you, if you obey the voice of the Lord your God. Blessed shall you be in the city, and blessed shall you be in the field. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 28,2-3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Remember Jesus Christ, risen from the dead, the offspring of David, as preached in my gospel, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Ostermontag</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Yet you are holy, enthroned on the praises of Israel. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 22,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But they urged him strongly, saying, “Stay with us, for it is toward evening and the day is now far spent.” So he went in to stay with them.</Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 24, 29</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>who say to a tree, ‘You are my father,’ and to a stone, ‘You gave me birth.’ For they have turned their back to me, and not their face. But in the time of their trouble they say, ‘Arise and save us!’ </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 2,27</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Or do you presume on the riches of his kindness and forbearance and patience, not knowing that God’s kindness is meant to lead you to repentance? </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 2,4</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>My soul clings to you; your right hand upholds me. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 63,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>We know that everyone who has been born of God does not keep on sinning, but he who was born of God protects him, and the evil one does not touch him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 5,18</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“Turn to me and be saved, all the ends of the earth! For I am God, and there is no other. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 45,22</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>He is the propitiation for our sins, and not for ours only but also for the sins of the whole world. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 2,2</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>A Song of Ascents. When the Lord restored the fortunes of Zion, we were like those who dream. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 126,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>[[Now when he rose early on the first day of the week, he appeared first to Mary Magdalene, from whom he had cast out seven demons. She went and told those who had been with him, as they mourned and wept. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Mark 16,9-10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>They cast their silver into the streets, and their gold is like an unclean thing. Their silver and gold are not able to deliver them in the day of the wrath of the Lord. They cannot satisfy their hunger or fill their stomachs with it. For it was the stumbling block of their iniquity. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 7,19</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Then he will answer them, saying, ‘Truly, I say to you, as you did not do it to one of the least of these, you did not do it to me.’ </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 25,45</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Quasimodogeniti (Wie die neugeborenen Kindlein. 1.Petrus 2,2)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>And God heard the voice of the boy, and the angel of God called to Hagar from heaven and said to her, “What troubles you, Hagar? Fear not, for God has heard the voice of the boy where he is.  Up! Lift up the boy, and hold him fast with your hand, for I will make him into a great nation.”  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 21,17-18</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So then it depends not on human will or exertion, but on God, who has mercy.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 9,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“The Lord is in the right, for I have rebelled against his word; but hear, all you peoples, and see my suffering; my young women and my young men have gone into captivity. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Lamentations 1,18</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Now may the God of peace who brought again from the dead our Lord Jesus, the great shepherd of the sheep, by the blood of the eternal covenant, equip you with everything good that you may do his will, working in us that which is pleasing in his sight, through Jesus Christ, to whom be glory forever and ever. Amen. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,20-21</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Be not far from me, for trouble is near, and there is none to help. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 22,11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And I am sure of this, that he who began a good work in you will bring it to completion at the day of Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 1,6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You rule the raging of the sea; when its waves rise, you still them. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 89,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>and from Jesus Christ the faithful witness, the firstborn of the dead, and the ruler of kings on earth. To him who loves us and has freed us from our sins by his blood </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 1,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For I know my transgressions, and my sin is ever before me. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 51,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>In him we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of our trespasses, according to the riches of his grace, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 1,7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>But if he says, ‘I have no pleasure in you,’ behold, here I am, let him do to me what seems good to him.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>2 Samuel 15,26</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>When they had finished breakfast, Jesus said to Simon Peter, “Simon, son of John, do you love me more than these?” He said to him, “Yes, Lord; you know that I love you.” He said to him, “Feed my lambs.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 21,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Who among you fears the Lord and obeys the voice of his servant? Let him who walks in darkness and has no light trust in the name of the Lord and rely on his God. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 50,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>He has delivered us from the domain of darkness and transferred us to the kingdom of his beloved Son, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Miserikordias Domini (Die Erde ist voll der Güte des HERRN. Psalm 33,5)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>My soul also is greatly troubled. But you, O Lord—how long? Turn, O Lord, deliver my life; save me for the sake of your steadfast love.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 6,3.4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Likewise the Spirit helps us in our weakness. For we do not know what to pray for as we ought, but the Spirit himself intercedes for us with groanings too deep for words. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,26</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For a man’s ways are before the eyes of the Lord, and he ponders all his paths. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 5,21</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>I am the good shepherd. I know my own and my own know me, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 10,14</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Is it not to share your bread with the hungry and bring the homeless poor into your house; when you see the naked, to cover him, and not to hide yourself from your own flesh? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 58,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>We love because he first loved us. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 4,19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Behold, children are a heritage from the Lord, the fruit of the womb a reward. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 127,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Then children were brought to him that he might lay his hands on them and pray. The disciples rebuked the people, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 19,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Like birds hovering, so the Lord of hosts will protect Jerusalem; he will protect and deliver it; he will spare and rescue it.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 31,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But God’s firm foundation stands, bearing this seal: “The Lord knows those who are his,” and, “Let everyone who names the name of the Lord depart from iniquity.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“But will God indeed dwell on the earth? Behold, heaven and the highest heaven cannot contain you; how much less this house that I have built! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers> 1 Kings 8,27</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>No one has ever seen God; if we love one another, God abides in us and his love is perfected in us. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 4,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The snares of death encompassed me; the pangs of Sheol laid hold on me; I suffered distress and anguish. Then I called on the name of the Lord: “O Lord, I pray, deliver my soul!” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 116,3.4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But he was in the stern, asleep on the cushion. And they woke him and said to him, “Teacher, do you not care that we are perishing?”  And he awoke and rebuked the wind and said to the sea, “Peace! Be still!” And the wind ceased, and there was a great calm. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Mark 4,38-39</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Jubilate (Jauchzet Gott, alle Lande! Psalm 66,1)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>lest like a lion they tear my soul apart, rending it in pieces, with none to deliver. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 7,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>I do not ask that you take them out of the world, but that you keep them from the evil one. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 17,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I see him, but not now; I behold him, but not near: a star shall come out of Jacob, and a scepter shall rise out of Israel; it shall crush the forehead of Moab and break down all the sons of Sheth. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Numbers 24,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>casting all your anxieties on him, because he cares for you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 5,7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Your righteousness is like the mountains of God; your judgments are like the great deep; man and beast you save, O Lord. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 36,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But God, being rich in mercy, because of the great love with which he loved us, even when we were dead in our trespasses, made us alive together with Christ—by grace you have been saved— </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,4-5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And he said, “Naked I came from my mother’s womb, and naked shall I return. The Lord gave, and the Lord has taken away; blessed be the name of the Lord.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Job 1,21</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And we know that for those who love God all things work together for good, for those who are called according to his purpose. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,28</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And Joseph’s master took him and put him into the prison, the place where the king’s prisoners were confined, and he was there in prison. But the Lord was with Joseph and showed him steadfast love and gave him favor in the sight of the keeper of the prison. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 39,20.21</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>The light shines in the darkness, and the darkness has not overcome it. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 1,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Bless the Lord, O my soul, and forget not all his benefits, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 103,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us in Christ with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 1,3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For this is the covenant that I will make with the house of Israel after those days, declares the Lord: I will put my law within them, and I will write it on their hearts. And I will be their God, and they shall be my people. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,33</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And you show that you are a letter from Christ delivered by us, written not with ink but with the Spirit of the living God, not on tablets of stone but on tablets of human hearts. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 3,3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Kantate (Singet dem HERRN ein neues Lied! Psalm 98,1)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>I am yours; save me, for I have sought your precepts. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 119,94</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>I have said these things to you, that in me you may have peace. In the world you will have tribulation. But take heart; I have overcome the world.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 16,33</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-04-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I spread out my hands all the day to a rebellious people, who walk in a way that is not good, following their own devices; </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 65,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>but God shows his love for us in that while we were still sinners, Christ died for us. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Behold my servant, whom I uphold, my chosen, in whom my soul delights; I have put my Spirit upon him; he will bring forth justice to the nations. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 42,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>O righteous Father, even though the world does not know you, I know you, and these know that you have sent me. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 17,25</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Yet now be strong, O Zerubbabel, declares the Lord. Be strong, O Joshua, son of Jehozadak, the high priest. Be strong, all you people of the land, declares the Lord. Work, for I am with you, declares the Lord of hosts, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Haggai 2,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So neither he who plants nor he who waters is anything, but only God who gives the growth. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 3,7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Oh, let the evil of the wicked come to an end, and may you establish the righteous— you who test the minds and hearts, O righteous God! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 7,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For the word of God is living and active, sharper than any two-edged sword, piercing to the division of soul and of spirit, of joints and of marrow, and discerning the thoughts and intentions of the heart. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 4,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>and rend your hearts and not your garments.” Return to the Lord your God, for he is gracious and merciful, slow to anger, and abounding in steadfast love; and he relents over disaster. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Joel 2,13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Be merciful, even as your Father is merciful. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 6,36</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord rewards every man for his righteousness and his faithfulness, for the Lord gave you into my hand today, and I would not put out my hand against the Lord’s anointed. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 26,23</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“Blessed are those who hunger and thirst for righteousness, for they shall be satisfied. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Rogate (Betet!)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>O Lord, by these things men live, and in all these is the life of my spirit. Oh restore me to health and make me live! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 38,16</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Then one of them, when he saw that he was healed, turned back, praising God with a loud voice; </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 17,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>My son, do not despise the Lord’s discipline or be weary of his reproof, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 3,11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Finally, brothers, rejoice. Aim for restoration, comfort one another, agree with one another, live in peace; and the God of love and peace will be with you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 13,11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>O Lord, you are my God; I will exalt you; I will praise your name, for you have done wonderful things, plans formed of old, faithful and sure. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 25,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Let us hold fast the confession of our hope without wavering, for he who promised is faithful. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 10,23</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For thus said the Lord God, the Holy One of Israel, “In returning and rest you shall be saved; in quietness and in trust shall be your strength.” But you were unwilling, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 30,15</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But the Lord answered her, “Martha, Martha, you are anxious and troubled about many things, but one thing is necessary. Mary has chosen the good portion, which will not be taken away from her.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 10,41-42</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Himmelfahrt des Herrn</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>And the Lord will guide you continually and satisfy your desire in scorched places and make your bones strong; and you shall be like a watered garden, like a spring of water, whose waters do not fail. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 58,11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“I will not leave you as orphans; I will come to you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 14,18</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“At the set time that I appoint I will judge with equity. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 75,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But you are a chosen race, a royal priesthood, a holy nation, a people for his own possession, that you may proclaim the excellencies of him who called you out of darkness into his marvelous light. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For I will satisfy the weary soul, and every languishing soul I will replenish.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,25</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And as he reclined at table in his house, many tax collectors and sinners were reclining with Jesus and his disciples, for there were many who followed him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Mark 2,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Exaudi (HERR, höre meine Stimme! Psalm 27,7)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>the Lord make his face to shine upon you and be gracious to you; </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Numbers 6,25</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>All the saints greet you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 13,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>He loves righteousness and justice; the earth is full of the steadfast love of the Lord. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 33,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But I say to you, Love your enemies and pray for those who persecute you, so that you may be sons of your Father who is in heaven. For he makes his sun rise on the evil and on the good, and sends rain on the just and on the unjust. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,44-45</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>A Psalm. Oh sing to the Lord a new song, for he has done marvelous things! His right hand and his holy arm have worked salvation for him. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 98,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>addressing one another in psalms and hymns and spiritual songs, singing and making melody to the Lord with your heart, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord is good to all, and his mercy is over all that he has made. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 145,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>that the creation itself will be set free from its bondage to corruption and obtain the freedom of the glory of the children of God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,21</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Let this be recorded for a generation to come, so that a people yet to be created may praise the Lord: </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 102,18</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But the tax collector, standing far off, would not even lift up his eyes to heaven, but beat his breast, saying, ‘God, be merciful to me, a sinner!’ I tell you, this man went down to his house justified, rather than the other. For everyone who exalts himself will be humbled, but the one who humbles himself will be exalted.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 18,13-14</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>So Moses returned to the Lord and said, “Alas, this people has sinned a great sin. They have made for themselves gods of gold. But now, if you will forgive their sin—but if not, please blot me out of your book that you have written.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 32,31.32</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And you see and hear that not only in Ephesus but in almost all of Asia this Paul has persuaded and turned away a great many people, saying that gods made with hands are not gods. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 19,26</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>He heals the brokenhearted and binds up their wounds. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 147,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>When the crowds learned it, they followed him, and he welcomed them and spoke to them of the kingdom of God and cured those who had need of healing. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 9,11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Pfingstfest</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Behold, the Lord’s hand is not shortened, that it cannot save, or his ear dull, that it cannot hear; but your iniquities have made a separation between you and your God, and your sins have hidden his face from you so that he does not hear. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 59,1-2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Nevertheless, I tell you the truth: it is to your advantage that I go away, for if I do not go away, the Helper will not come to you. But if I go, I will send him to you. And when he comes, he will convict the world concerning sin and righteousness and judgment: </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 16,7-8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Pfingstmontag</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Whoever oppresses a poor man insults his Maker, but he who is generous to the needy honors him. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 14,31</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Let your reasonableness be known to everyone. The Lord is at hand; </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord preserves the simple; when I was brought low, he saved me. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 116,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But he said to me, “My grace is sufficient for you, for my power is made perfect in weakness.” Therefore I will boast all the more gladly of my weaknesses, so that the power of Christ may rest upon me. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 12,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext/>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 16,32</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext/>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 14,19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext/>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 32,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext/>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 7,47</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For the Lord of hosts has a day against all that is proud and lofty, against all that is lifted up—and it shall be brought low; </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 2,12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Bear fruits in keeping with repentance. And do not begin to say to yourselves, ‘We have Abraham as our father.’ For I tell you, God is able from these stones to raise up children for Abraham. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 3,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Set a guard, O Lord, over my mouth; keep watch over the door of my lips! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 141,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For you were called to freedom, brothers. Only do not use your freedom as an opportunity for the flesh, but through love serve one another. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Galatians 5,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Trinitatis (Dreieinigkeit)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>“You who have escaped from the sword, go, do not stand still! Remember the Lord from far away, and let Jerusalem come into your mind: </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 51,50</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>praying at all times in the Spirit, with all prayer and supplication. To that end, keep alert with all perseverance, making supplication for all the saints, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 6,18</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“Turn back, and say to Hezekiah the leader of my people, Thus says the Lord, the God of David your father: I have heard your prayer; I have seen your tears. Behold, I will heal you. On the third day you shall go up to the house of the Lord, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>2 Kings 20,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>It was Mary who anointed the Lord with ointment and wiped his feet with her hair, whose brother Lazarus was ill. So the sisters sent to him, saying, “Lord, he whom you love is ill.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 11,2-3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>At the command of the Lord the people of Israel set out, and at the command of the Lord they camped. As long as the cloud rested over the tabernacle, they remained in camp. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Numbers 9,18</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And Simon answered, “Master, we toiled all night and took nothing! But at your word I will let down the nets.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 5,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Bless the Lord, all his works, in all places of his dominion. Bless the Lord, O my soul! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 103,22</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And do not get drunk with wine, for that is debauchery, but be filled with the Spirit, addressing one another in psalms and hymns and spiritual songs, singing and making melody to the Lord with your heart, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,18-19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-05-3100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Surely the righteous shall give thanks to your name; the upright shall dwell in your presence. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 140,13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And he lifted up his eyes on his disciples, and said: “Blessed are you who are poor, for yours is the kingdom of God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 6,20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>My soul is in the midst of lions; I lie down amid fiery beasts— the children of man, whose teeth are spears and arrows, whose tongues are sharp swords. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 57,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And we have seen and testify that the Father has sent his Son to be the Savior of the world. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 4,14</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Lead me in your truth and teach me, for you are the God of my salvation; for you I wait all the day long. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 25,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But if we hope for what we do not see, we wait for it with patience. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,25</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>1. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Light dawns in the darkness for the upright; he is gracious, merciful, and righteous. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 112,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>giving thanks to the Father, who has qualified you to share in the inheritance of the saints in light. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“Because he holds fast to me in love, I will deliver him; I will protect him, because he knows my name. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 91,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>As the Father has loved me, so have I loved you. Abide in my love. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 15,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And the people came to Moses and said, “We have sinned, for we have spoken against the Lord and against you. Pray to the Lord, that he take away the serpents from us.” So Moses prayed for the people. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Numbers 21,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So if the Son sets you free, you will be free indeed.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 8,36</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>God, the Lord, is my strength; he makes my feet like the deer’s; he makes me tread on my high places. To the choirmaster: with stringed instruments. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Habbakuk 3,19</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But he said to me, “My grace is sufficient for you, for my power is made perfect in weakness.” Therefore I will boast all the more gladly of my weaknesses, so that the power of Christ may rest upon me. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 12,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>As for you, you meant evil against me, but God meant it for good, to bring it about that many people should be kept alive, as they are today. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 50,20</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For judgment is without mercy to one who has shown no mercy. Mercy triumphs over judgment. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 2,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The nations shall see your righteousness, and all the kings your glory, and you shall be called by a new name that the mouth of the Lord will give. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 62,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>To him the gatekeeper opens. The sheep hear his voice, and he calls his own sheep by name and leads them out.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 10,3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“And you, Solomon my son, know the God of your father and serve him with a whole heart and with a willing mind, for the Lord searches all hearts and understands every plan and thought. If you seek him, he will be found by you, but if you forsake him, he will cast you off forever. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 28,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Nathanael said to him, “How do you know me?” Jesus answered him, “Before Philip called you, when you were under the fig tree, I saw you.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 1,48</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>2. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Let us lift up our hearts and hands to God in heaven: </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Lamentations 3,41</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Continue steadfastly in prayer, being watchful in it with thanksgiving. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 4,2</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord is near to all who call on him, to all who call on him in truth. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 145,18</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And whatever you ask in prayer, you will receive, if you have faith.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 21,22</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Why should you be like a man confused, like a mighty warrior who cannot save? Yet you, O Lord, are in the midst of us, and we are called by your name; do not leave us.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 14,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>for in Christ Jesus you are all sons of God, through faith. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Galatians 3,26</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>He will cover you with his pinions, and under his wings you will find refuge; his faithfulness is a shield and buckler. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 91,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>What then shall we say to these things? If God is for us, who can be against us? </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,31</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>that your way may be known on earth, your saving power among all nations. Let the peoples praise you, O God; let all the peoples praise you! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 67,2-3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>making known to us the mystery of his will, according to his purpose, which he set forth in Christ as a plan for the fullness of time, to unite all things in him, things in heaven and things on earth. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 1,9-10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>But he was pierced for our transgressions; he was crushed for our iniquities; upon him was the chastisement that brought us peace, and with his wounds we are healed. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 53,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>In this is love, not that we have loved God but that he loved us and sent his Son to be the propitiation for our sins. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 4,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Behold, it was for my welfare that I had great bitterness; but in love you have delivered my life from the pit of destruction, for you have cast all my sins behind your back. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 38,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Now may our Lord Jesus Christ himself, and God our Father, who loved us and gave us eternal comfort and good hope through grace, comfort your hearts and establish them in every good work and word. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 2,16-17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>3. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>according to the covenant that I made with you when you came out of Egypt. My Spirit remains in your midst. Fear not. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Haggai 2,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>and hope does not put us to shame, because God’s love has been poured into our hearts through the Holy Spirit who has been given to us. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I will rejoice in doing them good, and I will plant them in this land in faithfulness, with all my heart and all my soul. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 32,41</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>I am the door. If anyone enters by me, he will be saved and will go in and out and find pasture. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 10,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>withholds his hand from iniquity, takes no interest or profit, obeys my rules, and walks in my statutes; he shall not die for his father’s iniquity; he shall surely live. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 18,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>knowing that you were ransomed from the futile ways inherited from your forefathers, not with perishable things such as silver or gold, but with the precious blood of Christ, like that of a lamb without blemish or spot. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 1,18-19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord will open to you his good treasury, the heavens, to give the rain to your land in its season and to bless all the work of your hands. And you shall lend to many nations, but you shall not borrow. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 28,12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For from his fullness we have all received, grace upon grace. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 1,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>O Lord of hosts, blessed is the one who trusts in you!</Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 84,12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>In hope he believed against hope, that he should become the father of many nations, as he had been told, “So shall your offspring be.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 4,18</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Be silent, all flesh, before the Lord, for he has roused himself from his holy dwelling.</Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Zechariah 2,13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>In this the love of God was made manifest among us, that God sent his only Son into the world, so that we might live through him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 4,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For the Lord will not forsake his people, for his great name’s sake, because it has pleased the Lord to make you a people for himself. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 12,22</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For you know the grace of our Lord Jesus Christ, that though he was rich, yet for your sake he became poor, so that you by his poverty might become rich. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 8,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>4. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Daniel answered and said: “Blessed be the name of God forever and ever, to whom belong wisdom and might. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Daniel 2,20</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>John answered, “A person cannot receive even one thing unless it is given him from heaven. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 3,27</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Do not spurn us, for your name’s sake; do not dishonor your glorious throne; remember and do not break your covenant with us. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 14,21</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>To this end we always pray for you, that our God may make you worthy of his calling and may fulfill every resolve for good and every work of faith by his power, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 1,11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Not to us, O Lord, not to us, but to your name give glory, for the sake of your steadfast love and your faithfulness! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 115,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Pray then like this: “Our Father in heaven, hallowed be your name. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“You shall not bear false witness against your neighbor. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 20,16</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Brothers, if anyone is caught in any transgression, you who are spiritual should restore him in a spirit of gentleness. Keep watch on yourself, lest you too be tempted. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Galatians 6,1</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>let the wicked forsake his way, and the unrighteous man his thoughts; let him return to the Lord, that he may have compassion on him, and to our God, for he will abundantly pardon.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 55,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And Zacchaeus stood and said to the Lord, “Behold, Lord, the half of my goods I give to the poor. And if I have defrauded anyone of anything, I restore it fourfold.” And Jesus said to him, “Today salvation has come to this house, since he also is a son of Abraham. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 19,8-9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Then you will remember your ways and be ashamed when you take your sisters, both your elder and your younger, and I give them to you as daughters, but not on account of the covenant with you. that you may remember and be confounded, and never open your mouth again because of your shame, when I atone for you for all that you have done, declares the Lord God.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 16,61.63</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>The saying is trustworthy and deserving of full acceptance, that Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners, of whom I am the foremost. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 1,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-06-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Sing praises to the Lord, who sits enthroned in Zion! Tell among the peoples his deeds! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 9,11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But the Lord stood by me and strengthened me, so that through me the message might be fully proclaimed and all the Gentiles might hear it. So I was rescued from the lion’s mouth. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 4,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>5. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Foreigners shall build up your walls, and their kings shall minister to you; for in my wrath I struck you, but in my favor I have had mercy on you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 60,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Therefore, preparing your minds for action, and being sober-minded, set your hope fully on the grace that will be brought to you at the revelation of Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 1,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You have granted me life and steadfast love, and your care has preserved my spirit.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Job 10,12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Indeed he was ill, near to death. But God had mercy on him, and not only on him but on me also, lest I should have sorrow upon sorrow.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,27</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>What shall I render to the Lord for all his benefits to me? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 116,12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And he did not permit him but said to him, “Go home to your friends and tell them how much the Lord has done for you, and how he has had mercy on you.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Mark 5,19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Of David. Bless the Lord, O my soul, and all that is within me, bless his holy name! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 103,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>As he was drawing near—already on the way down the Mount of Olives—the whole multitude of his disciples began to rejoice and praise God with a loud voice for all the mighty works that they had seen, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 19,37</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>But Micaiah said, “As the Lord lives, what my God says, that I will speak.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 18,13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>preach the word; be ready in season and out of season; reprove, rebuke, and exhort, with complete patience and teaching. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 4,2</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>He who planted the ear, does he not hear? He who formed the eye, does he not see? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 94,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For the eyes of the Lord are on the righteous, and his ears are open to their prayer. But the face of the Lord is against those who do evil.”  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 3,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Enter not into judgment with your servant, for no one living is righteous before you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 143,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Note then the kindness and the severity of God: severity toward those who have fallen, but God’s kindness to you, provided you continue in his kindness. Otherwise you too will be cut off. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 11,22</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>6. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>You cause the grass to grow for the livestock and plants for man to cultivate, that he may bring forth food from the earth </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 104,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Give us each day our daily bread, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 11,3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For the Lord loves justice; he will not forsake his saints. They are preserved forever, but the children of the wicked shall be cut off. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 37,28</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Therefore be imitators of God, as beloved children. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,1</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>One gives freely, yet grows all the richer; another withholds what he should give, and only suffers want. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 11,24</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Do not neglect to show hospitality to strangers, for thereby some have entertained angels unawares. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,2</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And I said: “Woe is me! For I am lost; for I am a man of unclean lips, and I dwell in the midst of a people of unclean lips; for my eyes have seen the King, the Lord of hosts!” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 6,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Therefore, having put away falsehood, let each one of you speak the truth with his neighbor, for we are members one of another. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 4,25</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And the Spirit of the Lord shall rest upon him, the Spirit of wisdom and understanding, the Spirit of counsel and might, the Spirit of knowledge and the fear of the Lord. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 11,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And all the crowd sought to touch him, for power came out from him and healed them all. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 6,19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I made the earth and created man on it; it was my hands that stretched out the heavens, and I commanded all their host. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 45,12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>that they should seek God, and perhaps feel their way toward him and find him. Yet he is actually not far from each one of us, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 17,27</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Therefore the Lord waits to be gracious to you, and therefore he exalts himself to show mercy to you. For the Lord is a God of justice; blessed are all those who wait for him. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 30,18</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>If you know that he is righteous, you may be sure that everyone who practices righteousness has been born of him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 2,29</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>7. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>like heat in a dry place. You subdue the noise of the foreigners; as heat by the shade of a cloud, so the song of the ruthless is put down. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 25,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Whoever makes a practice of sinning is of the devil, for the devil has been sinning from the beginning. The reason the Son of God appeared was to destroy the works of the devil. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 3,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>May the Lord give strength to his people! May the Lord bless his people with peace! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 29,11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>As for the word that he sent to Israel, preaching good news of peace through Jesus Christ (he is Lord of all), </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 10,36</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>and you shall be to me a kingdom of priests and a holy nation.’ These are the words that you shall speak to the people of Israel.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 19,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Jesus said to them again, “Peace be with you. As the Father has sent me, even so I am sending you.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 20,21</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Return, O faithless children, declares the Lord; for I am your master; I will take you, one from a city and two from a family, and I will bring you to Zion. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 3,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>All that the Father gives me will come to me, and whoever comes to me I will never cast out. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 6,37</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Both riches and honor come from you, and you rule over all. In your hand are power and might, and in your hand it is to make great and to give strength to all. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 29,12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>An argument arose among them as to which of them was the greatest. But Jesus, knowing the reasoning of their hearts, took a child and put him by his side  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 9,46-47</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And I will put this third into the fire, and refine them as one refines silver, and test them as gold is tested. They will call upon my name, and I will answer them. I will say, ‘They are my people’; and they will say, ‘The Lord is my God.’” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Zechariah 13,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Not only that, but we rejoice in our sufferings, knowing that suffering produces endurance, and endurance produces character, and character produces hope,  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,3-4</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>then the Lord God formed the man of dust from the ground and breathed into his nostrils the breath of life, and the man became a living creature. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 2,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For we are his workmanship, created in Christ Jesus for good works, which God prepared beforehand, that we should walk in them. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>8. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>They collapse and fall, but we rise and stand upright.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 20,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>You then, my child, be strengthened by the grace that is in Christ Jesus, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,1</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I will multiply your offspring as the stars of heaven and will give to your offspring all these lands. And in your offspring all the nations of the earth shall be blessed, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 26,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>I tell you, many will come from east and west and recline at table with Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob in the kingdom of heaven, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 8,11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Turn to him from whom people have deeply revolted, O children of Israel. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 31,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Behold, I stand at the door and knock. If anyone hears my voice and opens the door, I will come in to him and eat with him, and he with me. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 3,20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>So God created man in his own image, in the image of God he created him; male and female he created them. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 1,27</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Nevertheless, in the Lord woman is not independent of man nor man of woman; for as woman was made from man, so man is now born of woman. And all things are from God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 11,11-12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For the mountains may depart and the hills be removed, but my steadfast love shall not depart from you, and my covenant of peace shall not be removed,” says the Lord, who has compassion on you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 54,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have eternal life. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 3,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Before I was afflicted I went astray, but now I keep your word. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 119,67</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Jesus answered him, “If anyone loves me, he will keep my word, and my Father will love him, and we will come to him and make our home with him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 14,23</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Then the Lord said to me, “You have seen well, for I am watching over my word to perform it.”  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 1,12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For the word of God is living and active, sharper than any two-edged sword, piercing to the division of soul and of spirit, of joints and of marrow, and discerning the thoughts and intentions of the heart. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 4,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>9. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Truly, you are a God who hides himself, O God of Israel, the Savior. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 45,15</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>No one has ever seen God; the only God, who is at the Father’s side, he has made him known. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 1,18</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Incline my heart to your testimonies, and not to selfish gain! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 119,36</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For the love of money is a root of all kinds of evils. It is through this craving that some have wandered away from the faith and pierced themselves with many pangs. But as for you, O man of God, flee these things. Pursue righteousness, godliness, faith, love, steadfastness, gentleness. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 6,10.11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-07-3100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“O Lord of hosts, God of Israel, enthroned above the cherubim, you are the God, you alone, of all the kingdoms of the earth; you have made heaven and earth. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 37,16</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Then I saw heaven opened, and behold, a white horse! The one sitting on it is called Faithful and True, and in righteousness he judges and makes war. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 19,11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Jonathan said to the young man who carried his armor, “Come, let us go over to the garrison of these uncircumcised. It may be that the Lord will work for us, for nothing can hinder the Lord from saving by many or by few.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 14,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Therefore I tell you, whatever you ask in prayer, believe that you have received it, and it will be yours. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Mark 11,24</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Attend to my cry, for I am brought very low! Deliver me from my persecutors, for they are too strong for me! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 142,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ! According to his great mercy, he has caused us to be born again to a living hope through the resurrection of Jesus Christ from the dead, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 1,3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You shall not seek their peace or their prosperity all your days forever. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 23,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>if we are faithless, he remains faithful— for he cannot deny himself. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>In his hand is the life of every living thing and the breath of all mankind. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Job 12,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For none of us lives to himself, and none of us dies to himself. For if we live, we live to the Lord, and if we die, we die to the Lord. So then, whether we live or whether we die, we are the Lord’s. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 14,7-8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>10. Sonntag nach Trinitatis (Israelsonntag)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>these I will bring to my holy mountain, and make them joyful in my house of prayer; their burnt offerings and their sacrifices will be accepted on my altar; for my house shall be called a house of prayer for all peoples.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 56,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But the hour is coming, and is now here, when the true worshipers will worship the Father in spirit and truth, for the Father is seeking such people to worship him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 4,23</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>the Lord protects him and keeps him alive; he is called blessed in the land; you do not give him up to the will of his enemies. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 41,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Bear one another’s burdens, and so fulfill the law of Christ. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Galatians 6,2</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You came near when I called on you; you said, ‘Do not fear!’ </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Lamentations 3,57</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And he saw that they were making headway painfully, for the wind was against them. And about the fourth watch of the night he came to them, walking on the sea. He meant to pass by them, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Mark 6,48</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord is exalted, for he dwells on high; he will fill Zion with justice and righteousness, and he will be the stability of your times, abundance of salvation, wisdom, and knowledge; the fear of the Lord is Zion’s treasure. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 33,5-6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And proclaim as you go, saying, ‘The kingdom of heaven is at hand.’ </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 10,7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You shall walk in all the way that the Lord your God has commanded you, that you may live, and that it may go well with you, and that you may live long in the land that you shall possess. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 5,33</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>He said to him, “What is written in the Law? How do you read it?”  And he answered, “You shall love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your strength and with all your mind, and your neighbor as yourself.” And he said to him, “You have answered correctly; do this, and you will live.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 10,26-28</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Behold, the nations are like a drop from a bucket, and are accounted as the dust on the scales; behold, he takes up the coastlands like fine dust. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 40,15</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And Jesus came and said to them, “All authority in heaven and on earth has been given to me. Go therefore and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit, teaching them to observe all that I have commanded you. And behold, I am with you always, to the end of the age.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 28,18-20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For your steadfast love is great to the heavens, your faithfulness to the clouds. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 57,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>both Jews and proselytes, Cretans and Arabians—we hear them telling in our own tongues the mighty works of God.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 2,11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>11. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>I gave my back to those who strike, and my cheeks to those who pull out the beard; I hid not my face from disgrace and spitting. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 50,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So Jesus also suffered outside the gate in order to sanctify the people through his own blood. Therefore let us go to him outside the camp and bear the reproach he endured. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,12-13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>But that prophet or that dreamer of dreams shall be put to death, because he has taught rebellion against the Lord your God, who brought you out of the land of Egypt and redeemed you out of the house of slavery, to make you leave the way in which the Lord your God commanded you to walk. So you shall purge the evil from your midst. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 13,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“This is my commandment, that you love one another as I have loved you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 15,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>He alone is my rock and my salvation, my fortress; I shall not be greatly shaken. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 62,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>teaching them to observe all that I have commanded you. And behold, I am with you always, to the end of the age.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 28,20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The name of the Lord is a strong tower; the righteous man runs into it and is safe. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 18,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“I am the Alpha and the Omega,” says the Lord God, “who is and who was and who is to come, the Almighty.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 1,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Thus says the Lord, your Redeemer, the Holy One of Israel: “I am the Lord your God, who teaches you to profit, who leads you in the way you should go.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 48,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Think over what I say, for the Lord will give you understanding in everything.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And the Lord said, “You pity the plant, for which you did not labor, nor did you make it grow, which came into being in a night and perished in a night.  And should not I pity Nineveh, that great city, in which there are more than 120,000 persons who do not know their right hand from their left, and also much cattle?” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jonah 4,10-11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Let no one seek his own good, but the good of his neighbor. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 10,24</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Then the people answered, “Far be it from us that we should forsake the Lord to serve other gods,  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Joshua 24,16</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>rooted and built up in him and established in the faith, just as you were taught, abounding in thanksgiving. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 2,7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>12. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>The Spirit of the Lord God is upon me, because the Lord has anointed me to bring good news to the poor; he has sent me to bind up the brokenhearted, to proclaim liberty to the captives, and the opening of the prison to those who are bound; </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 61,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Not that we lord it over your faith, but we work with you for your joy, for you stand firm in your faith. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,24</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And they kept the Feast of Unleavened Bread seven days with joy, for the Lord had made them joyful and had turned the heart of the king of Assyria to them, so that he aided them in the work of the house of God, the God of Israel. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezra 6,22</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And day by day, attending the temple together and breaking bread in their homes, they received their food with glad and generous hearts, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 2,46</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord our God be with us, as he was with our fathers. May he not leave us or forsake us, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers> 1 Kings 8,57</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And they went out and preached everywhere, while the Lord worked with them and confirmed the message by accompanying signs.]] </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Mark 16,20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Nevertheless, in your great mercies you did not make an end of them or forsake them, for you are a gracious and merciful God. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Nehemiah 9,31</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>We always thank God, the Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, when we pray for you, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>My soul longs, yes, faints for the courts of the Lord; my heart and flesh sing for joy to the living God. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 84,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For where two or three are gathered in my name, there am I among them.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 18,20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And the angel said to those who were standing before him, “Remove the filthy garments from him.” And to him he said, “Behold, I have taken your iniquity away from you, and I will clothe you with pure vestments.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Zechariah 3,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And the son said to him, ‘Father, I have sinned against heaven and before you. I am no longer worthy to be called your son.’ But the father said to his servants, ‘Bring quickly the best robe, and put it on him, and put a ring on his hand, and shoes on his feet. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 15,21-22</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Behold, I was brought forth in iniquity, and in sin did my mother conceive me. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 51,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 1,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>13. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Whoever is wise, let him understand these things; whoever is discerning, let him know them; for the ways of the Lord are right, and the upright walk in them, but transgressors stumble in them.</Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Hosea 14,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And let us consider how to stir up one another to love and good works, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 10,24</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“You have led in your steadfast love the people whom you have redeemed; you have guided them by your strength to your holy abode. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 15,13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And walk in love, as Christ loved us and gave himself up for us, a fragrant offering and sacrifice to God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,2</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord reigns, let the earth rejoice; let the many coastlands be glad! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 97,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And they sing the song of Moses, the servant of God, and the song of the Lamb, saying, “Great and amazing are your deeds, O Lord God the Almighty! Just and true are your ways, O King of the nations! Who will not fear, O Lord, and glorify your name? For you alone are holy. All nations will come and worship you, for your righteous acts have been revealed.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 15,3-4</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>On your walls, O Jerusalem, I have set watchmen; all the day and all the night they shall never be silent. You who put the Lord in remembrance, take no rest, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 62,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But you will receive power when the Holy Spirit has come upon you, and you will be my witnesses in Jerusalem and in all Judea and Samaria, and to the end of the earth.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 1,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And the Lord said to Moses,  “I have heard the grumbling of the people of Israel. Say to them, ‘At twilight you shall eat meat, and in the morning you shall be filled with bread. Then you shall know that I am the Lord your God.’” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 16,11-12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>One of his disciples, Andrew, Simon Peter’s brother, said to him, “There is a boy here who has five barley loaves and two fish, but what are they for so many?” Jesus said, “Have the people sit down.” Now there was much grass in the place. So the men sat down, about five thousand in number. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 6,8-10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-08-3100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Then the Lord called Samuel, and he said, “Here I am!”  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 3,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And going on a little farther, he saw James the son of Zebedee and John his brother, who were in their boat mending the nets.  And immediately he called them, and they left their father Zebedee in the boat with the hired servants and followed him.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Mark 1,19.20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“You shall not oppress a sojourner. You know the heart of a sojourner, for you were sojourners in the land of Egypt. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 23,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And he rose and took the child and his mother by night and departed to Egypt  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 2,14</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>14. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>All the ends of the earth shall remember and turn to the Lord, and all the families of the nations shall worship before you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 22,27</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Jesus said to them, “I am the bread of life; whoever comes to me shall not hunger, and whoever believes in me shall never thirst. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 6,35</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I have heard Ephraim grieving, ‘You have disciplined me, and I was disciplined, like an untrained calf; bring me back that I may be restored, for you are the Lord my God. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,18</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>and to be renewed in the spirit of your minds, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 4,23</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>So Samuel told him everything and hid nothing from him. And he said, “It is the Lord. Let him do what seems good to him.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 3,18</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Your kingdom come, your will be done, on earth as it is in heaven. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“Return, O faithless sons; I will heal your faithlessness.” “Behold, we come to you, for you are the Lord our God. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 3,22</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And because you are sons, God has sent the Spirit of his Son into our hearts, crying, “Abba! Father!” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Galatians 4,6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Do not be afraid of sudden terror or of the ruin of the wicked, when it comes, for the Lord will be your confidence and will keep your foot from being caught. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 3,25.26</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Finally, be strong in the Lord and in the strength of his might. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 6,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For there will never cease to be poor in the land. Therefore I command you, ‘You shall open wide your hand to your brother, to the needy and to the poor, in your land.’ </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 15,11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Little children, let us not love in word or talk but in deed and in truth. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 3,18</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And they shall know that I am the Lord their God with them, and that they, the house of Israel, are my people, declares the Lord God. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 34,30</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>You did not choose me, but I chose you and appointed you that you should go and bear fruit and that your fruit should abide, so that whatever you ask the Father in my name, he may give it to you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 15,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>15. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>then will you delight in right sacrifices, in burnt offerings and whole burnt offerings; then bulls will be offered on your altar. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 51,19</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And when Jesus heard it, he said to them, “Those who are well have no need of a physician, but those who are sick. I came not to call the righteous, but sinners.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Mark 2,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And I will make you to this people a fortified wall of bronze; they will fight against you, but they shall not prevail over you, for I am with you to save you and deliver you, declares the Lord. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 15,20</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“Let not your hearts be troubled. Believe in God; believe also in me. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 14,1</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>He will cover you with his pinions, and under his wings you will find refuge; his faithfulness is a shield and buckler. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 91,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But the Lord is faithful. He will establish you and guard you against the evil one. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 3,3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I cry out to God Most High, to God who fulfills his purpose for me. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 57,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>I am writing to you, little children, because your sins are forgiven for his name’s sake. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 2,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“Behold, I send an angel before you to guard you on the way and to bring you to the place that I have prepared. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 23,20</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>The Lord will rescue me from every evil deed and bring me safely into his heavenly kingdom. To him be the glory forever and ever. Amen. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 4,18</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Wondrously show your steadfast love, O Savior of those who seek refuge from their adversaries at your right hand. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 17,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And will not God give justice to his elect, who cry to him day and night? Will he delay long over them?</Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 18, 7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Out of Zion, the perfection of beauty, God shines forth. Our God comes; he does not keep silence; before him is a devouring fire, around him a mighty tempest. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 50,2-3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Long ago, at many times and in many ways, God spoke to our fathers by the prophets, but in these last days he has spoken to us by his Son, whom he appointed the heir of all things, through whom also he created the world. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 1,1-2</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>16. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Return, O Lord! How long? Have pity on your servants! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 90,13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So also you have sorrow now, but I will see you again, and your hearts will rejoice, and no one will take your joy from you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 16,22</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>They shall not defile themselves anymore with their idols and their detestable things, or with any of their transgressions. But I will save them from all the backslidings in which they have sinned, and will cleanse them; and they shall be my people, and I will be their God. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 37,23</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>and from Jesus Christ the faithful witness, the firstborn of the dead, and the ruler of kings on earth. To him who loves us and has freed us from our sins by his blood and made us a kingdom, priests to his God and Father, to him be glory and dominion forever and ever. Amen. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 1,5-6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Therefore Eli said to Samuel, “Go, lie down, and if he calls you, you shall say, ‘Speak, Lord, for your servant hears.’” So Samuel went and lay down in his place.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 3,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Let what you heard from the beginning abide in you. If what you heard from the beginning abides in you, then you too will abide in the Son and in the Father. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 2,24</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>so that those who dwell at the ends of the earth are in awe at your signs. You make the going out of the morning and the evening to shout for joy.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 65,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Be not afraid when a man becomes rich, when the glory of his house increases.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 49,16</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>and which now has been manifested through the appearing of our Savior Christ Jesus, who abolished death and brought life and immortality to light through the gospel, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 1,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord God took the man and put him in the garden of Eden to work it and keep it. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 2,15</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“Blessed are the meek, for they shall inherit the earth. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“The Rock, his work is perfect, for all his ways are justice. A God of faithfulness and without iniquity, just and upright is he. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 32,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>This is the message we have heard from him and proclaim to you, that God is light, and in him is no darkness at all. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 1,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>17. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>And no longer shall each one teach his neighbor and each his brother, saying, ‘Know the Lord,’ for they shall all know me, from the least of them to the greatest, declares the Lord. For I will forgive their iniquity, and I will remember their sin no more.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,34</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>My little children, I am writing these things to you so that you may not sin. But if anyone does sin, we have an advocate with the Father, Jesus Christ the righteous. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 2,1</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord your God will make you abundantly prosperous in all the work of your hand, in the fruit of your womb and in the fruit of your cattle and in the fruit of your ground. For the Lord will again take delight in prospering you, as he took delight in your fathers, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 30,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>for it is God who works in you, both to will and to work for his good pleasure. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Behold, I am with you and will keep you wherever you go, and will bring you back to this land. For I will not leave you until I have done what I have promised you.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 28,15</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>By faith Jacob, when dying, blessed each of the sons of Joseph, bowing in worship over the head of his staff. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 11,21</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>for the Lord will be your confidence and will keep your foot from being caught. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 3,26</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>No, in all these things we are more than conquerors through him who loved us. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,37</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>How can I give you up, O Ephraim? How can I hand you over, O Israel? How can I make you like Admah? How can I treat you like Zeboiim? My heart recoils within me; my compassion grows warm and tender. I will not execute my burning anger; I will not again destroy Ephraim; for I am God and not a man, the Holy One in your midst, and I will not come in wrath. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Hosea 11,8.9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Now the law came in to increase the trespass, but where sin increased, grace abounded all the more, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Blessed be God, because he has not rejected my prayer or removed his steadfast love from me!  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 66,20</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Do not be like them, for your Father knows what you need before you ask him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Michaelistag</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>And as you have been a byword of cursing among the nations, O house of Judah and house of Israel, so will I save you, and you shall be a blessing. Fear not, but let your hands be strong.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Zechariah 8,13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For this very night there stood before me an angel of the God to whom I belong and whom I worship, and he said, ‘Do not be afraid, Paul; you must stand before Caesar. And behold, God has granted you all those who sail with you.’ </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 27,23-24</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-09-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>18. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Out of my distress I called on the Lord; the Lord answered me and set me free. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 118,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>in whom we have boldness and access with confidence through our faith in him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 3,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Let the favor of the Lord our God be upon us, and establish the work of our hands upon us; yes, establish the work of our hands! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 90,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>I am the vine; you are the branches. Whoever abides in me and I in him, he it is that bears much fruit, for apart from me you can do nothing. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 15,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And now, behold, I know that you shall surely be king, and that the kingdom of Israel shall be established in your hand. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 24,20</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Come to terms quickly with your accuser while you are going with him to court, lest your accuser hand you over to the judge, and the judge to the guard, and you be put in prison. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,25</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>But Israel is saved by the Lord with everlasting salvation; you shall not be put to shame or confounded to all eternity. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 45,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>You also, be patient. Establish your hearts, for the coming of the Lord is at hand. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 5,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And you have seen their detestable things, their idols of wood and stone, of silver and gold, which were among them.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 29,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Let all bitterness and wrath and anger and clamor and slander be put away from you, along with all malice. Be kind to one another, tenderhearted, forgiving one another, as God in Christ forgave you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 4,31-32</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And he shall stand and shepherd his flock in the strength of the Lord, in the majesty of the name of the Lord his God. And they shall dwell secure, for now he shall be great to the ends of the earth. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Micah 5,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Now may the Lord of peace himself give you peace at all times in every way. The Lord be with you all. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 3,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext> Praise the Lord! I will give thanks to the Lord with my whole heart, in the company of the upright, in the congregation. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 111,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Let the word of Christ dwell in you richly, teaching and admonishing one another in all wisdom, singing psalms and hymns and spiritual songs, with thankfulness in your hearts to God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 3,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Erntedankfest</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Yet it was I who taught Ephraim to walk; I took them up by their arms, but they did not know that I healed them. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Hosea 11,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And count the patience of our Lord as salvation, just as our beloved brother Paul also wrote to you according to the wisdom given him, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Peter 3,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And Jonathan, Saul’s son, rose and went to David at Horesh, and strengthened his hand in God.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 23,16</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>eager to maintain the unity of the Spirit in the bond of peace. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 4,3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I have set the Lord always before me; because he is at my right hand, I shall not be shaken. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 16,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>By faith he left Egypt, not being afraid of the anger of the king, for he endured as seeing him who is invisible. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 11,27</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Why do you contend against him, saying, ‘He will answer none of man’s words’? For God speaks in one way, and in two, though man does not perceive it. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Job 33,13-14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>They said to each other, “Did not our hearts burn within us while he talked to us on the road, while he opened to us the Scriptures?” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 24,32</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Speak: “Thus declares the Lord, ‘The dead bodies of men shall fall like dung upon the open field, like sheaves after the reaper, and none shall gather them.’” Thus says the Lord: “Let not the wise man boast in his wisdom, let not the mighty man boast in his might, let not the rich man boast in his riches, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 9,22-23</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For if anyone thinks he is something, when he is nothing, he deceives himself. But let each one test his own work, and then his reason to boast will be in himself alone and not in his neighbor. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Galatians 6,3-4</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Your threshing shall last to the time of the grape harvest, and the grape harvest shall last to the time for sowing. And you shall eat your bread to the full and dwell in your land securely. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Leviticus 26,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>The thief comes only to steal and kill and destroy. I came that they may have life and have it abundantly. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 10,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Let us come into his presence with thanksgiving; let us make a joyful noise to him with songs of praise! For the Lord is a great God, and a great King above all gods. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 95,2-3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>May the God of endurance and encouragement grant you to live in such harmony with one another, in accord with Christ Jesus, that together you may with one voice glorify the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 15,5-6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>20. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>But Moses said to him, “Are you jealous for my sake? Would that all the Lord’s people were prophets, that the Lord would put his Spirit on them!” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Numbers 11,29</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And when he had said this, he breathed on them and said to them, “Receive the Holy Spirit. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 20,22</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>He said, “Then put away the foreign gods that are among you, and incline your heart to the Lord, the God of Israel.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Joshua 24,23</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>for at one time you were darkness, but now you are light in the Lord. Walk as children of light </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>To do righteousness and justice is more acceptable to the Lord than sacrifice. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 21,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Do not judge by appearances, but judge with right judgment.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 7,24</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For to us a child is born, to us a son is given; and the government shall be upon his shoulder, and his name shall be called Wonderful Counselor, Mighty God, Everlasting Father, Prince of Peace. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 9,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Jesus Christ is the same yesterday and today and forever. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And David said, “The Lord who delivered me from the paw of the lion and from the paw of the bear will deliver me from the hand of this Philistine.” And Saul said to David, “Go, and the Lord be with you!” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 17,37</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So, whether you eat or drink, or whatever you do, do all to the glory of God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 10,31</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>These are the generations of Noah. Noah was a righteous man, blameless in his generation. Noah walked with God. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 6,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>In the same way, let your light shine before others, so that they may see your good works and give glory to your Father who is in heaven. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“I overthrew some of you, as when God overthrew Sodom and Gomorrah, and you were as a brand plucked out of the burning; yet you did not return to me,” declares the Lord. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Amos 4,11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>What if some were unfaithful? Does their faithlessness nullify the faithfulness of God? By no means! Let God be true though every one were a liar, as it is written, “That you may be justified in your words, and prevail when you are judged.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 3,3-4</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>21. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>And I commend joy, for man has nothing better under the sun but to eat and drink and be joyful, for this will go with him in his toil through the days of his life that God has given him under the sun. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ecclesiastes 8,15</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For everything created by God is good, and nothing is to be rejected if it is received with thanksgiving, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 4,4</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>In the path of your judgments, O Lord, we wait for you; your name and remembrance are the desire of our soul. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 26,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Humble yourselves, therefore, under the mighty hand of God so that at the proper time he may exalt you, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 5,6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>and the Lord uprooted them from their land in anger and fury and great wrath, and cast them into another land, as they are this day.’ </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 29,28</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>They said to the woman, “It is no longer because of what you said that we believe, for we have heard for ourselves, and we know that this is indeed the Savior of the world.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 4,42</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Can man make for himself gods? Such are not gods!” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 16,20</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>See to it that no one takes you captive by philosophy and empty deceit, according to human tradition, according to the elemental spirits of the world, and not according to Christ. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 2,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I will ponder all your work, and meditate on your mighty deeds. Your way, O God, is holy. What god is great like our God? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 77,12-13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But Mary treasured up all these things, pondering them in her heart. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>My flesh and my heart may fail, but God is the strength of my heart and my portion forever. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 73,26</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>The following night the Lord stood by him and said, “Take courage, for as you have testified to the facts about me in Jerusalem, so you must testify also in Rome.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 23,11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Do not go after other gods to serve and worship them, or provoke me to anger with the work of your hands. Then I will do you no harm.’ </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 25,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Therefore, since we are surrounded by so great a cloud of witnesses, let us also lay aside every weight, and sin which clings so closely, and let us run with endurance the race that is set before us, looking to Jesus, the founder and perfecter of our faith, who for the joy that was set before him endured the cross, despising the shame, and is seated at the right hand of the throne of God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 12,1-2</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>22. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Now the Lord said to Abram, “Go from your country and your kindred and your father’s house to the land that I will show you. And I will make of you a great nation, and I will bless you and make your name great, so that you will be a blessing. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 12,1.2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Do not repay evil for evil or reviling for reviling, but on the contrary, bless, for to this you were called, that you may obtain a blessing. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 3,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>But you, dress yourself for work; arise, and say to them everything that I command you. Do not be dismayed by them, lest I dismay you before them. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 1,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Stand therefore, having fastened on the belt of truth, and having put on the breastplate of righteousness, and, as shoes for your feet, having put on the readiness given by the gospel of peace. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 6,14-15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The lot is cast into the lap, but its every decision is from the Lord. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 16,33</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But seek first the kingdom of God and his righteousness, and all these things will be added to you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,33</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-10-3100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Reformationstag</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>But Moses implored the Lord his God and said, “O Lord, why does your wrath burn hot against your people, whom you have brought out of the land of Egypt with great power and with a mighty hand? Why should the Egyptians say, ‘With evil intent did he bring them out, to kill them in the mountains and to consume them from the face of the earth’? Turn from your burning anger and relent from this disaster against your people. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 32,11.12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Who is to condemn? Christ Jesus is the one who died—more than that, who was raised—who is at the right hand of God, who indeed is interceding for us. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,34</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I will thank you in the great congregation; in the mighty throng I will praise you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 35,18</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>and every tongue confess that Jesus Christ is Lord, to the glory of God the Father. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And they offered great sacrifices that day and rejoiced, for God had made them rejoice with great joy; the women and children also rejoiced. And the joy of Jerusalem was heard far away.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Nehemiah 12,43</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Rejoice in the Lord always; again I will say, rejoice. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,4</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Even though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I will fear no evil, for you are with me; your rod and your staff, they comfort me. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 23,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For as we share abundantly in Christ’s sufferings, so through Christ we share abundantly in comfort too. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>23. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>You shall love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your might. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 6,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>so that Christ may dwell in your hearts through faith—that you, being rooted and grounded in love, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 3,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext> For he has delivered me from every trouble, and my eye has looked in triumph on my enemies.</Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 54,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of mercies and God of all comfort, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>How great are your works, O Lord! Your thoughts are very deep! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 92,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But that you may know that the Son of Man has authority on earth to forgive sins”—he said to the man who was paralyzed—“I say to you, rise, pick up your bed and go home.” And immediately he rose up before them and picked up what he had been lying on and went home, glorifying God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 5,24-25</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I have told the glad news of deliverance in the great congregation; behold, I have not restrained my lips, as you know, O Lord. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 40,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For this is the love of God, that we keep his commandments. And his commandments are not burdensome. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 5,3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And Jehoshaphat said to the king of Israel, “Inquire first for the word of the Lord.”  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 18,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But as for you, continue in what you have learned and have firmly believed, knowing from whom you learned it </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 3,14</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord our God be with us, as he was with our fathers. May he not leave us or forsake us, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers> 1 Kings 8,57</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>so that you may not be sluggish, but imitators of those who through faith and patience inherit the promises. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 6,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Praise the Lord! Oh give thanks to the Lord, for he is good, for his steadfast love endures forever! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 106,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For the grace of God has appeared, bringing salvation for all people, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Titus 2,11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Drittletzter Sonntag des Kirchenjahres</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>“I am the Lord your God, who brought you out of the land of Egypt, out of the house of slavery. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 20,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So they went out of the prison and visited Lydia. And when they had seen the brothers, they encouraged them and departed. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 16,40</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>and for all the work to be done by craftsmen, gold for the things of gold and silver for the things of silver. Who then will offer willingly, consecrating himself today to the Lord?”  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 29,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>The point is this: whoever sows sparingly will also reap sparingly, and whoever sows bountifully will also reap bountifully. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 9,6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>‘You yourselves have seen what I did to the Egyptians, and how I bore you on eagles’ wings and brought you to myself. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 19,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Now to him who is able to do far more abundantly than all that we ask or think, according to the power at work within us, to him be glory in the church and in Christ Jesus throughout all generations, forever and ever. Amen. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 3,20-21</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“Shower, O heavens, from above, and let the clouds rain down righteousness; let the earth open, that salvation and righteousness may bear fruit; let the earth cause them both to sprout; I the Lord have created it. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 45,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For he says, “In a favorable time I listened to you, and in a day of salvation I have helped you.” Behold, now is the favorable time; behold, now is the day of salvation. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 6,2</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord is the strength of his people; he is the saving refuge of his anointed. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 28,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But thanks be to God, who gives us the victory through our Lord Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 15,57</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“There is none holy like the Lord: for there is none besides you; there is no rock like our God. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 2,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“Everyone then who hears these words of mine and does them will be like a wise man who built his house on the rock. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 7,24</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Your sun shall no more go down, nor your moon withdraw itself; for the Lord will be your everlasting light, and your days of mourning shall be ended. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 60,20</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For the Lamb in the midst of the throne will be their shepherd, and he will guide them to springs of living water, and God will wipe away every tear from their eyes.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 7,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Vorletzter Sonntag des Kirchenjahres</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>The one who offers thanksgiving as his sacrifice glorifies me; to one who orders his way rightly I will show the salvation of God!” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 50,23</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>give thanks in all circumstances; for this is the will of God in Christ Jesus for you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,18</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>No man shall be able to stand before you all the days of your life. Just as I was with Moses, so I will be with you. I will not leave you or forsake you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Joshua 1,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Truly, truly, I say to you, you will weep and lament, but the world will rejoice. You will be sorrowful, but your sorrow will turn into joy. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 16,20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord will keep your going out and your coming in from this time forth and forevermore. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 121,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For here we have no lasting city, but we seek the city that is to come. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,14</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Buß- und Bettag</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Better is a little with righteousness than great revenues with injustice. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 16,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>that no one transgress and wrong his brother in this matter, because the Lord is an avenger in all these things, as we told you beforehand and solemnly warned you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 4,6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>and he went out to meet Asa and said to him, “Hear me, Asa, and all Judah and Benjamin: The Lord is with you while you are with him. If you seek him, he will be found by you, but if you forsake him, he will forsake you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 15,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“Ask, and it will be given to you; seek, and you will find; knock, and it will be opened to you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 7,7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Is not my word like fire, declares the Lord, and like a hammer that breaks the rock in pieces? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 23,29</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And when they had prayed, the place in which they were gathered together was shaken, and they were all filled with the Holy Spirit and continued to speak the word of God with boldness. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 4,31</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord works righteousness and justice for all who are oppressed. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 103,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And I heard a loud voice from the throne saying, “Behold, the dwelling place of God is with man. He will dwell with them, and they will be his people, and God himself will be with them as their God. He will wipe away every tear from their eyes, and death shall be no more, neither shall there be mourning, nor crying, nor pain anymore, for the former things have passed away.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 21,3-4</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Letzter Sonntag des Kirchenjahres (Ewigkeitssonntag)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Oh sing to the Lord a new song; sing to the Lord, all the earth! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 96,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>After this I looked, and behold, a great multitude that no one could number, from every nation, from all tribes and peoples and languages, standing before the throne and before the Lamb, clothed in white robes, with palm branches in their hands, and crying out with a loud voice, “Salvation belongs to our God who sits on the throne, and to the Lamb!” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 7,9-10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord watches over the sojourners; he upholds the widow and the fatherless, but the way of the wicked he brings to ruin. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 146,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>he has brought down the mighty from their thrones and exalted those of humble estate; he has filled the hungry with good things, and the rich he has sent away empty. He has helped his servant Israel, in remembrance of his mercy, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,52-54</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Is it not to share your bread with the hungry and bring the homeless poor into your house; when you see the naked, to cover him, and not to hide yourself from your own flesh? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 58,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Do not neglect to do good and to share what you have, for such sacrifices are pleasing to God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>that your eyes may be open night and day toward this house, the place of which you have said, ‘My name shall be there,’ that you may listen to the prayer that your servant offers toward this place. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers> 1 Kings 8,29</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So then you are no longer strangers and aliens, but you are fellow citizens with the saints and members of the household of God, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Behold, you have made my days a few handbreadths, and my lifetime is as nothing before you. Surely all mankind stands as a mere breath! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 39,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>When I saw him, I fell at his feet as though dead. But he laid his right hand on me, saying, “Fear not, I am the first and the last, and the living one. I died, and behold I am alive forevermore, and I have the keys of Death and Hades. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 1,17-18</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-11-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“And if you faithfully obey the voice of the Lord your God, being careful to do all his commandments that I command you today, the Lord your God will set you high above all the nations of the earth. Blessed shall you be when you come in, and blessed shall you be when you go out. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 28,1.6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And a vision appeared to Paul in the night: a man of Macedonia was standing there, urging him and saying, “Come over to Macedonia and help us.”  And when Paul had seen the vision, immediately we sought to go on into Macedonia, concluding that God had called us to preach the gospel to them. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 16,9-10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>But I am poor and needy; hasten to me, O God! You are my help and my deliverer; O Lord, do not delay! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 70,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>As he said these things, all his adversaries were put to shame, and all the people rejoiced at all the glorious things that were done by him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 13,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>1. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>“Therefore say to the house of Israel, Thus says the Lord God: Repent and turn away from your idols, and turn away your faces from all your abominations. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 14,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And the scribe said to him, “You are right, Teacher. You have truly said that he is one, and there is no other besides him. And to love him with all the heart and with all the understanding and with all the strength, and to love one’s neighbor as oneself, is much more than all whole burnt offerings and sacrifices.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Mark 12,32-33</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>He raises up the poor from the dust; he lifts the needy from the ash heap to make them sit with princes and inherit a seat of honor. For the pillars of the earth are the Lord’s, and on them he has set the world. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 2,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And when he has found it, he lays it on his shoulders, rejoicing. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 15,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For I have no pleasure in the death of anyone, declares the Lord God; so turn, and live.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 18,32</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>and to put on the new self, created after the likeness of God in true righteousness and holiness. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 4,24</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord is your keeper; the Lord is your shade on your right hand. The sun shall not strike you by day, nor the moon by night. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 121,5-6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>who will sustain you to the end, guiltless in the day of our Lord Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 1,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>With God we shall do valiantly; it is he who will tread down our foes.</Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 60,12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Simon Peter answered him, “Lord, to whom shall we go? You have the words of eternal life, and we have believed, and have come to know, that you are the Holy One of God.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 6,68-69</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And Hezekiah prayed before the Lord and said: “O Lord, the God of Israel, enthroned above the cherubim, you are the God, you alone, of all the kingdoms of the earth; you have made heaven and earth. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>2 Kings 19,15</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Who will not fear, O Lord, and glorify your name? For you alone are holy. All nations will come and worship you, for your righteous acts have been revealed.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 15,4</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I had heard of you by the hearing of the ear, but now my eye sees you;  therefore I despise myself, and repent in dust and ashes.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Job 42,5-6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And Peter remembered the saying of Jesus, “Before the rooster crows, you will deny me three times.” And he went out and wept bitterly. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 26,75</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>2. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>who frustrates the signs of liars and makes fools of diviners, who turns wise men back and makes their knowledge foolish, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 44,25</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Beloved, do not believe every spirit, but test the spirits to see whether they are from God, for many false prophets have gone out into the world. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 4,1</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>My soul will be satisfied as with fat and rich food, and my mouth will praise you with joyful lips, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 63,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>First of all, then, I urge that supplications, prayers, intercessions, and thanksgivings be made for all people,  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 2,1</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Sing for joy, O heavens, and exult, O earth; break forth, O mountains, into singing! For the Lord has comforted his people and will have compassion on his afflicted. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 49,13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And because of him you are in Christ Jesus, who became to us wisdom from God, righteousness and sanctification and redemption, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 1,30</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Even now, behold, my witness is in heaven, and he who testifies for me is on high. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Job 16,19</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>At my first defense no one came to stand by me, but all deserted me. May it not be charged against them! But the Lord stood by me and strengthened me, so that through me the message might be fully proclaimed and all the Gentiles might hear it. So I was rescued from the lion’s mouth. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 4,16-17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I have blotted out your transgressions like a cloud and your sins like mist; return to me, for I have redeemed you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 44,22</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For God did not send his Son into the world to condemn the world, but in order that the world might be saved through him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 3,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>From the rising of the sun to its setting, the name of the Lord is to be praised! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 113,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“Blessed be the Lord God of Israel, for he has visited and redeemed his people and has raised up a horn of salvation for us in the house of his servant David, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,68-69</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Evening and morning and at noon I utter my complaint and moan, and he hears my voice. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 55,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>In that day you will ask nothing of me. Truly, truly, I say to you, whatever you ask of the Father in my name, he will give it to you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 16,23</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>3. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>My wounds stink and fester because of my foolishness,  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 38,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>She will bear a son, and you shall call his name Jesus, for he will save his people from their sins.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 1,21</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The wild beasts will honor me, the jackals and the ostriches, for I give water in the wilderness, rivers in the desert, to give drink to my chosen people, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 43,20</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>On the last day of the feast, the great day, Jesus stood up and cried out, “If anyone thirsts, let him come to me and drink. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 7,37</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And he believed the Lord, and he counted it to him as righteousness. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 15,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>No unbelief made him waver concerning the promise of God, but he grew strong in his faith as he gave glory to God,  fully convinced that God was able to do what he had promised. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 4,20-21</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>the precepts of the Lord are right, rejoicing the heart; the commandment of the Lord is pure, enlightening the eyes; </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 19,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Whoever keeps his commandments abides in God, and God in him. And by this we know that he abides in us, by the Spirit whom he has given us. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1.John 3,24</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>When my enemies turn back, they stumble and perish before your presence.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 9,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And Mary said, “My soul magnifies the Lord, and my spirit rejoices in God my Savior, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,46-47</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The memory of the righteous is a blessing, but the name of the wicked will rot. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 10,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Then the righteous will shine like the sun in the kingdom of their Father. He who has ears, let him hear. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 13,43</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Kiss the Son, lest he be angry, and you perish in the way, for his wrath is quickly kindled. Blessed are all who take refuge in him. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 2,12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>which is why I suffer as I do. But I am not ashamed, for I know whom I have believed, and I am convinced that he is able to guard until that day what has been entrusted to me. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 1,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>4. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Oh, taste and see that the Lord is good! Blessed is the man who takes refuge in him! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 34,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And an angel of the Lord appeared to them, and the glory of the Lord shone around them, and they were filled with great fear. And the angel said to them, “Fear not, for behold, I bring you good news of great joy that will be for all the people. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,9-10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Heiliger Abend</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Of David. To you, O Lord, I call; my rock, be not deaf to me, lest, if you be silent to me, I become like those who go down to the pit. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 28,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For unto you is born this day in the city of David a Savior, who is Christ the Lord. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Weihnachtsfest</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>The Lord is my strength and my shield; in him my heart trusts, and I am helped; my heart exults, and with my song I give thanks to him. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 28,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And the shepherds returned, glorifying and praising God for all they had heard and seen, as it had been told them. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>2. Weihnachtstag</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Then the Lord God said, “It is not good that the man should be alone; I will make him a helper fit for him.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 2,18</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>he took him up in his arms and blessed God and said, “Lord, now you are letting your servant depart in peace, according to your word; for my eyes have seen your salvation </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,28-30</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Take care lest your heart be deceived, and you turn aside and serve other gods and worship them; </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 11,16</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For freedom Christ has set us free; stand firm therefore, and do not submit again to a yoke of slavery. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Galatians 5,1</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>A glad heart makes a cheerful face, but by sorrow of heart the spirit is crushed. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 15,13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of mercies and God of all comfort, who comforts us in all our affliction, so that we may be able to comfort those who are in any affliction, with the comfort with which we ourselves are comforted by God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,3.4</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Then he said to them, “Go your way. Eat the fat and drink sweet wine and send portions to anyone who has nothing ready, for this day is holy to our Lord. And do not be grieved, for the joy of the Lord is your strength.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Nehemiah 8,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>May the God of hope fill you with all joy and peace in believing, so that by the power of the Holy Spirit you may abound in hope. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 15,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>1. Sonntag nach Weihnachten</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>With a freewill offering I will sacrifice to you; I will give thanks to your name, O Lord, for it is good. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 54,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Now to him who is able to keep you from stumbling and to present you blameless before the presence of his glory with great joy, to the only God, our Savior, through Jesus Christ our Lord, be glory, majesty, dominion, and authority, before all time and now and forever. Amen. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Jude 24-25</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2018-12-3100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Altjahrsabend</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>And now, O Lord God, confirm forever the word that you have spoken concerning your servant and concerning his house, and do as you have spoken.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>2 Samuel 7,25</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For all the promises of God find their Yes in him. That is why it is through him that we utter our Amen to God for his glory. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
</FreeXml>