<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<FreeXml>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Neujahr</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>“You shall not pervert the justice due to your poor in his lawsuit. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 23,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“There was a rich man who was clothed in purple and fine linen and who feasted sumptuously every day. And at his gate was laid a poor man named Lazarus, covered with sores, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 16,19-20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Then he sent his brothers away, and as they departed, he said to them, “Do not quarrel on the way.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 45,24</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>bearing with one another and, if one has a complaint against another, forgiving each other; as the Lord has forgiven you, so you also must forgive. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 3,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>O you who love the Lord, hate evil! He preserves the lives of his saints; he delivers them from the hand of the wicked. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 97,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And after you have suffered a little while, the God of all grace, who has called you to his eternal glory in Christ, will himself restore, confirm, strengthen, and establish you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 5,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You looked for much, and behold, it came to little. And when you brought it home, I blew it away. Why? declares the Lord of hosts. Because of my house that lies in ruins, while each of you busies himself with his own house. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Haggai 1,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Do not be slothful in zeal, be fervent in spirit, serve the Lord. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>By myself I have sworn; from my mouth has gone out in righteousness a word that shall not return: ‘To me every knee shall bow, every tongue shall swear allegiance.’ “Only in the Lord, it shall be said of me, are righteousness and strength; to him shall come and be ashamed all who were incensed against him. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 45,23-24</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“I am the Alpha and the Omega,” says the Lord God, “who is and who was and who is to come, the Almighty.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 1,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Epiphanias (Fest der Erscheinung des HEERN)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>I would soon subdue their enemies and turn my hand against their foes. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 81,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For the grace of God has appeared, bringing salvation for all people, training us to renounce ungodliness and worldly passions, and to live self-controlled, upright, and godly lives in the present age, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Titus 2,11-12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Heaping oppression upon oppression, and deceit upon deceit, they refuse to know me, declares the Lord. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 9,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Blessed is the man who remains steadfast under trial, for when he has stood the test he will receive the crown of life, which God has promised to those who love him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 1,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Indeed, none who wait for you shall be put to shame; they shall be ashamed who are wantonly treacherous. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 25,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For even when we came into Macedonia, our bodies had no rest, but we were afflicted at every turn—fighting without and fear within. But God, who comforts the downcast, comforted us by the coming of Titus, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 7,5-6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Because of your promise, and according to your own heart, you have brought about all this greatness, to make your servant know it.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>2 Samuel 7,21</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>In this the love of God was made manifest among us, that God sent his only Son into the world, so that we might live through him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1. John 4,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Then we departed from the river Ahava on the twelfth day of the first month, to go to Jerusalem. The hand of our God was on us, and he delivered us from the hand of the enemy and from ambushes by the way. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezra 8,31</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>My sheep hear my voice, and I know them, and they follow me. I give them eternal life, and they will never perish, and no one will snatch them out of my hand. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 10,27-28</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>In peace I will both lie down and sleep; for you alone, O Lord, make me dwell in safety. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 4,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>As for the rich in this present age, charge them not to be haughty, nor to set their hopes on the uncertainty of riches, but on God, who richly provides us with everything to enjoy. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 6,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>for these nations, which you are about to dispossess, listen to fortune-tellers and to diviners. But as for you, the Lord your God has not allowed you to do this.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 18,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And so, from the day we heard, we have not ceased to pray for you, asking that you may be filled with the knowledge of his will in all spiritual wisdom and understanding, so as to walk in a manner worthy of the Lord, fully pleasing to him: bearing fruit in every good work and increasing in the knowledge of God; </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,9-10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>1. Sonntag nach Epiphanias</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>In overflowing anger for a moment I hid my face from you, but with everlasting love I will have compassion on you,” says the Lord, your Redeemer. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 54,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Or do you presume on the riches of his kindness and forbearance and patience, not knowing that God’s kindness is meant to lead you to repentance? </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 2,4</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I will give them a heart to know that I am the Lord, and they shall be my people and I will be their God, for they shall return to me with their whole heart. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 24,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>As for the word that he sent to Israel, preaching good news of peace through Jesus Christ (he is Lord of all), </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 10,36</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You who fear the Lord, praise him! All you offspring of Jacob, glorify him, and stand in awe of him, all you offspring of Israel! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 22,23</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So they departed quickly from the tomb with fear and great joy, and ran to tell his disciples. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 28,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>some of the gods of the peoples who are around you, whether near you or far off from you, from the one end of the earth to the other, But you shall kill him. Your hand shall be first against him to put him to death, and afterward the hand of all the people. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 13,7.9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For freedom Christ has set us free; stand firm therefore, and do not submit again to a yoke of slavery. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Galatians 5,1</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And he said, “No; but I am the commander of the army of the Lord. Now I have come.” And Joshua fell on his face to the earth and worshiped and said to him, “What does my lord say to his servant?” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Joshua 5,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But blessed are your eyes, for they see, and your ears, for they hear. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 13,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Then the earth reeled and rocked; the foundations also of the mountains trembled and quaked, because he was angry. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 18,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Then he touched their eyes, saying, “According to your faith be it done to you.” And their eyes were opened. And Jesus sternly warned them, “See that no one knows about it.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 9,29-30</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For the Lord of hosts has purposed, and who will annul it? His hand is stretched out, and who will turn it back? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 14,27</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>What then shall we say to these things? If God is for us, who can be against us? </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,31</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>2. Sonntag nach Epiphanias</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>You search out my path and my lying down and are acquainted with all my ways.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 139,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Are not two sparrows sold for a penny? And not one of them will fall to the ground apart from your Father.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 10,29</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Come, behold the works of the Lord, how he has brought desolations on the earth. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 46,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But the Lord is faithful. He will establish you and guard you against the evil one. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 3,3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>and return to the Lord your God, you and your children, and obey his voice in all that I command you today, with all your heart and with all your soul, then the Lord your God will restore your fortunes and have mercy on you, and he will gather you again from all the peoples where the Lord your God has scattered you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 30,2.3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Draw near to God, and he will draw near to you. Cleanse your hands, you sinners, and purify your hearts, you double-minded. Be wretched and mourn and weep. Let your laughter be turned to mourning and your joy to gloom. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 4,8-9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I will make a covenant of peace with them. It shall be an everlasting covenant with them. And I will set them in their land and multiply them, and will set my sanctuary in their midst forevermore. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 37,26</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And he came and preached peace to you who were far off and peace to those who were near. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>With weeping they shall come, and with pleas for mercy I will lead them back, I will make them walk by brooks of water, in a straight path in which they shall not stumble, for I am a father to Israel, and Ephraim is my firstborn. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For the Son of Man came to seek and to save the lost.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 19,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>O Lord, how manifold are your works! In wisdom have you made them all; the earth is full of your creatures. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 104,24</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And why are you anxious about clothing? Consider the lilies of the field, how they grow: they neither toil nor spin,  yet I tell you, even Solomon in all his glory was not arrayed like one of these. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,28-29</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“Behold, the days are coming, declares the Lord, when the city shall be rebuilt for the Lord from the Tower of Hananel to the Corner Gate. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,38</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>They will bring into it the glory and the honor of the nations.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 21,26</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Lezter Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Uphold me according to your promise, that I may live, and let me not be put to shame in my hope! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 119,116</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“I know your works. Behold, I have set before you an open door, which no one is able to shut. I know that you have but little power, and yet you have kept my word and have not denied my name. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 3,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Glad songs of salvation are in the tents of the righteous: “The right hand of the Lord does valiantly, the right hand of the Lord exalts, the right hand of the Lord does valiantly!” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 118,15.16</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Rejoice in the Lord always; again I will say, rejoice. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,4</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>O you hope of Israel, its savior in time of trouble, why should you be like a stranger in the land, like a traveler who turns aside to tarry for a night? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 14,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For now we see in a mirror dimly, but then face to face. Now I know in part; then I shall know fully, even as I have been fully known. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 13,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord has remembered us; he will bless us; he will bless the house of Israel; he will bless the house of Aaron; </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 115,12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Nevertheless, do not rejoice in this, that the spirits are subject to you, but rejoice that your names are written in heaven.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 10,20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-01-3100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>There is one whose rash words are like sword thrusts, but the tongue of the wise brings healing. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 12,18</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Look at the ships also: though they are so large and are driven by strong winds, they are guided by a very small rudder wherever the will of the pilot directs.  So also the tongue is a small member, yet it boasts of great things. How great a forest is set ablaze by such a small fire! </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 3,4-5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Give attention to the sound of my cry, my King and my God, for to you do I pray. O Lord, in the morning you hear my voice; in the morning I prepare a sacrifice for you and watch. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 5,2-3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Immediately the father of the child cried out and said, “I believe; help my unbelief!” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Mark 9,24</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>that my glory may sing your praise and not be silent. O Lord my God, I will give thanks to you forever! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 30,12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Then one of them, when he saw that he was healed, turned back, praising God with a loud voice; </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 17,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>5. Sonntag vor der Passionszeit</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>“Behold, the days are coming, declares the Lord, when I will make a new covenant with the house of Israel and the house of Judah, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,31</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But you have come to Mount Zion and to the city of the living God, the heavenly Jerusalem, and to innumerable angels in festal gathering, and to Jesus, the mediator of a new covenant, and to the sprinkled blood that speaks a better word than the blood of Abel. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 12,22.24</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>the precepts of the Lord are right, rejoicing the heart; the commandment of the Lord is pure, enlightening the eyes; </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 19,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>in whom are hidden all the treasures of wisdom and knowledge. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 2,3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And those who know your name put their trust in you, for you, O Lord, have not forsaken those who seek you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 9,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And will not God give justice to his elect, who cry to him day and night? Will he delay long over them? </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 18,7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>O land, land, land, hear the word of the Lord! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 22,29</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So then let us not sleep, as others do, but let us keep awake and be sober. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>He is like a tree planted by streams of water that yields its fruit in its season, and its leaf does not wither. In all that he does, he prospers. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 1,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>By this my Father is glorified, that you bear much fruit and so prove to be my disciples. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 15,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Please pardon the iniquity of this people, according to the greatness of your steadfast love, just as you have forgiven this people, from Egypt until now.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Numbers 14,19</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>and forgive us our debts, as we also have forgiven our debtors.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You gave a wide place for my steps under me, and my feet did not slip. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 18,36</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Finally, be strong in the Lord and in the strength of his might. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 6,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>4. Sonntag vor der Passionszeit</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Make haste to help me, O Lord, my salvation!</Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 38,23</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But he was in the stern, asleep on the cushion. And they woke him and said to him, “Teacher, do you not care that we are perishing?”  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Mark 4,38</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You make known to me the path of life; in your presence there is fullness of joy; at your right hand are pleasures forevermore. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 16,11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, patience, kindness, goodness, faithfulness, gentleness, self-control; against such things there is no law. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Galatians 5,22-23</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>To the Lord our God belong mercy and forgiveness, for we have rebelled against him </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Daniel 9,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Be merciful, even as your Father is merciful. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 6,36</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For you are our Father, though Abraham does not know us, and Israel does not acknowledge us; you, O Lord, are our Father, our Redeemer from of old is your name. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 63,16</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Pray then like this: “Our Father in heaven, hallowed be your name. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>remember the former things of old; for I am God, and there is no other; I am God, and there is none like me,  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 46,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>looking to Jesus, the founder and perfecter of our faith, who for the joy that was set before him endured the cross, despising the shame, and is seated at the right hand of the throne of God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 12,2</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And I will give you a new heart, and a new spirit I will put within you. And I will remove the heart of stone from your flesh and give you a heart of flesh. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 36,26</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>and, having been set free from sin, have become slaves of righteousness. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 6,18</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Praise the Lord, all nations! Extol him, all peoples! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 117,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>one God and Father of all, who is over all and through all and in all. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 4,6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>3. Sonntag vor der Passionszeit – Septuagesimae</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Bless our God, O peoples; let the sound of his praise be heard,  who has kept our soul among the living and has not let our feet slip. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 66,8-9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>so that we who were the first to hope in Christ might be to the praise of his glory. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 1,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For he wounds, but he binds up; he shatters, but his hands heal. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Job 5,18</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Humble yourselves, therefore, under the mighty hand of God so that at the proper time he may exalt you, casting all your anxieties on him, because he cares for you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 5,6-7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Kaph: My soul longs for your salvation; I hope in your word. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 119,81</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So Jesus said to the Jews who had believed him, “If you abide in my word, you are truly my disciples, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 8,31</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I stretch out my hands to you; my soul thirsts for you like a parched land. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 143,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Come to me, all who labor and are heavy laden, and I will give you rest. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 11,28</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Keep back your servant also from presumptuous sins; let them not have dominion over me! Then I shall be blameless, and innocent of great transgression. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 19,13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>All that the Father gives me will come to me, and whoever comes to me I will never cast out. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 6,37</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And no inhabitant will say, “I am sick”; the people who dwell there will be forgiven their iniquity. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 33,24</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Therefore, since we have been justified by faith, we have peace with God through our Lord Jesus Christ. Through him we have also obtained access by faith into this grace in which we stand, and we rejoice in hope of the glory of God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,1-2</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“Behold, the days are coming,” declares the Lord, “when the plowman shall overtake the reaper and the treader of grapes him who sows the seed; the mountains shall drip sweet wine, and all the hills shall flow with it. I will restore the fortunes of my people Israel, and they shall rebuild the ruined cities and inhabit them; they shall plant vineyards and drink their wine, and they shall make gardens and eat their fruit. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Amos 9,13-14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>through the middle of the street of the city; also, on either side of the river, the tree of life with its twelve kinds of fruit, yielding its fruit each month. The leaves of the tree were for the healing of the nations. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 22,2</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>2. Sonntag vor der Passionszeit – Sexagesimae</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>For I said, “Steadfast love will be built up forever; in the heavens you will establish your faithfulness.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 89,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For from his fullness we have all received, grace upon grace. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 1,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>In those days and in that time, declares the Lord, iniquity shall be sought in Israel, and there shall be none, and sin in Judah, and none shall be found, for I will pardon those whom I leave as a remnant. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 50,20</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>More than that, we also rejoice in God through our Lord Jesus Christ, through whom we have now received reconciliation. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You shall treat the stranger who sojourns with you as the native among you, and you shall love him as yourself, for you were strangers in the land of Egypt: I am the Lord your God. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Leviticus 19,34</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Beloved, it is a faithful thing you do in all your efforts for these brothers, strangers as they are, who testified to your love before the church. You will do well to send them on their journey in a manner worthy of God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>3. John 1,5-6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I will seek the lost, and I will bring back the strayed, and I will bind up the injured, and I will strengthen the weak, and the fat and the strong I will destroy. I will feed them in justice. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 34,16</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>What do you think? If a man has a hundred sheep, and one of them has gone astray, does he not leave the ninety-nine on the mountains and go in search of the one that went astray? </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 18,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-02-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>A voice says, “Cry!” And I said, “What shall I cry?” All flesh is grass, and all its beauty is like the flower of the field. The grass withers, the flower fades, but the word of our God will stand forever. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 40,6.8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Heaven and earth will pass away, but my words will not pass away. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 24,35</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Thus says the Lord, who makes a way in the sea, a path in the mighty waters, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 43,16</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>and not frightened in anything by your opponents. This is a clear sign to them of their destruction, but of your salvation, and that from God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 1,28</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And he humbled you and let you hunger and fed you with manna, which you did not know, nor did your fathers know, that he might make you know that man does not live by bread alone, but man lives by every word that comes from the mouth of the Lord. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 8,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>It is the Spirit who gives life; the flesh is no help at all. The words that I have spoken to you are spirit and life. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 6,63</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Sonntag vor der Passionszeit – Estomihi (Sei mir ein starker Fels! Psalm 31,3)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>For he stands at the right hand of the needy one, to save him from those who condemn his soul to death. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 109,31</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And as they continued to ask him, he stood up and said to them, “Let him who is without sin among you be the first to throw a stone at her.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 8,7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Who is like the Lord our God, who is seated on high, who looks far down on the heavens and the earth? He raises the poor from the dust and lifts the needy from the ash heap, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 113,5-7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>who, though he was in the form of God, did not count equality with God a thing to be grasped, but emptied himself, by taking the form of a servant, being born in the likeness of men. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,6-7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>But the path of the righteous is like the light of dawn, which shines brighter and brighter until full day. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 4,18</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Again Jesus spoke to them, saying, “I am the light of the world. Whoever follows me will not walk in darkness, but will have the light of life.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 8,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>O Lord, let me not be put to shame, for I call upon you; let the wicked be put to shame; let them go silently to Sheol. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 31,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And Mary said, “My soul magnifies the Lord, and my spirit rejoices in God my Savior, for he has looked on the humble estate of his servant. For behold, from now on all generations will call me blessed; </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,46-48</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord roars from Zion, and utters his voice from Jerusalem, and the heavens and the earth quake. But the Lord is a refuge to his people, a stronghold to the people of Israel. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Joel 4,16</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>so that by two unchangeable things, in which it is impossible for God to lie, we who have fled for refuge might have strong encouragement to hold fast to the hope set before us. We have this as a sure and steadfast anchor of the soul, a hope that enters into the inner place behind the curtain, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 6,18-19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I am the Lord; that is my name; my glory I give to no other, nor my praise to carved idols. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 42,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>yet for us there is one God, the Father, from whom are all things and for whom we exist, and one Lord, Jesus Christ, through whom are all things and through whom we exist. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 8,6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And it shall come to pass that as I have watched over them to pluck up and break down, to overthrow, destroy, and bring harm, so I will watch over them to build and to plant, declares the Lord. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,28</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For God has not destined us for wrath, but to obtain salvation through our Lord Jesus Christ, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>1. Sonntag der Passionszeit – Invokavit (Er ruft mich an, darum will ich ihn erhören. Psalm 91,15)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>For when I kept silent, my bones wasted away through my groaning all day long. For day and night your hand was heavy upon me; my strength was dried up as by the heat of summer. I acknowledged my sin to you, and I did not cover my iniquity; I said, “I will confess my transgressions to the Lord,” and you forgave the iniquity of my sin. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 32,3.4.5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Just so, I tell you, there is joy before the angels of God over one sinner who repents.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 15,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Then Jacob awoke from his sleep and said, “Surely the Lord is in this place, and I did not know it.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 28,16</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For he says, “In a favorable time I listened to you, and in a day of salvation I have helped you.” Behold, now is the favorable time; behold, now is the day of salvation. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 6,2</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“And you shall not covet your neighbor’s wife. And you shall not desire your neighbor’s house, his field, or his male servant, or his female servant, his ox, or his donkey, or anything that is your neighbor’s.’  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 5,21</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Love does no wrong to a neighbor; therefore love is the fulfilling of the law. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 13,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I will sing to the Lord, because he has dealt bountifully with me.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 13,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Is anyone among you suffering? Let him pray. Is anyone cheerful? Let him sing praise. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 5,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I am a companion of all who fear you, of those who keep your precepts. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 119,63</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Let the word of Christ dwell in you richly, teaching and admonishing one another in all wisdom, singing psalms and hymns and spiritual songs, with thankfulness in your hearts to God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 3,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Thus says the Lord: Do justice and righteousness, and deliver from the hand of the oppressor him who has been robbed. And do no wrong or violence to the resident alien, the fatherless, and the widow, nor shed innocent blood in this place. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 22,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>for at one time you were darkness, but now you are light in the Lord. Walk as children of light (for the fruit of light is found in all that is good and right and true), </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,8-9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For the Lord is righteous; he loves righteous deeds; the upright shall behold his face. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 11,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>You therefore must be perfect, as your heavenly Father is perfect. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,48</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>2. Sonntag der Passionszeit – Reminiszere (Gedenke, Herr, an deine Barmherzigkeit! Psalm 25,6)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>The living, the living, he thanks you, as I do this day; the father makes known to the children your faithfulness. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 38,19</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>but Jesus said, “Let the little children come to me and do not hinder them, for to such belongs the kingdom of heaven.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 19,14</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Woe to those who decree iniquitous decrees, and the writers who keep writing oppression, to turn aside the needy from justice and to rob the poor of my people of their right, that widows may be their spoil, and that they may make the fatherless their prey! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 10,1.2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Do not be conformed to this world, but be transformed by the renewal of your mind, that by testing you may discern what is the will of God, what is good and acceptable and perfect. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,2</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I will make your oppressors eat their own flesh, and they shall be drunk with their own blood as with wine. Then all flesh shall know that I am the Lord your Savior, and your Redeemer, the Mighty One of Jacob.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 49,26</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“The kingdom of heaven may be compared to a king who gave a wedding feast for his son, And those servants went out into the roads and gathered all whom they found, both bad and good. So the wedding hall was filled with guests. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 22,2.10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Then he took the Book of the Covenant and read it in the hearing of the people. And they said, “All that the Lord has spoken we will do, and we will be obedient.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 24,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For whoever does the will of my Father in heaven is my brother and sister and mother.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 12,50</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>the Lord opens the eyes of the blind. The Lord lifts up those who are bowed down; the Lord loves the righteous. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 146,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>for this reason, brothers, in all our distress and affliction we have been comforted about you through your faith. For now we live, if you are standing fast in the Lord. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 3,7-8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Let your work be shown to your servants, and your glorious power to their children. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 90,16</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Look at the birds of the air: they neither sow nor reap nor gather into barns, and yet your heavenly Father feeds them. Are you not of more value than they? </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,26</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You guide me with your counsel, and afterward you will receive me to glory. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 73,24</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>I have fought the good fight, I have finished the race, I have kept the faith. Henceforth there is laid up for me the crown of righteousness, which the Lord, the righteous judge, will award to me on that day, and not only to me but also to all who have loved his appearing. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 4,7-8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>3. Sonntag der Passionszeit – Okuli (Meine Augen sehen stets auf den Herrn. Psalm 25,15)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Like a swallow or a crane I chirp; I moan like a dove. My eyes are weary with looking upward. O Lord, I am oppressed; be my pledge of safety! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 38,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And when Jesus entered Peter’s house, he saw his mother-in-law lying sick with a fever. He touched her hand, and the fever left her, and she rose and began to serve him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 8,14-15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“Yet your people say, ‘The way of the Lord is not just,’ when it is their own way that is not just. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 33,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“If you love me, you will keep my commandments. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 14,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Remember not the sins of my youth or my transgressions; according to your steadfast love remember me, for the sake of your goodness, O Lord! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 25,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But God, being rich in mercy, because of the great love with which he loved us, even when we were dead in our trespasses, made us alive together with Christ—by grace you have been saved— </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,4-5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And he said, “O man greatly loved, fear not, peace be with you; be strong and of good courage.” And as he spoke to me, I was strengthened and said, “Let my lord speak, for you have strengthened me.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Daniel 10,19</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Peace I leave with you; my peace I give to you. Not as the world gives do I give to you. Let not your hearts be troubled, neither let them be afraid. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 14,27</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“You shall not put the Lord your God to the test, as you tested him at Massah. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 6,16</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Your kingdom come, your will be done, on earth as it is in heaven. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Therefore he shall give them up until the time when she who is in labor has given birth; then the rest of his brothers shall return to the people of Israel. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Micah 5,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Then will appear in heaven the sign of the Son of Man, and then all the tribes of the earth will mourn, and they will see the Son of Man coming on the clouds of heaven with power and great glory. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 24,30</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You shall not fall in with the many to do evil, nor shall you bear witness in a lawsuit, siding with the many, so as to pervert justice,  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 23,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Let brotherly love continue. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,1</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-03-3100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>4. Sonntag der Passionszeit – Lätare (Freuet euch mit Jerusalem! Jesaja 66,10)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>But this is gain for a land in every way: a king committed to cultivated fields.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ecclesiastes 5,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Sell your possessions, and give to the needy. Provide yourselves with moneybags that do not grow old, with a treasure in the heavens that does not fail, where no thief approaches and no moth destroys. For where your treasure is, there will your heart be also. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 12,33-34</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>O Lord, you hear the desire of the afflicted; you will strengthen their heart; you will incline your ear </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 10,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>May the God of hope fill you with all joy and peace in believing, so that by the power of the Holy Spirit you may abound in hope. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 15,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>But when the people of Israel cried out to the Lord, the Lord raised up a deliverer for the people of Israel, who saved them, Othniel the son of Kenaz, Caleb’s younger brother. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Judges 3,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>and from Jesus Christ the faithful witness, the firstborn of the dead, and the ruler of kings on earth. To him who loves us and has freed us from our sins by his blood and made us a kingdom, priests to his God and Father, to him be glory and dominion forever and ever. Amen. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 1,5.6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“Who is like you, O Lord, among the gods? Who is like you, majestic in holiness, awesome in glorious deeds, doing wonders? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 15,11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And we know that the Son of God has come and has given us understanding, so that we may know him who is true; and we are in him who is true, in his Son Jesus Christ. He is the true God and eternal life. Little children, keep yourselves from idols. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1. John 5,20.21</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Then he said to me, “Son of man, these bones are the whole house of Israel. Behold, they say, ‘Our bones are dried up, and our hope is lost; we are indeed cut off.’ Therefore prophesy, and say to them, Thus says the Lord God: Behold, I will open your graves and raise you from your graves, O my people. And I will bring you into the land of Israel. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 37,11-12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“Truly, truly, I say to you, an hour is coming, and is now here, when the dead will hear the voice of the Son of God, and those who hear will live. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 5,25</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And he said to him, “What is your name?” And he said, “Jacob.”  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 32,27</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And behold, a woman who had suffered from a discharge of blood for twelve years came up behind him and touched the fringe of his garment, for she said to herself, “If I only touch his garment, I will be made well.”  Jesus turned, and seeing her he said, “Take heart, daughter; your faith has made you well.” And instantly the woman was made well. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 9,20-22</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“I know that you can do all things, and that no purpose of yours can be thwarted. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Job 42,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But the centurion replied, “Lord, I am not worthy to have you come under my roof, but only say the word, and my servant will be healed. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 8,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>5. Sonntag der Passionszeit – Judika (Schaffe mir Recht, Gott! Psalm 43,1)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Even the sparrow finds a home, and the swallow a nest for herself, where she may lay her young, at your altars, O Lord of hosts, my King and my God. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 84,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>As the Father has loved me, so have I loved you. Abide in my love. These things I have spoken to you, that my joy may be in you, and that your joy may be full. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 15,9.11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>my soul waits for the Lord more than watchmen for the morning, more than watchmen for the morning. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 130,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But you, beloved, building yourselves up in your most holy faith and praying in the Holy Spirit, keep yourselves in the love of God, waiting for the mercy of our Lord Jesus Christ that leads to eternal life. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Jude 1,20-21</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Then I will encamp at my house as a guard, so that none shall march to and fro; no oppressor shall again march over them, for now I see with my own eyes. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Zechariah 9,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And I tell you, you are Peter, and on this rock I will build my church, and the gates of hell shall not prevail against it. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 16,18</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I made the earth and created man on it; it was my hands that stretched out the heavens, and I commanded all their host. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 45,12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For by him all things were created, in heaven and on earth, visible and invisible, whether thrones or dominions or rulers or authorities—all things were created through him and for him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Good and upright is the Lord; therefore he instructs sinners in the way. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 25,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Then Peter came up and said to him, “Lord, how often will my brother sin against me, and I forgive him? As many as seven times?” Jesus said to him, “I do not say to you seven times, but seventy-seven times.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 18,21-22</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You who have made me see many troubles and calamities will revive me again; from the depths of the earth you will bring me up again. You will increase my greatness and comfort me again.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 71,20-21</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So it is not the will of my Father who is in heaven that one of these little ones should perish. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 18,14</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>A soft answer turns away wrath, but a harsh word stirs up anger. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 15,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“Blessed are the peacemakers, for they shall be called sons of God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>6. Sonntag der Passionszeit – Palmsonntag</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Look down from your holy habitation, from heaven, and bless your people Israel and the ground that you have given us, as you swore to our fathers, a land flowing with milk and honey.’ </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 26,15</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>He has helped his servant Israel, in remembrance of his mercy, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,54</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Show us your steadfast love, O Lord, and grant us your salvation.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 85,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So also you have sorrow now, but I will see you again, and your hearts will rejoice, and no one will take your joy from you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 16,22</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Let not those who hope in you be put to shame through me, O Lord God of hosts; let not those who seek you be brought to dishonor through me, O God of Israel. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 69,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The God of Israel has spoken; the Rock of Israel has said to me: When one rules justly over men, ruling in the fear of God, he dawns on them like the morning light, like the sun shining forth on a cloudless morning, like rain that makes grass to sprout from the earth. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>2 Samuel 23,3-4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“You are the light of the world. A city set on a hill cannot be hidden. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,14</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Gründonnerstag</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>But the Lord said to Samuel, “Do not look on his appearance or on the height of his stature, because I have rejected him. For the Lord sees not as man sees: man looks on the outward appearance, but the Lord looks on the heart.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 16,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And the Lord turned and looked at Peter. And Peter remembered the saying of the Lord, how he had said to him, “Before the rooster crows today, you will deny me three times.” And he went out and wept bitterly.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 22,61-62</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Karfreitag</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>The name of the second he called Ephraim, “For God has made me fruitful in the land of my affliction.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 41,52</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And he said, “Jesus, remember me when you come into your kingdom.” And he said to him, “Truly, I say to you, today you will be with me in paradise.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 23,42-43</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“Hear, O Israel: The Lord our God, the Lord is one. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 6,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And this is eternal life, that they know you, the only true God, and Jesus Christ whom you have sent. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 17,3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Osterfest</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>“Woe to him who strives with him who formed him, a pot among earthen pots! Does the clay say to him who forms it, ‘What are you making?’ or ‘Your work has no handles’? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 45,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Therefore, if anyone is in Christ, he is a new creation. The old has passed away; behold, the new has come. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 5,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Ostermontag</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>It shall come to pass in the latter days that the mountain of the house of the Lord shall be established as the highest of the mountains, and shall be lifted up above the hills; and all the nations shall flow to it, He shall judge between the nations, and shall decide disputes for many peoples; and they shall beat their swords into plowshares, and their spears into pruning hooks; nation shall not lift up sword against nation, neither shall they learn war anymore. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 2,2.4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Jesus said to them again, “Peace be with you. As the Father has sent me, even so I am sending you.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 20,21</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For the Lord will vindicate his people and have compassion on his servants, when he sees that their power is gone and there is none remaining, bond or free. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 32,36</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>I tell you, he will give justice to them speedily. Nevertheless, when the Son of Man comes, will he find faith on earth?” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 18,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>But my eyes are toward you, O God, my Lord; in you I seek refuge; leave me not defenseless! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 141,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>When he had said this, he showed them his hands and his side. Then the disciples were glad when they saw the Lord. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 20,20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Satisfy us in the morning with your steadfast love, that we may rejoice and be glad all our days. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 90,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us in Christ with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 1,3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Why do you spend your money for that which is not bread, and your labor for that which does not satisfy? Listen diligently to me, and eat what is good, and delight yourselves in rich food. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 55,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Do not work for the food that perishes, but for the food that endures to eternal life, which the Son of Man will give to you. For on him God the Father has set his seal.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 6,27</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Then I proclaimed a fast there, at the river Ahava, that we might humble ourselves before our God, to seek from him a safe journey for ourselves, our children, and all our goods. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezra 8,21</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Jesus said to him, “I am the way, and the truth, and the life. No one comes to the Father except through me. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 14,6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>1. Sonntag nach Ostern – Quasimodogeniti (Wie die neugeborenen Kindlein. 1.Petrus 2,2)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>“See now that I, even I, am he, and there is no god beside me; I kill and I make alive; I wound and I heal; and there is none that can deliver out of my hand. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 32,39</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Again I tell you, it is easier for a camel to go through the eye of a needle than for a rich person to enter the kingdom of God.” When the disciples heard this, they were greatly astonished, saying, “Who then can be saved?”  But Jesus looked at them and said, “With man this is impossible, but with God all things are possible.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 19,24-26</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For God will bring every deed into judgment, with every secret thing, whether good or evil. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ecclesiastes 12,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-04-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You shall not wrong one another, but you shall fear your God, for I am the Lord your God. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Leviticus 25,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For I have given you an example, that you also should do just as I have done to you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 13,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>So I saw that there is nothing better than that a man should rejoice in his work, for that is his lot. Who can bring him to see what will be after him? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ecclesiastes 3,22</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>giving thanks to the Father, who has qualified you to share in the inheritance of the saints in light. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“You shall stand up before the gray head and honor the face of an old man, and you shall fear your God: I am the Lord. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Leviticus 19,32</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Do nothing from selfish ambition or conceit, but in humility count others more significant than yourselves. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>As a pleasing aroma I will accept you, when I bring you out from the peoples and gather you out of the countries where you have been scattered. And I will manifest my holiness among you in the sight of the nations. And you shall know that I am the Lord, when I bring you into the land of Israel, the country that I swore to give to your fathers. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 20,41.42</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>teaching them to observe all that I have commanded you. And behold, I am with you always, to the end of the age.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 28,20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>With God we shall do valiantly; it is he who will tread down our foes.</Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 60,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And whatever you do, in word or deed, do everything in the name of the Lord Jesus, giving thanks to God the Father through him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 3,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>2. Sonntag nach Ostern – Miserikordias Domini (Die Erde ist voll der Güte des HERRN. Psalm 33,5)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Thus the Lord used to speak to Moses face to face, as a man speaks to his friend. When Moses turned again into the camp, his assistant Joshua the son of Nun, a young man, would not depart from the tent. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 33,11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>They said to each other, “Did not our hearts burn within us while he talked to us on the road, while he opened to us the Scriptures?” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 24,32</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>They shall ask the way to Zion, with faces turned toward it, saying, ‘Come, let us join ourselves to the Lord in an everlasting covenant that will never be forgotten.’ </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 50,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Simon Peter answered him, “Lord, to whom shall we go? You have the words of eternal life, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 6,68</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And David was greatly distressed, for the people spoke of stoning him, because all the people were bitter in soul, each for his sons and daughters. But David strengthened himself in the Lord his God. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 30,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>I thank my God always when I remember you in my prayers, and I pray that the sharing of your faith may become effective for the full knowledge of every good thing that is in us for the sake of Christ. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philemon 1,4.6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>and in the wilderness, where you have seen how the Lord your God carried you, as a man carries his son, all the way that you went until you came to this place.’ </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 1,31</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So we have come to know and to believe the love that God has for us. God is love, and whoever abides in love abides in God, and God abides in him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1. John 4,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I was mute and silent; I held my peace to no avail, and my distress grew worse. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 39,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Know this, my beloved brothers: let every person be quick to hear, slow to speak, slow to anger; </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 1,19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord, the God of heaven, who took me from my father’s house and from the land of my kindred, and who spoke to me and swore to me, ‘To your offspring I will give this land,’ he will send his angel before you, and you shall take a wife for my son from there. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 24,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But the angel said to the women, “Do not be afraid, for I know that you seek Jesus who was crucified.  Then go quickly and tell his disciples that he has risen from the dead, and behold, he is going before you to Galilee; there you will see him. See, I have told you.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 28,5.7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>the Lord lift up his countenance upon you and give you peace. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Numbers 6,26</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>3. Sonntag nach Ostern – Jubilate (Jauchzet Gott, alle Lande! Psalm 66,1)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>The Lord is good, a stronghold in the day of trouble; he knows those who take refuge in him. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Nahum 1,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>We are afflicted in every way, but not crushed; perplexed, but not driven to despair; </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 4,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For from the rising of the sun to its setting my name will be great among the nations, and in every place incense will be offered to my name, and a pure offering. For my name will be great among the nations, says the Lord of hosts. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Malachi 1,11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>and every tongue confess that Jesus Christ is Lord, to the glory of God the Father. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord repay you for what you have done, and a full reward be given you by the Lord, the God of Israel, under whose wings you have come to take refuge!” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ruth 2,12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>I commend to you our sister Phoebe, a servant of the church at Cenchreae, that you may welcome her in the Lord in a way worthy of the saints, and help her in whatever she may need from you, for she has been a patron of many and of myself as well. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 16,1-2</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For our transgressions are multiplied before you, and our sins testify against us; for our transgressions are with us, and we know our iniquities:  transgressing, and denying the Lord, and turning back from following our God, speaking oppression and revolt, conceiving and uttering from the heart lying words. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 59,12-13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1. John 1,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>This also comes from the Lord of hosts; he is wonderful in counsel and excellent in wisdom. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 28,29</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Jesus said to them, “Have you never read in the Scriptures: “‘The stone that the builders rejected has become the cornerstone; this was the Lord’s doing, and it is marvelous in our eyes’? </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 21,42</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For he will command his angels concerning you to guard you in all your ways. On their hands they will bear you up, lest you strike your foot against a stone. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 91,11-12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Are they not all ministering spirits sent out to serve for the sake of those who are to inherit salvation? </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 1,14</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And all that generation also were gathered to their fathers. And there arose another generation after them who did not know the Lord or the work that he had done for Israel.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Judges 2,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Remember Jesus Christ, risen from the dead, the offspring of David, as preached in my gospel, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>4. Sonntag nach Ostern – Kantate (Singet dem HERRN ein neues Lied! Psalm 98,1)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Does not he see my ways and number all my steps? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Job 31,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And no creature is hidden from his sight, but all are naked and exposed to the eyes of him to whom we must give account. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 4,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>He is your praise. He is your God, who has done for you these great and terrifying things that your eyes have seen. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 10,21</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>I am the Alpha and the Omega, the first and the last, the beginning and the end.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 22,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I hate those who pay regard to worthless idols, but I trust in the Lord. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 31,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For the law of the Spirit of life has set you free in Christ Jesus from the law of sin and death. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,2</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>It will be said on that day, “Behold, this is our God; we have waited for him, that he might save us. This is the Lord; we have waited for him; let us be glad and rejoice in his salvation.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 25,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“Blessed be the Lord God of Israel, for he has visited and redeemed his people </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,68</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Your words were found, and I ate them, and your words became to me a joy and the delight of my heart, for I am called by your name, O Lord, God of hosts. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 15,16</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But he said, “Blessed rather are those who hear the word of God and keep it!” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 11,28</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>God is not man, that he should lie, or a son of man, that he should change his mind. Has he said, and will he not do it? Or has he spoken, and will he not fulfill it? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Numbers 23,19</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>He is the radiance of the glory of God and the exact imprint of his nature, and he upholds the universe by the word of his power. After making purification for sins, he sat down at the right hand of the Majesty on high, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 1,3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Raise a song; sound the tambourine, the sweet lyre with the harp. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 81,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>What am I to do? I will pray with my spirit, but I will pray with my mind also; I will sing praise with my spirit, but I will sing with my mind also. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 14,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>5. Sonntag nach Ostern – Rogate (Betet!)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>I love the Lord, because he has heard my voice and my pleas for mercy. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 116,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But when you pray, go into your room and shut the door and pray to your Father who is in secret. And your Father who sees in secret will reward you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Great salvation he brings to his king, and shows steadfast love to his anointed, to David and his offspring forever. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 18,50</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>for we cannot but speak of what we have seen and heard.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 4,20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Oh come, let us sing to the Lord; let us make a joyful noise to the rock of our salvation! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 95,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And day by day, attending the temple together and breaking bread in their homes, they received their food with glad and generous hearts, praising God and having favor with all the people. And the Lord added to their number day by day those who were being saved. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 2,46-47</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The counsel of the Lord stands forever, the plans of his heart to all generations. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 33,11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And now I commend you to God and to the word of his grace, which is able to build you up and to give you the inheritance among all those who are sanctified. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 20,32</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Christi Himmelfahrt</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>For you will not abandon my soul to Sheol, or let your holy one see corruption. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 16,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Consequently, he is able to save to the uttermost those who draw near to God through him, since he always lives to make intercession for them. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 7,25</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-05-3100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>So even to old age and gray hairs, O God, do not forsake me, until I proclaim your might to another generation, your power to all those to come. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 71,18</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So we do not lose heart. Though our outer self is wasting away, our inner self is being renewed day by day. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 4,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Great are the works of the Lord, studied by all who delight in them. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 111,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>that the God of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of glory, may give you the Spirit of wisdom and of revelation in the knowledge of him, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 1,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>6. Sonntag nach Ostern – Exaudi (HERR, höre meine Stimme! Psalm 27,7)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Know that the Lord, he is God! It is he who made us, and we are his; we are his people, and the sheep of his pasture. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 100,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>You did not choose me, but I chose you and appointed you that you should go and bear fruit and that your fruit should abide, so that whatever you ask the Father in my name, he may give it to you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 15,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Restore us to yourself, O Lord, that we may be restored! Renew our days as of old— </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Lamentations 5,21</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And I will ask the Father, and he will give you another Helper, to be with you forever, even the Spirit of truth, whom the world cannot receive, because it neither sees him nor knows him. You know him, for he dwells with you and will be in you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 14,16-17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord will fight for you, and you have only to be silent.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 14,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>No, in all these things we are more than conquerors through him who loved us. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,37</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For thus said the Lord God, the Holy One of Israel, “In returning and rest you shall be saved; in quietness and in trust shall be your strength.” But you were unwilling, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 30,15</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And which of you by being anxious can add a single hour to his span of life? </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,27</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And he said to man, ‘Behold, the fear of the Lord, that is wisdom, and to turn away from evil is understanding.’” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Job 28,28</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But if the unbelieving partner separates, let it be so. In such cases the brother or sister is not enslaved. God has called you to peace. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 7,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“Only take care, and keep your soul diligently, lest you forget the things that your eyes have seen, and lest they depart from your heart all the days of your life. Make them known to your children and your children’s children— </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 4,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>I am coming soon. Hold fast what you have, so that no one may seize your crown. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 3,11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For if you return to the Lord, your brothers and your children will find compassion with their captors and return to this land. For the Lord your God is gracious and merciful and will not turn away his face from you, if you return to him.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 30,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Repent therefore, and turn back, that your sins may be blotted out, that times of refreshing may come from the presence of the Lord, and that he may send the Christ appointed for you, Jesus, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 3,19-20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Pfingstfest</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Correct me, O Lord, but in justice; not in your anger, lest you bring me to nothing. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 10,24</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And when he comes, he will convict the world concerning sin and righteousness and judgment: </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 16,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Pfingstmontag</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>The Lord will reign forever and ever.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 15,18</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>As he was drawing near—already on the way down the Mount of Olives—the whole multitude of his disciples began to rejoice and praise God with a loud voice for all the mighty works that they had seen, saying, “Blessed is the King who comes in the name of the Lord! Peace in heaven and glory in the highest!” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 19,37-38</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>the Lord—knows the thoughts of man, that they are but a breath. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 94,11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>that I may know him and the power of his resurrection, and may share his sufferings, becoming like him in his death, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 3,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>and I will set a sign among them. And from them I will send survivors to the nations, to Tarshish, Pul, and Lud, who draw the bow, to Tubal and Javan, to the coastlands far away, that have not heard my fame or seen my glory. And they shall declare my glory among the nations. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 66,19</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And Jesus came and said to them, “All authority in heaven and on earth has been given to me. Go therefore and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit, teaching them to observe all that I have commanded you. And behold, I am with you always, to the end of the age.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 28,18-20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>See, this alone I found, that God made man upright, but they have sought out many schemes. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ecclesiastes 7,29</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>You will recognize them by their fruits. Are grapes gathered from thornbushes, or figs from thistles? </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 7,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The man gazed at her in silence to learn whether the Lord had prospered his journey or not.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 24,21</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For you have need of endurance, so that when you have done the will of God you may receive what is promised. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 10,36</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>O Lord, open my lips, and my mouth will declare your praise.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 51,15</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>who desires all people to be saved and to come to the knowledge of the truth. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 2,4</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Trinitatis (Dreieinigkeit)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>But for me it is good to be near God; I have made the Lord God my refuge, that I may tell of all your works. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 73,28</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But you are a chosen race, a royal priesthood, a holy nation, a people for his own possession, that you may proclaim the excellencies of him who called you out of darkness into his marvelous light. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“For as the rain and the snow come down from heaven and do not return there but water the earth, making it bring forth and sprout, giving seed to the sower and bread to the eater, so shall my word be that goes out from my mouth; it shall not return to me empty, but it shall accomplish that which I purpose, and shall succeed in the thing for which I sent it. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 55,10-11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>and my speech and my message were not in plausible words of wisdom, but in demonstration of the Spirit and of power, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 2,4</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Then the Lord put out his hand and touched my mouth. And the Lord said to me, “Behold, I have put my words in your mouth. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 1,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Settle it therefore in your minds not to meditate beforehand how to answer, for I will give you a mouth and wisdom, which none of your adversaries will be able to withstand or contradict. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 21,14-15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>he will bless those who fear the Lord, both the small and the great. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 115,13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>for in Christ Jesus you are all sons of God, through faith. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Galatians 3,26</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>even to your old age I am he, and to gray hairs I will carry you. I have made, and I will bear; I will carry and will save. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 46,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>God is faithful, by whom you were called into the fellowship of his Son, Jesus Christ our Lord. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 1,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Out of them shall come songs of thanksgiving, and the voices of those who celebrate. I will multiply them, and they shall not be few; I will make them honored, and they shall not be small. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 30,19</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>He told them another parable. “The kingdom of heaven is like leaven that a woman took and hid in three measures of flour, till it was all leavened.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 13,33</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>When I look at your heavens, the work of your fingers, the moon and the stars, which you have set in place, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 8,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>and said to them, “Whoever receives this child in my name receives me, and whoever receives me receives him who sent me. For he who is least among you all is the one who is great.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 9,48</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>1. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>I prayed to the Lord my God and made confession, saying, “O Lord, the great and awesome God, who keeps covenant and steadfast love with those who love him and keep his commandments, we have sinned and done wrong and acted wickedly and rebelled, turning aside from your commandments and rules. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Daniel 9,4-5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Now the law came in to increase the trespass, but where sin increased, grace abounded all the more, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Johannistag</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>But he said to her, “You speak as one of the foolish women would speak. Shall we receive good from God, and shall we not receive evil?” In all this Job did not sin with his lips. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Job 2,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>saying, “Father, if you are willing, remove this cup from me. Nevertheless, not my will, but yours, be done.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 22,42</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For a brief moment I deserted you, but with great compassion I will gather you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 54,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“I will not leave you as orphans; I will come to you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 14,18</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For my life is spent with sorrow, and my years with sighing; my strength fails because of my iniquity, and my bones waste away. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 31,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Why, even the hairs of your head are all numbered. Fear not; you are of more value than many sparrows. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 12,7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“You have heard; now see all this; and will you not declare it? From this time forth I announce to you new things, hidden things that you have not known. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 48,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>making known to us the mystery of his will, according to his purpose, which he set forth in Christ </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 1,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And the Lord drove out before us all the peoples, the Amorites who lived in the land. Therefore we also will serve the Lord, for he is our God.”  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Joshua 24,18</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>so we, though many, are one body in Christ, and individually members one of another. Having gifts that differ according to the grace given to us, let us use them: if prophecy, in proportion to our faith; </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,5-6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I will punish you according to the fruit of your deeds, declares the Lord; I will kindle a fire in her forest, and it shall devour all that is around her.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 21,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And let us not grow weary of doing good, for in due season we will reap, if we do not give up. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Galatians 6,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-06-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>2. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>You shall serve the Lord your God, and he will bless your bread and your water, and I will take sickness away from among you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 23,25</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Therefore do not be anxious, saying, ‘What shall we eat?’ or ‘What shall we drink?’ or ‘What shall we wear?’  For the Gentiles seek after all these things, and your heavenly Father knows that you need them all. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,31.32</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Search me, O God, and know my heart! Try me and know my thoughts! And see if there be any grievous way in me, and lead me in the way everlasting! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 139,23-24</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Who is wise and understanding among you? By his good conduct let him show his works in the meekness of wisdom. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 3,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Do not let my heart incline to any evil, to busy myself with wicked deeds in company with men who work iniquity, and let me not eat of their delicacies! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 141,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Do not be overcome by evil, but overcome evil with good.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,21</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>So teach us to number our days that we may get a heart of wisdom. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 90,12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“Everyone then who hears these words of mine and does them will be like a wise man who built his house on the rock. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 7,24</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Restore us, O Lord God of hosts! Let your face shine, that we may be saved!</Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 80,19</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Now may our Lord Jesus Christ himself, and God our Father, who loved us and gave us eternal comfort and good hope through grace, comfort your hearts and establish them in every good work and word. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 2,16-17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>To the choirmaster. A Psalm of David. O Lord, you have searched me and known me! You know when I sit down and when I rise up; you discern my thoughts from afar. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 139,1-2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>for “‘In him we live and move and have our being’; as even some of your own poets have said, “‘For we are indeed his offspring.’ </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 17,28</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I will feast the soul of the priests with abundance, and my people shall be satisfied with my goodness, declares the Lord.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Heal the sick, raise the dead, cleanse lepers, cast out demons. You received without paying; give without pay. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 10,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>3. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Seek the Lord, all you humble of the land, who do his just commands; seek righteousness; seek humility; perhaps you may be hidden on the day of the anger of the Lord. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Zephaniah 2,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“Blessed are those who hunger and thirst for righteousness, for they shall be satisfied. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For whoever has despised the day of small things shall rejoice, and shall see the plumb line in the hand of Zerubbabel. “These seven are the eyes of the Lord, which range through the whole earth.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Zechariah 4,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>He put another parable before them, saying, “The kingdom of heaven is like a grain of mustard seed that a man took and sowed in his field. It is the smallest of all seeds, but when it has grown it is larger than all the garden plants and becomes a tree, so that the birds of the air come and make nests in its branches.”  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 13,31-32</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For thus says the Lord to the house of Israel: “Seek me and live; </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Amos 5,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>While you have the light, believe in the light, that you may become sons of light.” When Jesus had said these things, he departed and hid himself from them. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 12,36</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>and it was the duty of the trumpeters and singers to make themselves heard in unison in praise and thanksgiving to the Lord), and when the song was raised, with trumpets and cymbals and other musical instruments, in praise to the Lord, “For he is good, for his steadfast love endures forever,” the house, the house of the Lord, was filled with a cloud, so that the priests could not stand to minister because of the cloud, for the glory of the Lord filled the house of God. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 5,13.14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>may have strength to comprehend with all the saints what is the breadth and length and height and depth, and to know the love of Christ that surpasses knowledge, that you may be filled with all the fullness of God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 3,18-19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>He shall judge between the nations, and shall decide disputes for many peoples; and they shall beat their swords into plowshares, and their spears into pruning hooks; nation shall not lift up sword against nation, neither shall they learn war anymore. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 2,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“Glory to God in the highest, and on earth peace among those with whom he is pleased!” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,14</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Now therefore, if you will indeed obey my voice and keep my covenant, you shall be my treasured possession among all peoples, for all the earth is mine; </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 19,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>who saved us and called us to a holy calling, not because of our works but because of his own purpose and grace, which he gave us in Christ Jesus before the ages began, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 1,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Shall not all these take up their taunt against him, with scoffing and riddles for him, and say, “Woe to him who heaps up what is not his own— for how long?— and loads himself with pledges!” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Habbakuk 2,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And he said to them, “Take care, and be on your guard against all covetousness, for one’s life does not consist in the abundance of his possessions.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 12,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>4. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Restore us, O Lord God of hosts! Let your face shine, that we may be saved! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 80,19</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And Jesus said to him, “Recover your sight; your faith has made you well.” And immediately he recovered his sight and followed him, glorifying God. And all the people, when they saw it, gave praise to God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 18,42-43</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You shall walk after the Lord your God and fear him and keep his commandments and obey his voice, and you shall serve him and hold fast to him. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 13,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Not only that, but we rejoice in our sufferings, knowing that suffering produces endurance, and endurance produces character, and character produces hope,  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,3-4</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Let not your mouth lead you into sin, and do not say before the messenger that it was a mistake. Why should God be angry at your voice and destroy the work of your hands? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ecclesiastes 5,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>If any of you lacks wisdom, let him ask God, who gives generously to all without reproach, and it will be given him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 1,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Therefore the Lord has kept ready the calamity and has brought it upon us, for the Lord our God is righteous in all the works that he has done, and we have not obeyed his voice. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Daniel 9,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Every good gift and every perfect gift is from above, coming down from the Father of lights, with whom there is no variation or shadow due to change. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 1,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The Lord is slow to anger and great in power, and the Lord will by no means clear the guilty. His way is in whirlwind and storm, and the clouds are the dust of his feet. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Nahum 1,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And count the patience of our Lord as salvation, just as our beloved brother Paul also wrote to you according to the wisdom given him, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Peter 3,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I hold my life in my hand continually, but I do not forget your law. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 119,109</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And you became imitators of us and of the Lord, for you received the word in much affliction, with the joy of the Holy Spirit, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 1,6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>They shall not hurt or destroy in all my holy mountain; for the earth shall be full of the knowledge of the Lord as the waters cover the sea. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 11,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For in him all the fullness of God was pleased to dwell, and through him to reconcile to himself all things, whether on earth or in heaven, making peace by the blood of his cross. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,19-20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>5. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>For I desire steadfast love and not sacrifice, the knowledge of God rather than burnt offerings. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Hosea 6,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So now faith, hope, and love abide, these three; but the greatest of these is love.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 13,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You keep him in perfect peace whose mind is stayed on you, because he trusts in you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 26,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And we desire each one of you to show the same earnestness to have the full assurance of hope until the end, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 6,11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>A Song of Ascents. Out of the depths I cry to you, O Lord! O Lord, hear my voice! Let your ears be attentive to the voice of my pleas for mercy! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 130,1-2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But immediately Jesus spoke to them, saying, “Take heart; it is I. Do not be afraid.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 14,27</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>But as for me, I will look to the Lord; I will wait for the God of my salvation; my God will hear me. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Micah 7,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>and hope does not put us to shame, because God’s love has been poured into our hearts through the Holy Spirit who has been given to us. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“Where were you when I laid the foundation of the earth? Tell me, if you have understanding. and said, ‘Thus far shall you come, and no farther, and here shall your proud waves be stayed’? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Job 38,4.11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>By faith we understand that the universe was created by the word of God, so that what is seen was not made out of things that are visible. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 11,3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Therefore say to them, Thus declares the Lord of hosts: Return to me, says the Lord of hosts, and I will return to you, says the Lord of hosts. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Zechariah 1,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Go and learn what this means: ‘I desire mercy, and not sacrifice.’ For I came not to call the righteous, but sinners.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 9,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And the ransomed of the Lord shall return and come to Zion with singing; everlasting joy shall be upon their heads; they shall obtain gladness and joy, and sorrow and sighing shall flee away. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 51,11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Then we who are alive, who are left, will be caught up together with them in the clouds to meet the Lord in the air, and so we will always be with the Lord. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 4,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>6. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>For the Lord hears the needy and does not despise his own people who are prisoners. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 69,33</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And she had a sister called Mary, who sat at the Lord’s feet and listened to his teaching. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 10,39</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For this child I prayed, and the Lord has granted me my petition that I made to him. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 1,27</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“Ask, and it will be given to you; seek, and you will find; knock, and it will be opened to you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 7,7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I believe that I shall look upon the goodness of the Lord in the land of the living! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 27,13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And he said to me, “It is done! I am the Alpha and the Omega, the beginning and the end. To the thirsty I will give from the spring of the water of life without payment. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 21,6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-07-3100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>But the Lord is in his holy temple; let all the earth keep silence before him.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Habbakuk 2,20</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>He who has ears to hear, let him hear. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 11,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Deliver my soul from the sword, my precious life from the power of the dog! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 22,20</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>To this day I have had the help that comes from God, and so I stand here testifying both to small and great, saying nothing but what the prophets and Moses said would come to pass: </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 26,22</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>When a man’s ways please the Lord, he makes even his enemies to be at peace with him. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 16,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But love your enemies, and do good, and lend, expecting nothing in return, and your reward will be great, and you will be sons of the Most High, for he is kind to the ungrateful and the evil. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 6,35</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Hear, you who are far off, what I have done; and you who are near, acknowledge my might.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 33,13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>He who did not spare his own Son but gave him up for us all, how will he not also with him graciously give us all things? </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,32</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>7. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>And one called to another and said: “Holy, holy, holy is the Lord of hosts; the whole earth is full of his glory!” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 6,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Then I heard what seemed to be the voice of a great multitude, like the roar of many waters and like the sound of mighty peals of thunder, crying out, “Hallelujah! For the Lord our God the Almighty reigns. Let us rejoice and exult and give him the glory, for the marriage of the Lamb has come, and his Bride has made herself ready; </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 19,6-7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>There is no one who calls upon your name, who rouses himself to take hold of you; for you have hidden your face from us, and have made us melt in the hand of our iniquities. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 64,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For we are his workmanship, created in Christ Jesus for good works, which God prepared beforehand, that we should walk in them. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>He who vindicates me is near. Who will contend with me? Let us stand up together. Who is my adversary? Let him come near to me. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 50,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And when Jesus came to the place, he looked up and said to him, “Zacchaeus, hurry and come down, for I must stay at your house today.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 19,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext> Now muster your troops, O daughter of troops; siege is laid against us; with a rod they strike the judge of Israel on the cheek. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Micah 5,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>God chose what is low and despised in the world, even things that are not, to bring to nothing things that are, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 1,28</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>and said, “O Lord, God of our fathers, are you not God in heaven? You rule over all the kingdoms of the nations. In your hand are power and might, so that none is able to withstand you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 20,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Now to him who is able to do far more abundantly than all that we ask or think, according to the power at work within us, to him be glory in the church and in Christ Jesus throughout all generations, forever and ever. Amen. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 3,20-21</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Then he said to me, “This is the word of the Lord to Zerubbabel: Not by might, nor by power, but by my Spirit, says the Lord of hosts. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Zechariah 4,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For through the Spirit, by faith, we ourselves eagerly wait for the hope of righteousness. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Galatians 5,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“You shall not spread a false report. You shall not join hands with a wicked man to be a malicious witness. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 23,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>for by your words you will be justified, and by your words you will be condemned.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 12,37</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>8. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Therefore the Lord waits to be gracious to you, and therefore he exalts himself to show mercy to you. For the Lord is a God of justice; blessed are all those who wait for him. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 30,18</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>You then, my child, be strengthened by the grace that is in Christ Jesus, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,1</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And they sang responsively, praising and giving thanks to the Lord, “For he is good, for his steadfast love endures forever toward Israel.” And all the people shouted with a great shout when they praised the Lord, because the foundation of the house of the Lord was laid. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezra 3,11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>As he said these things, all his adversaries were put to shame, and all the people rejoiced at all the glorious things that were done by him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 13,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>He makes me lie down in green pastures. He leads me beside still waters. He restores my soul. He leads me in paths of righteousness for his name’s sake. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 23,2-3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>The thief comes only to steal and kill and destroy. I came that they may have life and have it abundantly. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 10,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I said, ‘Surely you will fear me; you will accept correction. Then your dwelling would not be cut off according to all that I have appointed against you.’ But all the more they were eager to make all their deeds corrupt. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Zephaniah 3,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>From that time Jesus began to preach, saying, “Repent, for the kingdom of heaven is at hand.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 4,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>How beautiful upon the mountains are the feet of him who brings good news, who publishes peace, who brings good news of happiness, who publishes salvation, who says to Zion, “Your God reigns.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 52,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Whatever house you enter, first say, ‘Peace be to this house!’ </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 10,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I, the Lord, am its keeper; every moment I water it. Lest anyone punish it, I keep it night and day;  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 27,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But God’s firm foundation stands, bearing this seal: “The Lord knows those who are his,” and, “Let everyone who names the name of the Lord depart from iniquity.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>So Moses and Aaron went in to Pharaoh and said to him, “Thus says the Lord, the God of the Hebrews, ‘How long will you refuse to humble yourself before me? Let my people go, that they may serve me. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 10,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Submit yourselves therefore to God. Resist the devil, and he will flee from you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 4,7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>9. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Commit your way to the Lord; trust in him, and he will act. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 37,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And I am sure of this, that he who began a good work in you will bring it to completion at the day of Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 1,6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Rejoice greatly, O daughter of Zion! Shout aloud, O daughter of Jerusalem! Behold, your king is coming to you; righteous and having salvation is he, humble and mounted on a donkey, on a colt, the foal of a donkey. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Zechariah 9,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>even as the Son of Man came not to be served but to serve, and to give his life as a ransom for many.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 20,28</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For every boot of the tramping warrior in battle tumult and every garment rolled in blood will be burned as fuel for the fire. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 9,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>He said to them, “But who do you say that I am?”  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 16,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I will bear the indignation of the Lord because I have sinned against him, until he pleads my cause and executes judgment for me. He will bring me out to the light; I shall look upon his vindication. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Micah 7,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Humble yourselves before the Lord, and he will exalt you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 4,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>By oppression and judgment he was taken away; and as for his generation, who considered that he was cut off out of the land of the living, stricken for the transgression of my people? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 53,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Consider him who endured from sinners such hostility against himself, so that you may not grow weary or fainthearted. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 12,3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Yours, O Lord, is the greatness and the power and the glory and the victory and the majesty, for all that is in the heavens and in the earth is yours. Yours is the kingdom, O Lord, and you are exalted as head above all. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 29,11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“Worthy are you, our Lord and God, to receive glory and honor and power, for you created all things, and by your will they existed and were created.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Revelation 4,11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You will seek me and find me, when you seek me with all your heart. I will be found by you, declares the Lord, and I will restore your fortunes and gather you from all the nations and all the places where I have driven you, declares the Lord, and I will bring you back to the place from which I sent you into exile. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 29,13-14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Set your minds on things that are above, not on things that are on earth. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 3,2</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>10. Sonntag nach Trinitatis (Israelsonntag)</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>And the surviving remnant of the house of Judah shall again take root downward and bear fruit upward. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>2 Kings 19,30</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>If the dough offered as firstfruits is holy, so is the whole lump, and if the root is holy, so are the branches. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 11,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Thus says the Lord: “In a time of favor I have answered you; in a day of salvation I have helped you; I will keep you and give you as a covenant to the people, to establish the land, to apportion the desolate heritages, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 49,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For there is no distinction between Jew and Greek; for the same Lord is Lord of all, bestowing his riches on all who call on him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 10,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“Behold, I send my messenger, and he will prepare the way before me. And the Lord whom you seek will suddenly come to his temple; and the messenger of the covenant in whom you delight, behold, he is coming, says the Lord of hosts. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Malachi 3,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And the angel said to them, “Fear not, for behold, I bring you good news of great joy that will be for all the people. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>But Moses said to God, “Who am I that I should go to Pharaoh and bring the children of Israel out of Egypt?” He said, “But I will be with you, and this shall be the sign for you, that I have sent you: when you have brought the people out of Egypt, you shall serve God on this mountain.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 3,11-12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But he said to me, “My grace is sufficient for you, for my power is made perfect in weakness.” Therefore I will boast all the more gladly of my weaknesses, so that the power of Christ may rest upon me. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 12,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The fear of the Lord is instruction in wisdom, and humility comes before honor. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 15,33</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>If anyone imagines that he knows something, he does not yet know as he ought to know. But if anyone loves God, he is known by God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 8,2-3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Who knows? God may turn and relent and turn from his fierce anger, so that we may not perish.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jonah 3,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>The Lord is not slow to fulfill his promise as some count slowness, but is patient toward you, not wishing that any should perish, but that all should reach repentance. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Peter 3,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-08-3100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Our help is in the name of the Lord, who made heaven and earth. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 124,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Do not be like them, for your Father knows what you need before you ask him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>11. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Give thanks to the Lord of lords, for his steadfast love endures forever; to him who alone does great wonders, for his steadfast love endures forever; </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 136,3.4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Thanks be to God for his inexpressible gift! </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 9,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And he said, “I will make all my goodness pass before you and will proclaim before you my name ‘The Lord.’ And I will be gracious to whom I will be gracious, and will show mercy on whom I will show mercy. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 33,19</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>the righteousness of God through faith in Jesus Christ for all who believe. For there is no distinction: for all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God, and are justified by his grace as a gift, through the redemption that is in Christ Jesus, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 3,22-24</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I will wait for the Lord, who is hiding his face from the house of Jacob, and I will hope in him. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 8,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So we are always of good courage. We know that while we are at home in the body we are away from the Lord, for we walk by faith, not by sight. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 5,6-7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>things that we have heard and known, that our fathers have told us. We will not hide them from their children, but tell to the coming generation the glorious deeds of the Lord, and his might, and the wonders that he has done. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 78,3-4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Nor do people light a lamp and put it under a basket, but on a stand, and it gives light to all in the house. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Let the heavens be glad, and let the earth rejoice, and let them say among the nations, “The Lord reigns!” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 16,31</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>so that at the name of Jesus every knee should bow, in heaven and on earth and under the earth, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>A Song of Ascents. Of David. Behold, how good and pleasant it is when brothers dwell in unity! It is like the dew of Hermon, which falls on the mountains of Zion! For there the Lord has commanded the blessing, life forevermore. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 133,1.3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Love one another with brotherly affection. Outdo one another in showing honor. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“Behold, his soul is puffed up; it is not upright within him, but the righteous shall live by his faith. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Habbakuk 2,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Take my yoke upon you, and learn from me, for I am gentle and lowly in heart, and you will find rest for your souls. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 11,29</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>12. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Behold my servant, whom I uphold, my chosen, in whom my soul delights; I have put my Spirit upon him; he will bring forth justice to the nations. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 42,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Then Pilate said to him, “So you are a king?” Jesus answered, “You say that I am a king. For this purpose I was born and for this purpose I have come into the world—to bear witness to the truth. Everyone who is of the truth listens to my voice.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 18,37</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“O my people, what have I done to you? How have I wearied you? Answer me! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Micah 6,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And he said to him, ‘Son, you are always with me, and all that is mine is yours. It was fitting to celebrate and be glad, for this your brother was dead, and is alive; he was lost, and is found.’” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 15,31-32</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>O Lord of hosts, blessed is the one who trusts in you! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 84,12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And my God will supply every need of yours according to his riches in glory in Christ Jesus. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You shall not pervert justice. You shall not show partiality, and you shall not accept a bribe, for a bribe blinds the eyes of the wise and subverts the cause of the righteous. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 16,19</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But God’s firm foundation stands, bearing this seal: “The Lord knows those who are his,” and, “Let everyone who names the name of the Lord depart from iniquity.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Answer me, O Lord, answer me, that this people may know that you, O Lord, are God, and that you have turned their hearts back.”  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers> 1 Kings 18,37</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And it is my prayer that your love may abound more and more, with knowledge and all discernment, so that you may approve what is excellent, and so be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 1,9-10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“Why is light given to him who is in misery, and life to the bitter in soul, who long for death, but it comes not, and dig for it more than for hidden treasures, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Job 3,20-21</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For because he himself has suffered when tempted, he is able to help those who are being tempted. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 2,18</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And I will set up over them one shepherd, my servant David, and he shall feed them: he shall feed them and be their shepherd. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 34,23</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>I am the good shepherd. I know my own and my own know me, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 10,14</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>13. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>The Lord is my rock and my fortress and my deliverer, my God, my rock, in whom I take refuge, my shield, and the horn of my salvation, my stronghold. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 18,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And behold, a woman of the city, who was a sinner, when she learned that he was reclining at table in the Pharisee’s house, brought an alabaster flask of ointment, and standing behind him at his feet, weeping, she began to wet his feet with her tears and wiped them with the hair of her head and kissed his feet and anointed them with the ointment. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 7,37.38</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Seek good, and not evil, that you may live; and so the Lord, the God of hosts, will be with you, as you have said. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Amos 5,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Have this mind among yourselves, which is yours in Christ Jesus, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>But where are your gods that you made for yourself? Let them arise, if they can save you, in your time of trouble; for as many as your cities are your gods, O Judah. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 2,28</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And he said to them, “Why are you afraid, O you of little faith?” Then he rose and rebuked the winds and the sea, and there was a great calm. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 8,26</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>In the way of your testimonies I delight as much as in all riches. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 119,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And he said to them, “Therefore every scribe who has been trained for the kingdom of heaven is like a master of a house, who brings out of his treasure what is new and what is old.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 13,52</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And the Lord went before them by day in a pillar of cloud to lead them along the way, and by night in a pillar of fire to give them light, that they might travel by day and by night. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 13,21</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Therefore we must pay much closer attention to what we have heard, lest we drift away from it.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 2,1</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The meek shall obtain fresh joy in the Lord, and the poor among mankind shall exult in the Holy One of Israel. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 29,19</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And when the Pharisees saw this, they said to his disciples, “Why does your teacher eat with tax collectors and sinners?” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 9,11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Then he said, “I am God, the God of your father. Do not be afraid to go down to Egypt, for there I will make you into a great nation. I myself will go down with you to Egypt, and I will also bring you up again, and Joseph’s hand shall close your eyes.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 46,3.4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Therefore lift your drooping hands and strengthen your weak knees, and make straight paths for your feet, so that what is lame may not be put out of joint but rather be healed. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 12,12-13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>14. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Lead me in your truth and teach me, for you are the God of my salvation; for you I wait all the day long. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 25,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Neither be called instructors, for you have one instructor, the Christ. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 23,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The bows of the mighty are broken, but the feeble bind on strength. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 2,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>but as servants of God we commend ourselves in every way: by great endurance, in afflictions, hardships, calamities, by truthful speech, and the power of God; with the weapons of righteousness for the right hand and for the left; </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 6,4.7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I will give them a heart to know that I am the Lord, and they shall be my people and I will be their God, for they shall return to me with their whole heart. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 24,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And it is God who establishes us with you in Christ, and has anointed us, and who has also put his seal on us and given us his Spirit in our hearts as a guarantee. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,21-22</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Justice, and only justice, you shall follow, that you may live and inherit the land that the Lord your God is giving you.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 16,20</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>if indeed you continue in the faith, stable and steadfast, not shifting from the hope of the gospel that you heard, which has been proclaimed in all creation under heaven, and of which I, Paul, became a minister. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,23</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>In the fear of the Lord one has strong confidence, and his children will have a refuge. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 14,26</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>which is why I suffer as I do. But I am not ashamed, for I know whom I have believed, and I am convinced that he is able to guard until that day what has been entrusted to me. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 1,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>also that everyone should eat and drink and take pleasure in all his toil—this is God’s gift to man. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ecclesiastes 3,13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Give us this day our daily bread, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>But you, O God, will cast them down into the pit of destruction; men of blood and treachery shall not live out half their days. But I will trust in you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 55,23</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Therefore do not throw away your confidence, which has a great reward. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 10,35</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>15. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>The king is not saved by his great army; a warrior is not delivered by his great strength. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 33,16</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But when Herod died, behold, an angel of the Lord appeared in a dream to Joseph in Egypt,  saying, “Rise, take the child and his mother and go to the land of Israel, for those who sought the child’s life are dead.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 2,19-20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-09-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Then my enemies will turn back in the day when I call. This I know, that God is for me. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 56,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of mercies and God of all comfort, who comforts us in all our affliction, so that we may be able to comfort those who are in any affliction, with the comfort with which we ourselves are comforted by God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,3-4</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I must perform my vows to you, O God; I will render thank offerings to you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 56,12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>I can do all things through him who strengthens me. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Now when Job’s three friends heard of all this evil that had come upon him, they came each from his own place, Eliphaz the Temanite, Bildad the Shuhite, and Zophar the Naamathite. They made an appointment together to come to show him sympathy and comfort him. And they sat with him on the ground seven days and seven nights, and no one spoke a word to him, for they saw that his suffering was very great. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Job 2,11.13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Love bears all things, believes all things, hopes all things, endures all things. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 13,7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And in the days of those kings the God of heaven will set up a kingdom that shall never be destroyed, nor shall the kingdom be left to another people. It shall break in pieces all these kingdoms and bring them to an end, and it shall stand forever, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Daniel 2,44</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And Asa went out to meet him, and they drew up their lines of battle in the Valley of Zephathah at Mareshah. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 14,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But he said to me, “My grace is sufficient for you, for my power is made perfect in weakness.” Therefore I will boast all the more gladly of my weaknesses, so that the power of Christ may rest upon me. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 12,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>declaring the end from the beginning and from ancient times things not yet done, saying, ‘My counsel shall stand, and I will accomplish all my purpose,’ </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 46,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So the last will be first, and the first last.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 20,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Erntedankfest</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>The latter glory of this house shall be greater than the former, says the Lord of hosts. And in this place I will give peace, declares the Lord of hosts.’” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Haggai 2,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>What you have learned and received and heard and seen in me—practice these things, and the God of peace will be with you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>He said, “The Lord is my rock and my fortress and my deliverer, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>2 Samuel 22,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>He delivered us from such a deadly peril, and he will deliver us. On him we have set our hope that he will deliver us again. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Those who look to him are radiant, and their faces shall never be ashamed. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 34,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“Or what woman, having ten silver coins, if she loses one coin, does not light a lamp and sweep the house and seek diligently until she finds it?  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 15,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Then let us arise and go up to Bethel, so that I may make there an altar to the God who answers me in the day of my distress and has been with me wherever I have gone.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 35,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>giving thanks always and for everything to God the Father in the name of our Lord Jesus Christ, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I will be like the dew to Israel; he shall blossom like the lily; he shall take root like the trees of Lebanon; </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Hosea 14,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And have mercy on those who doubt;  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Jude 1,22</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Woe to those who go down to Egypt for help and rely on horses, who trust in chariots because they are many and in horsemen because they are very strong, but do not look to the Holy One of Israel or consult the Lord! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 31,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Not that we are sufficient in ourselves to claim anything as coming from us, but our sufficiency is from God, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 3,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Mightier than the thunders of many waters, mightier than the waves of the sea, the Lord on high is mighty! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 93,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>He said to them, “Where is your faith?” And they were afraid, and they marveled, saying to one another, “Who then is this, that he commands even winds and water, and they obey him?” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 8,25</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>17. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>He changes times and seasons; he removes kings and sets up kings; he gives wisdom to the wise and knowledge to those who have understanding; </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Daniel 2,21</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But the wisdom from above is first pure, then peaceable, gentle, open to reason, full of mercy and good fruits, impartial and sincere. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 3,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And I will deliver you from all your uncleannesses. And I will summon the grain and make it abundant and lay no famine upon you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 36,29</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>There is therefore now no condemnation for those who are in Christ Jesus.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,1</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>he says: “It is too light a thing that you should be my servant to raise up the tribes of Jacob and to bring back the preserved of Israel; I will make you as a light for the nations, that my salvation may reach to the end of the earth.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 49,6</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Therefore God has highly exalted him and bestowed on him the name that is above every name, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>But he said to them, “Do not delay me, since the Lord has prospered my way. Send me away that I may go to my master.”  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 24,56</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>As Jesus passed on from there, he saw a man called Matthew sitting at the tax booth, and he said to him, “Follow me.” And he rose and followed him. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 9,9</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And if you make a sale to your neighbor or buy from your neighbor, you shall not wrong one another. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Leviticus 25,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“So whatever you wish that others would do to you, do also to them, for this is the Law and the Prophets. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 7,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Whoever pursues righteousness and kindness will find life, righteousness, and honor. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 21,21</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For the kingdom of God is not a matter of eating and drinking but of righteousness and peace and joy in the Holy Spirit. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 14,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Put them in fear, O Lord! Let the nations know that they are but men! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 9,20</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>I do not ask that you take them out of the world, but that you keep them from the evil one. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 17,15</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>18. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>I will make with them an everlasting covenant, that I will not turn away from doing good to them. And I will put the fear of me in their hearts, that they may not turn from me. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 32,40</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So then it depends not on human will or exertion, but on God, who has mercy.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 9,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“Son of man, prophesy against the shepherds of Israel; prophesy, and say to them, even to the shepherds, Thus says the Lord God: Ah, shepherds of Israel who have been feeding yourselves! Should not shepherds feed the sheep? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 34,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Let each of you look not only to his own interests, but also to the interests of others. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,4</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Then Elijah said to all the people, “Come near to me.” And all the people came near to him. And he repaired the altar of the Lord that had been thrown down. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers> 1 Kings 18,30</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So then let us pursue what makes for peace and for mutual upbuilding. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 14,19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>A merchant, in whose hands are false balances, he loves to oppress. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Hosea 12,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Therefore put away all filthiness and rampant wickedness and receive with meekness the implanted word, which is able to save your souls. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 1,21</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>you let men ride over our heads; we went through fire and through water; yet you have brought us out to a place of abundance. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 66,12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For everyone who has been born of God overcomes the world. And this is the victory that has overcome the world—our faith. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1. John 5,4</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>God thunders wondrously with his voice; he does great things that we cannot comprehend. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Job 37,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For from him and through him and to him are all things. To him be glory forever. Amen. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 11,36</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For you are a people holy to the Lord your God, and the Lord has chosen you to be a people for his treasured possession, out of all the peoples who are on the face of the earth. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 14,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>since God is one—who will justify the circumcised by faith and the uncircumcised through faith. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 3,30</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>19. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>The Lord makes poor and makes rich; he brings low and he exalts. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 2,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>always carrying in the body the death of Jesus, so that the life of Jesus may also be manifested in our bodies. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 4,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>He shall seduce with flattery those who violate the covenant, but the people who know their God shall stand firm and take action.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Daniel 11,32</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>In the same way, let your light shine before others, so that they may see your good works and give glory to your Father who is in heaven. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>But I with the voice of thanksgiving will sacrifice to you; what I have vowed I will pay. Salvation belongs to the Lord!” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jonah 2,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“No one can serve two masters, for either he will hate the one and love the other, or he will be devoted to the one and despise the other. You cannot serve God and money. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,24</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Remember the wondrous works that he has done, his miracles, and the judgments he uttered, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 105,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Then he ordered the crowds to sit down on the grass, and taking the five loaves and the two fish, he looked up to heaven and said a blessing. Then he broke the loaves and gave them to the disciples, and the disciples gave them to the crowds. And they all ate and were satisfied. And they took up twelve baskets full of the broken pieces left over.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 14,19-20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-10-3100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Reformationstag</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Oh give thanks to the Lord; call upon his name; make known his deeds among the peoples! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 105,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And we have seen and testify that the Father has sent his Son to be the Savior of the world. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1. John 4,14</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For your name’s sake, O Lord, pardon my guilt, for it is great. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 25,11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>In him we have redemption through his blood, the forgiveness of our trespasses, according to the riches of his grace, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 1,7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Whoever goes about slandering reveals secrets, but he who is trustworthy in spirit keeps a thing covered. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 11,13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>O Timothy, guard the deposit entrusted to you. Avoid the irreverent babble and contradictions of what is falsely called “knowledge,” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 6,20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>20. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>The sacrifices of God are a broken spirit; a broken and contrite heart, O God, you will not despise. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 51,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And with great power the apostles were giving their testimony to the resurrection of the Lord Jesus, and great grace was upon them all. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 4,33</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>But the steadfast love of the Lord is from everlasting to everlasting on those who fear him, and his righteousness to children’s children, to those who keep his covenant and remember to do his commandments. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 103,17-18</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Only let your manner of life be worthy of the gospel of Christ, so that whether I come and see you or am absent, I may hear of you that you are standing firm in one spirit, with one mind striving side by side for the faith of the gospel, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 1,27</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Arise, shine, for your light has come, and the glory of the Lord has risen upon you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 60,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>I have come into the world as light, so that whoever believes in me may not remain in darkness. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 12,46</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>All the nations you have made shall come and worship before you, O Lord, and shall glorify your name. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 86,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And this gospel of the kingdom will be proclaimed throughout the whole world as a testimony to all nations, and then the end will come. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 24,14</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For we are strangers before you and sojourners, as all our fathers were. Our days on the earth are like a shadow, and there is no abiding. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 29,15</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>In my Father’s house are many rooms. If it were not so, would I have told you that I go to prepare a place for you? </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 14,2</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And the people of Israel said to Samuel, “Do not cease to cry out to the Lord our God for us, that he may save us from the hand of the Philistines.”  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 7,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Therefore, confess your sins to one another and pray for one another, that you may be healed. The prayer of a righteous person has great power as it is working. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 5,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Who has measured the Spirit of the Lord, or what man shows him his counsel? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 40,13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Being then God’s offspring, we ought not to think that the divine being is like gold or silver or stone, an image formed by the art and imagination of man. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 17,29</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Drittletzter Sonntag des Kirchenjahres</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>A Song of Ascents. Of Solomon. Unless the Lord builds the house, those who build it labor in vain. Unless the Lord watches over the city, the watchman stays awake in vain. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 127,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So neither he who plants nor he who waters is anything, but only God who gives the growth. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 3,7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>But if you will not obey the voice of the Lord, but rebel against the commandment of the Lord, then the hand of the Lord will be against you and your king. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 12,15</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For your obedience is known to all, so that I rejoice over you, but I want you to be wise as to what is good and innocent as to what is evil. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 16,19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“For thus says the Lord God: Behold, I, I myself will search for my sheep and will seek them out. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 34,11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>When he saw the crowds, he had compassion for them, because they were harassed and helpless, like sheep without a shepherd. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 9,36</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Therefore he shall give them up until the time when she who is in labor has given birth; then the rest of his brothers shall return to the people of Israel. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Micah 5,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For in him the whole fullness of deity dwells bodily, and you have been filled in him, who is the head of all rule and authority. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 2,9-10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Save us, we pray, O Lord! O Lord, we pray, give us success!  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 118,25</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>for it is God who works in you, both to will and to work for his good pleasure. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>When words are many, transgression is not lacking, but whoever restrains his lips is prudent. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Proverbs 10,19</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>With it we bless our Lord and Father, and with it we curse people who are made in the likeness of God. From the same mouth come blessing and cursing. My brothers, these things ought not to be so.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 3,9-10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>The adversaries of the Lord shall be broken to pieces; against them he will thunder in heaven. The Lord will judge the ends of the earth; he will give strength to his king and exalt the horn of his anointed.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 2,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“When the Son of Man comes in his glory, and all the angels with him, then he will sit on his glorious throne. Before him will be gathered all the nations, and he will separate people one from another as a shepherd separates the sheep from the goats. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 25,31-32</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Vorletzter Sonntag des Kirchenjahres</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>And the people of Israel cried out to the Lord, saying, “We have sinned against you, because we have forsaken our God and have served the Baals.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Judges 10,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>He has delivered us from the domain of darkness and transferred us to the kingdom of his beloved Son, in whom we have redemption, the forgiveness of sins. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,13-14</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You hem me in, behind and before, and lay your hand upon me. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 139,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Who shall separate us from the love of Christ? Shall tribulation, or distress, or persecution, or famine, or nakedness, or danger, or sword?  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,35</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>They will fight against you, but they shall not prevail against you, for I am with you, declares the Lord, to deliver you.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 1,19</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For the kingdom of God does not consist in talk but in power. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 4,20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Buss- und Bettag</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>My lips will shout for joy, when I sing praises to you; my soul also, which you have redeemed. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 71,23</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>addressing one another in psalms and hymns and spiritual songs, singing and making melody to the Lord with your heart, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“Behold, I am the Lord, the God of all flesh. Is anything too hard for me? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 32,27</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Now to him who is able to strengthen you according to my gospel and the preaching of Jesus Christ, according to the revelation of the mystery that was kept secret for long ages to the only wise God be glory forevermore through Jesus Christ! Amen. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 16,25.27</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Blessed are those who dwell in your house, ever singing your praise! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 84,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For where two or three are gathered in my name, there am I among them.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 18,20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>A Psalm of David. The Lord is my shepherd; I shall not want. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 23,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>but as servants of God we commend ourselves in every way: by great endurance, in afflictions, hardships, calamities, as sorrowful, yet always rejoicing; as poor, yet making many rich; as having nothing, yet possessing everything. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 6,4.10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Letzter Sonntag des Kirchenjahres – Ewigkeitssonntag</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Light is sown for the righteous, and joy for the upright in heart. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 97,11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“Blessed are those who mourn, for they shall be comforted. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,4</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And God said to Abraham, “As for you, you shall keep my covenant, you and your offspring after you throughout their generations.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 17,9</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>who has made us sufficient to be ministers of a new covenant, not of the letter but of the Spirit. For the letter kills, but the Spirit gives life. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 3,6</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You make known to me the path of life; in your presence there is fullness of joy; at your right hand are pleasures forevermore. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 16,11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Brothers, I do not consider that I have made it my own. But one thing I do: forgetting what lies behind and straining forward to what lies ahead, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 3,13</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“Speak to all the congregation of the people of Israel and say to them, You shall be holy, for I the Lord your God am holy. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Leviticus 19,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Of his own will he brought us forth by the word of truth, that we should be a kind of firstfruits of his creatures. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 1,18</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For in death there is no remembrance of you; in Sheol who will give you praise? </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 6,5</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>If you then, who are evil, know how to give good gifts to your children, how much more will your Father who is in heaven give good things to those who ask him! </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 7,11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>As a father shows compassion to his children, so the Lord shows compassion to those who fear him. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 103,13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>I tell you, many will come from east and west and recline at table with Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob in the kingdom of heaven, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 8,11</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-11-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Kings shall be your foster fathers, and their queens your nursing mothers. With their faces to the ground they shall bow down to you, and lick the dust of your feet. Then you will know that I am the Lord; those who wait for me shall not be put to shame.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 49,23</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Rejoice in hope, be patient in tribulation, be constant in prayer. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,12</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-0100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>1. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Who would not fear you, O King of the nations? For this is your due; for among all the wise ones of the nations and in all their kingdoms there is none like you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 10,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Now may the God of peace who brought again from the dead our Lord Jesus, the great shepherd of the sheep, by the blood of the eternal covenant, equip you with everything good that you may do his will, working in us that which is pleasing in his sight, through Jesus Christ, to whom be glory forever and ever. Amen. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,20.21</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-0200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And the Lord said to Joshua, “Do not fear and do not be dismayed. Take all the fighting men with you, and arise, go up to Ai. See, I have given into your hand the king of Ai, and his people, his city, and his land. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Joshua 8,1</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>There is no fear in love, but perfect love casts out fear. For fear has to do with punishment, and whoever fears has not been perfected in love. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1. John 4,18</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-0300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And Asa went out to meet him, and they drew up their lines of battle in the Valley of Zephathah at Mareshah. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 14,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For everyone who asks receives, and the one who seeks finds, and to the one who knocks it will be opened.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 7,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-0400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For I will defend this city to save it, for my own sake and for the sake of my servant David.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>2 Kings 19,34</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So the church throughout all Judea and Galilee and Samaria had peace and was being built up. And walking in the fear of the Lord and in the comfort of the Holy Spirit, it multiplied. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Acts 9,31</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-0500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And he said, “Go out and stand on the mount before the Lord.” And behold, the Lord passed by, and a great and strong wind tore the mountains and broke in pieces the rocks before the Lord, but the Lord was not in the wind. And after the wind an earthquake, but the Lord was not in the earthquake. And after the earthquake a fire, but the Lord was not in the fire. And after the fire the sound of a low whisper.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers> 1 Kings 19,11-12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>God is spirit, and those who worship him must worship in spirit and truth.”  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 4,24</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-0600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Our God is a God of salvation, and to God, the Lord, belong deliverances from death. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 68,20</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And we know that for those who love God all things work together for good, for those who are called according to his purpose. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,28</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-0700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Send out your light and your truth; let them lead me; let them bring me to your holy hill and to your dwelling! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 43,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>This is the message we have heard from him and proclaim to you, that God is light, and in him is no darkness at all. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1. John 1,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-0800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>2. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>And the Lord will guide you continually and satisfy your desire in scorched places and make your bones strong; and you shall be like a watered garden, like a spring of water, whose waters do not fail. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 58,11</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Whoever believes in me, as the Scripture has said, ‘Out of his heart will flow rivers of living water.’” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 7,38</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-0900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>You shall not be partial in judgment. You shall hear the small and the great alike. You shall not be intimidated by anyone, for the judgment is God’s. And the case that is too hard for you, you shall bring to me, and I will hear it.’ </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 1,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For with the judgment you pronounce you will be judged, and with the measure you use it will be measured to you. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 7,2</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-1000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And he said, “Behold, I am making a covenant. Before all your people I will do marvels, such as have not been created in all the earth or in any nation. And all the people among whom you are shall see the work of the Lord, for it is an awesome thing that I will do with you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 34,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And he went throughout all Galilee, teaching in their synagogues and proclaiming the gospel of the kingdom and healing every disease and every affliction among the people. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 4,23</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-1100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>But Noah found favor in the eyes of the Lord. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Genesis 6,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Therefore, as you received Christ Jesus the Lord, so walk in him, rooted and built up in him and established in the faith, just as you were taught, abounding in thanksgiving. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Colossians 2,6-7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-1200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>There was no end of all the people, all of whom he led. Yet those who come later will not rejoice in him. Surely this also is vanity and a striving after wind.</Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ecclesiastes 4,17</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“And when you pray, do not heap up empty phrases as the Gentiles do, for they think that they will be heard for their many words. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-1300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For the Lord will not forsake his people; he will not abandon his heritage; </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 94,14</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>But our citizenship is in heaven, and from it we await a Savior, the Lord Jesus Christ, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 3,20</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-1400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Sing praises to the Lord, O you his saints, and give thanks to his holy name. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 30,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For the wages of sin is death, but the free gift of God is eternal life in Christ Jesus our Lord. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 6,23</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-1500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>3. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Blessed is the one you choose and bring near, to dwell in your courts! We shall be satisfied with the goodness of your house, the holiness of your temple! </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 65,4</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And you, child, will be called the prophet of the Most High; for you will go before the Lord to prepare his ways, to give knowledge of salvation to his people in the forgiveness of their sins, because of the tender mercy of our God, whereby the sunrise shall visit us from on high </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,76-78</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-1600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“Can a woman forget her nursing child, that she should have no compassion on the son of her womb? Even these may forget, yet I will not forget you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 49,15</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>For I am sure that neither death nor life, nor angels nor rulers, nor things present nor things to come, nor powers,  nor height nor depth, nor anything else in all creation, will be able to separate us from the love of God in Christ Jesus our Lord.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,38-39</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-1700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>“And in that day I will answer, declares the Lord, I will answer the heavens, and they shall answer the earth, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Hosea 2,21</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>“For God so loved the world, that he gave his only Son, that whoever believes in him should not perish but have eternal life. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 3,16</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-1800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I will instruct you and teach you in the way you should go; I will counsel you with my eye upon you. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 32,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And the angel said to her, “Do not be afraid, Mary, for you have found favor with God. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,30</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-1900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>A Song of Ascents. I lift up my eyes to the hills. From where does my help come? My help comes from the Lord, who made heaven and earth. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 121,1-2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>You also, be patient. Establish your hearts, for the coming of the Lord is at hand. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 5,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-2000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Why, when I came, was there no man; why, when I called, was there no one to answer? Is my hand shortened, that it cannot redeem? Or have I no power to deliver? Behold, by my rebuke I dry up the sea, I make the rivers a desert; their fish stink for lack of water and die of thirst. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 50,2</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>having the eyes of your hearts enlightened, that you may know what is the hope to which he has called you, what are the riches of his glorious inheritance in the saints, and what is the immeasurable greatness of his power toward us who believe, according to the working of his great might </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 1,18-19</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-2100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>Many bulls encompass me; strong bulls of Bashan surround me; </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 22,12</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So the sisters sent to him, saying, “Lord, he whom you love is ill.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 11,3</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-2200:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>4. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>You shall give to him freely, and your heart shall not be grudging when you give to him, because for this the Lord your God will bless you in all your work and in all that you undertake. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 15,10</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Let your reasonableness be known to everyone. The Lord is at hand; </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-2300:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>I will cleanse them from all the guilt of their sin against me, and I will forgive all the guilt of their sin and rebellion against me. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 33,8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>She will bear a son, and you shall call his name Jesus, for he will save his people from their sins.” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Matthew 1,21</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-2400:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Heiliger Abend</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Lift up your heads, O gates! And be lifted up, O ancient doors, that the King of glory may come in. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 24,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>So Jesus came out, wearing the crown of thorns and the purple robe. Pilate said to them, “Behold the man!” </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>John 19,5</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-2500:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>4</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Weihnachtsfest</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>for my people have committed two evils: they have forsaken me, the fountain of living waters, and hewed out cisterns for themselves, broken cisterns that can hold no water. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Jeremiah 2,13</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>In this is love, not that we have loved God but that he loved us and sent his Son to be the propitiation for our sins. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>1. John 4,10</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-2600:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>5</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>2. Weihnachtstag</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>“Hear, O kings; give ear, O princes; to the Lord I will sing; I will make melody to the Lord, the God of Israel.  </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Judges 5,3</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And when they saw it, they made known the saying that had been told them concerning this child.  And all who heard it wondered at what the shepherds told them.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,17-18</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-2700:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>6</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>For he is our God, and we are the people of his pasture, and the sheep of his hand. Today, if you hear his voice, do not harden your hearts, as at Meribah, as on the day at Massah in the wilderness, </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Psalm 95,7-8</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And do not get drunk with wine, for that is debauchery, but be filled with the Spirit, </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,18</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-2800:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>7</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>And the trees of the field shall yield their fruit, and the earth shall yield its increase, and they shall be secure in their land. And they shall know that I am the Lord, when I break the bars of their yoke, and deliver them from the hand of those who enslaved them. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Ezekiel 34,27</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Now the Lord is the Spirit, and where the Spirit of the Lord is, there is freedom. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 3,17</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-2900:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>1</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>1. Sonntag nach Weihnachten</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Even youths shall faint and be weary, and young men shall fall exhausted;  but they who wait for the Lord shall renew their strength; they shall mount up with wings like eagles; they shall run and not be weary; they shall walk and not faint. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Isaiah 40,30-31</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>for God gave us a spirit not of fear but of power and love and self-control. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 1,7</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-3000:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>2</Wtag>
        <Sonntag/>
        <Losungstext>and that all this assembly may know that the Lord saves not with sword and spear. For the battle is the Lord’s, and he will give you into our hand.” </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>1 Samuel 17,47</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>And a harvest of righteousness is sown in peace by those who make peace. </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>James 3,18</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
    <Losungen>
        <Datum>2019-12-3100:00:00</Datum>
        <Wtag>3</Wtag>
        <Sonntag>Altjahresabend</Sonntag>
        <Losungstext>Keep far from a false charge, and do not kill the innocent and righteous, for I will not acquit the wicked. </Losungstext>
        <Losungsvers>Exodus 23,7</Losungsvers>
        <Lehrtext>Finally, brothers, whatever is true, whatever is honorable, whatever is just, whatever is pure, whatever is lovely, whatever is commendable, if there is any excellence, if there is anything worthy of praise, think about these things.  </Lehrtext>
        <Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,8</Lehrtextvers>
    </Losungen>
</FreeXml>