<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><FreeXml><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag>Neujahr</Sonntag><Losungstext>For you, O God, have tested us; you have tried us as silver is tried. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 66,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Not only that, but we rejoice in our sufferings, knowing that suffering produces endurance, and endurance produces character, and character produces hope, and hope does not put us to shame, because God’s love has been poured into our hearts through the Holy Spirit who has been given to us. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,3.4.5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He will swallow up death forever; and the Lord God will wipe away tears from all faces, and the reproach of his people he will take away from all the earth, for the Lord has spoken. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 25,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Rejoice in hope, be patient in tribulation, be constant in prayer. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Delight yourself in the Lord, and he will give you the desires of your heart. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 37,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore I tell you, whatever you ask in prayer, believe that you have received it, and it will be yours. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 11,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“You shall not murder. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 20,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“But I say to you who hear, Love your enemies, do good to those who hate you, bless those who curse you, pray for those who abuse you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 6,27.28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>2. Sonntag nach Weihnachten</Sonntag><Losungstext>There are many who say, “Who will show us some good? Lift up the light of your face upon us, O Lord!” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 4,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Again Jesus spoke to them, saying, “I am the light of the world. Whoever follows me will not walk in darkness, but will have the light of life.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 8,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag>Fest der Erscheinung des Herrn – Epiphanias</Sonntag><Losungstext>Why do you say, O Jacob, and speak, O Israel, “My way is hidden from the Lord, and my right is disregarded by my God”? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 40,27</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But God’s firm foundation stands, bearing this seal: “The Lord knows those who are his,” and, “Let everyone who names the name of the Lord depart from iniquity.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Behold, I will shake my hand over them, and they shall become plunder for those who served them. Then you will know that the Lord of hosts has sent me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 2,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>What then shall we say to these things? If God is for us, who can be against us? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Let your steadfast love, O Lord, be upon us, even as we hope in you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 33,22</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let us hold fast the confession of our hope without wavering, for he who promised is faithful. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 10,23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>the God who equipped me with strength and made my way blameless. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 18,32</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I thank my God always when I remember you in my prayers, and I pray that the sharing of your faith may become effective for the full knowledge of every good thing that is in us for the sake of Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philemon 1,4.6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The wicked is overthrown through his evildoing, but the righteous finds refuge in his death. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 14,32</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For I am sure that neither death nor life, nor angels nor rulers, nor things present nor things to come, nor powers, nor height nor depth, nor anything else in all creation, will be able to separate us from the love of God in Christ Jesus our Lord. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,38.39</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But let justice roll down like waters, and righteousness like an ever-flowing stream. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Amos 5,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And Jesus called them to him and said to them, “You know that those who are considered rulers of the Gentiles lord it over them, and their great ones exercise authority over them. But it shall not be so among you. But whoever would be great among you must be your servant, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 10,42.43</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>1. Sonntag nach Epiphanias</Sonntag><Losungstext>he reveals deep and hidden things; he knows what is in the darkness, and the light dwells with him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 2,22</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Oh, the depth of the riches and wisdom and knowledge of God! How unsearchable are his judgments and how inscrutable his ways! </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 11,33</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>O Lord, the hope of Israel, all who forsake you shall be put to shame; those who turn away from you shall be written in the earth, for they have forsaken the Lord, the fountain of living water. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 17,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and saying, “The time is fulfilled, and the kingdom of God is at hand; repent and believe in the gospel.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 1,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>If you do well, will you not be accepted? And if you do not do well, sin is crouching at the door. Its desire is contrary to you, but you must rule over it.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 4,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But as for you, O man of God, flee these things. Pursue righteousness, godliness, faith, love, steadfastness, gentleness. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 6,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But the Lord said to him, “Peace be to you. Do not fear; you shall not die.” Then Gideon built an altar there to the Lord and called it, The Lord Is Peace. To this day it still stands at Ophrah, which belongs to the Abiezrites. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Judges 6,23.24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let us then with confidence draw near to the throne of grace, that we may receive mercy and find grace to help in time of need. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 4,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The earth, O Lord, is full of your steadfast love; teach me your statutes! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 119,64</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>All Scripture is breathed out by God and profitable for teaching, for reproof, for correction, and for training in righteousness, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 3,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>So Moses and Aaron went in to Pharaoh and said to him, “Thus says the Lord, the God of the Hebrews, ‘How long will you refuse to humble yourself before me? Let my people go, that they may serve me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 10,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Behold, I am sending you out as sheep in the midst of wolves, so be wise as serpents and innocent as doves. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 10,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>‘O Lord God, you have only begun to show your servant your greatness and your mighty hand. For what god is there in heaven or on earth who can do such works and mighty acts as yours? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 3,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For from him and through him and to him are all things. To him be glory forever. Amen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 11,36</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>2. Sonntag nach Epiphanias</Sonntag><Losungstext>Again, when a wicked person turns away from the wickedness he has committed and does what is just and right, he shall save his life. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 18,27</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The saying is trustworthy and deserving of full acceptance, that Christ Jesus came into the world to save sinners, of whom I am the foremost. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 1,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Blessed is the man against whom the Lord counts no iniquity, and in whose spirit there is no deceit. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 32,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore, if anyone is in Christ, he is a new creation. The old has passed away; behold, the new has come. All this is from God, who through Christ reconciled us to himself and gave us the ministry of reconciliation; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 5,17.18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I am the Lord your God, who brought you out of the land of Egypt, that you should not be their slaves. And I have broken the bars of your yoke and made you walk erect. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Leviticus 26,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For freedom Christ has set us free; stand firm therefore, and do not submit again to a yoke of slavery. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Galatians 5,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the head of Ephraim is Samaria, and the head of Samaria is the son of Remaliah. If you are not firm in faith, you will not be firm at all.’” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 7,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Fight the good fight of the faith. Take hold of the eternal life to which you were called and about which you made the good confession in the presence of many witnesses. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 6,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For you have delivered my soul from death, my eyes from tears, my feet from stumbling; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 116,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and deliver all those who through fear of death were subject to lifelong slavery. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 2,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The haughty looks of man shall be brought low, and the lofty pride of men shall be humbled, and the Lord alone will be exalted in that day. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 2,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not be deceived: God is not mocked, for whatever one sows, that will he also reap. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Galatians 6,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Have you not known? Have you not heard? The Lord is the everlasting God, the Creator of the ends of the earth. He does not faint or grow weary; his understanding is unsearchable. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 40,28</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>May the God of hope fill you with all joy and peace in believing, so that by the power of the Holy Spirit you may abound in hope. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 15,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>3. Sonntag nach Epiphanias</Sonntag><Losungstext>You rule the raging of the sea; when its waves rise, you still them. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 89,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now may the Lord of peace himself give you peace at all times in every way. The Lord be with you all. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 3,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Who has performed and done this, calling the generations from the beginning? I, the Lord, the first, and with the last; I am he. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 41,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>As for the word that he sent to Israel, preaching good news of peace through Jesus Christ (he is Lord of all), </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 10,36</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>If he tears down, none can rebuild; if he shuts a man in, none can open. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 12,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“And to the angel of the church in Philadelphia write: ‘The words of the holy one, the true one, who has the key of David, who opens and no one will shut, who shuts and no one opens. “I know your works. Behold, I have set before you an open door, which no one is able to shut. I know that you have but little power, and yet you have kept my word and have not denied my name. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 3,7.8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>a bruised reed he will not break, and a faintly burning wick he will not quench; he will faithfully bring forth justice. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 42,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the Son of Man came to seek and to save the lost.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 19,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“You shall do no injustice in court. You shall not be partial to the poor or defer to the great, but in righteousness shall you judge your neighbor. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Leviticus 19,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>My brothers, show no partiality as you hold the faith in our Lord Jesus Christ, the Lord of glory. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 2,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-01-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But Hannah answered, “No, my lord, I am a woman troubled in spirit. I have drunk neither wine nor strong drink, but I have been pouring out my soul before the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 1,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>casting all your anxieties on him, because he cares for you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 5,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Oh that you had paid attention to my commandments! Then your peace would have been like a river, and your righteousness like the waves of the sea; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 48,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And because of him you are in Christ Jesus, who became to us wisdom from God, righteousness and sanctification and redemption, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 1,30</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Letzter Sonntag nach Epiphanias</Sonntag><Losungstext>But the Lord God helps me; therefore I have not been disgraced; therefore I have set my face like a flint, and I know that I shall not be put to shame. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 50,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>To this day I have had the help that comes from God, and so I stand here testifying both to small and great, saying nothing but what the prophets and Moses said would come to pass: </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 26,22</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Only in the Lord, it shall be said of me, are righteousness and strength; to him shall come and be ashamed all who were incensed against him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 45,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and every tongue confess that Jesus Christ is Lord, to the glory of God the Father. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>When the poor and needy seek water, and there is none, and their tongue is parched with thirst, I the Lord will answer them; I the God of Israel will not forsake them. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 41,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said to me, “It is done! I am the Alpha and the Omega, the beginning and the end. To the thirsty I will give from the spring of the water of life without payment. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 21,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord will save me, and we will play my music on stringed instruments all the days of our lives, at the house of the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 38,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And leaping up, he stood and began to walk, and entered the temple with them, walking and leaping and praising God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 3,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He remembers his covenant forever, the word that he commanded, for a thousand generations, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 105,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Heaven and earth will pass away, but my words will not pass away. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 13,31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And these words that I command you today shall be on your heart. You shall teach them diligently to your children, and shall talk of them when you sit in your house, and when you walk by the way, and when you lie down, and when you rise. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 6,6.7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The aim of our charge is love that issues from a pure heart and a good conscience and a sincere faith. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 1,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Sing to the Lord; praise the Lord! For he has delivered the life of the needy from the hand of evildoers. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 20,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>he has brought down the mighty from their thrones and exalted those of humble estate; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,52</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>3. Sonntag vor der Passionszeit – Septuagesimae</Sonntag><Losungstext>Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord! We bless you from the house of the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 118,26</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he came and preached peace to you who were far off and peace to those who were near. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But he said to me, ‘The Lord, before whom I have walked, will send his angel with you and prosper your way. You shall take a wife for my son from my clan and from my father’s house. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 24,40</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>When our days there were ended, we departed and went on our journey, and they all, with wives and children, accompanied us until we were outside the city. And kneeling down on the beach, we prayed </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 21,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He restores my soul. He leads me in paths of righteousness for his name’s sake. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 23,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I am the good shepherd. I know my own and my own know me, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 10,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>yet I will remember my covenant with you in the days of your youth, and I will establish for you an everlasting covenant. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 16,60</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And after you have suffered a little while, the God of all grace, who has called you to his eternal glory in Christ, will himself restore, confirm, strengthen, and establish you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 5,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>It is the Lord who goes before you. He will be with you; he will not leave you or forsake you. Do not fear or be dismayed.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 31,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>My sheep hear my voice, and I know them, and they follow me. I give them eternal life, and they will never perish, and no one will snatch them out of my hand. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 10,27.28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Why have you despised the word of the Lord, to do what is evil in his sight? You have struck down Uriah the Hittite with the sword and have taken his wife to be your wife and have killed him with the sword of the Ammonites. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Samuel 12,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore, since we are surrounded by so great a cloud of witnesses, let us also lay aside every weight, and sin which clings so closely, and let us run with endurance the race that is set before us, looking to Jesus, the founder and perfecter of our faith, who for the joy that was set before him endured the cross, despising the shame, and is seated at the right hand of the throne of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 12,1.2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>O house of Jacob, come, let us walk in the light of the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 2,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Besides this you know the time, that the hour has come for you to wake from sleep. For salvation is nearer to us now than when we first believed. The night is far gone; the day is at hand. So then let us cast off the works of darkness and put on the armor of light. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 13,11.12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>2. Sonntag vor der Passionszeit – Sexagesimae</Sonntag><Losungstext>To the choirmaster: with stringed instruments. A Psalm of David. Answer me when I call, O God of my righteousness! You have given me relief when I was in distress. Be gracious to me and hear my prayer! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 4,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Blessed are those who mourn, for they shall be comforted. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>All the ends of the earth shall remember and turn to the Lord, and all the families of the nations shall worship before you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 22,27</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>who desires all people to be saved and to come to the knowledge of the truth. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 2,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Fear not, O land; be glad and rejoice, for the Lord has done great things! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joel 2,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Great indeed, we confess, is the mystery of godliness: He was manifested in the flesh, vindicated by the Spirit, seen by angels, proclaimed among the nations, believed on in the world, taken up in glory. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 3,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>A Psalm of Asaph. The Mighty One, God the Lord, speaks and summons the earth from the rising of the sun to its setting. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 50,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>that is, in Christ God was reconciling the world to himself, not counting their trespasses against them, and entrusting to us the message of reconciliation. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 5,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The command that Jonadab the son of Rechab gave to his sons, to drink no wine, has been kept, and they drink none to this day, for they have obeyed their father’s command. I have spoken to you persistently, but you have not listened to me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 35,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But he said, “Blessed rather are those who hear the word of God and keep it!” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 11,28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Now out of the ground the Lord God had formed every beast of the field and every bird of the heavens and brought them to the man to see what he would call them. And whatever the man called every living creature, that was its name. The man gave names to all livestock and to the birds of the heavens and to every beast of the field. But for Adam there was not found a helper fit for him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 2,19.20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Look at the birds of the air: they neither sow nor reap nor gather into barns, and yet your heavenly Father feeds them. Are you not of more value than they? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,26</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Yet you say, ‘The way of the Lord is not just.’ Hear now, O house of Israel: Is my way not just? Is it not your ways that are not just? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 18,25</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>If we say we have no sin, we deceive ourselves, and the truth is not in us. If we confess our sins, he is faithful and just to forgive us our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 John 1,8.9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>SONNTAG VOR DER PASSIONSZEIT - ESTOMIHI (Sei mir ein starker Fels! Psalm 31,3)</Sonntag><Losungstext>Their children shall be as they were of old, and their congregation shall be established before me, and I will punish all who oppress them. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 30,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>in whom the whole structure, being joined together, grows into a holy temple in the Lord. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Let us test and examine our ways, and return to the Lord! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Lamentations 3,40</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But he who is joined to the Lord becomes one spirit with him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 6,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And I will multiply on you man and beast, and they shall multiply and be fruitful. And I will cause you to be inhabited as in your former times, and will do more good to you than ever before. Then you will know that I am the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 36,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And God is able to make all grace abound to you, so that having all sufficiency in all things at all times, you may abound in every good work. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 9,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Oh that my ways may be steadfast in keeping your statutes! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 119,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>When the days drew near for him to be taken up, he set his face to go to Jerusalem. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 9,51</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>On God rests my salvation and my glory; my mighty rock, my refuge is God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 62,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Blessed are you when others revile you and persecute you and utter all kinds of evil against you falsely on my account. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>To the choirmaster: according to The Doe of the Dawn. A Psalm of David. My God, my God, why have you forsaken me? Why are you so far from saving me, from the words of my groaning? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 22,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So Peter was kept in prison, but earnest prayer for him was made to God by the church. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 12,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-02-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And as you have been a byword of cursing among the nations, O house of Judah and house of Israel, so will I save you, and you shall be a blessing. Fear not, but let your hands be strong.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 8,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I thank him who has given me strength, Christ Jesus our Lord, because he judged me faithful, appointing me to his service, though formerly I was a blasphemer, persecutor, and insolent opponent. But I received mercy because I had acted ignorantly in unbelief, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 1,12.13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>1. Sonntag der Passionszeit – Invokavit (Er ruft mich an, darum will ich ihn erhören. Psalm 91,15)</Sonntag><Losungstext>I thank you that you have answered me and have become my salvation. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 118,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said to her, “Daughter, your faith has made you well; go in peace, and be healed of your disease.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 5,34</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>for justice will return to the righteous, and all the upright in heart will follow it. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 94,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>In the same way, let your light shine before others, so that they may see your good works and give glory to your Father who is in heaven. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>To the choirmaster: with stringed instruments; according to The Sheminith. A Psalm of David. O Lord, rebuke me not in your anger, nor discipline me in your wrath. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 6,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For God has not destined us for wrath, but to obtain salvation through our Lord Jesus Christ, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You who fear the Lord, trust in the Lord! He is their help and their shield. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 115,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>having the eyes of your hearts enlightened, that you may know what is the hope to which he has called you, what are the riches of his glorious inheritance in the saints, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 1,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>So you shall keep the commandments of the Lord your God by walking in his ways and by fearing him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 8,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But as for you, continue in what you have learned and have firmly believed, knowing from whom you learned it </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 3,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then the eyes of the blind shall be opened, and the ears of the deaf unstopped; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 35,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>the blind receive their sight and the lame walk, lepers are cleansed and the deaf hear, and the dead are raised up, and the poor have good news preached to them. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 11,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>These are the things that you shall do: Speak the truth to one another; render in your gates judgments that are true and make for peace; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 8,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>it does not rejoice at wrongdoing, but rejoices with the truth. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 13,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>2. Sonntag der Passionszeit – Reminiszere (Gedenke, HERR, an deine Barmherzigkeit! Psalm 25,6)</Sonntag><Losungstext>“You shall not hate your brother in your heart, but you shall reason frankly with your neighbor, lest you incur sin because of him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Leviticus 19,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But I say to you, Love your enemies and pray for those who persecute you, so that you may be sons of your Father who is in heaven. For he makes his sun rise on the evil and on the good, and sends rain on the just and on the unjust. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,44.45</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Your iniquities have turned these away, and your sins have kept good from you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 5,25</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For I do not do the good I want, but the evil I do not want is what I keep on doing. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 7,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Of David. The Lord is my light and my salvation; whom shall I fear? The Lord is the stronghold of my life; of whom shall I be afraid? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 27,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for God gave us a spirit not of fear but of power and love and self-control. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 1,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Now I, Nebuchadnezzar, praise and extol and honor the King of heaven, for all his works are right and his ways are just; and those who walk in pride he is able to humble. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 4,37</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Take my yoke upon you, and learn from me, for I am gentle and lowly in heart, and you will find rest for your souls. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 11,29</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Plead my cause and redeem me; give me life according to your promise! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 119,154</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So Philip ran to him and heard him reading Isaiah the prophet and asked, “Do you understand what you are reading?” And he said, “How can I, unless someone guides me?” And he invited Philip to come up and sit with him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 8,30.31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You shall not curse the deaf or put a stumbling block before the blind, but you shall fear your God: I am the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Leviticus 19,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Bear one another’s burdens, and so fulfill the law of Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Galatians 6,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For with you is the fountain of life; in your light do we see light. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 36,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Whoever has the Son has life; whoever does not have the Son of God does not have life. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 John 5,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>3. Sonntag der Passionszeit – Okuli (Meine Augen sehen stets auf den HERRN. Psalm 25,15)</Sonntag><Losungstext>And God said to him, “Because you have asked this, and have not asked for yourself long life or riches or the life of your enemies, but have asked for yourself understanding to discern what is right, behold, I now do according to your word. Behold, I give you a wise and discerning mind, so that none like you has been before you and none like you shall arise after you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Kings 3,11.12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But seek first the kingdom of God and his righteousness, and all these things will be added to you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,33</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I cry out to God Most High, to God who fulfills his purpose for me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 57,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And you will be hated by all for my name’s sake. But the one who endures to the end will be saved. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 13,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Moreover, by them is your servant warned; in keeping them there is great reward. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 19,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Have nothing to do with irreverent, silly myths. Rather train yourself for godliness; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 4,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>These all look to you, to give them their food in due season. When you give it to them, they gather it up; when you open your hand, they are filled with good things. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 104,27.28</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>if indeed you have tasted that the Lord is good. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But the Lord was gracious to them and had compassion on them, and he turned toward them, because of his covenant with Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob, and would not destroy them, nor has he cast them from his presence until now. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Kings 13,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the gifts and the calling of God are irrevocable. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 11,29</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For he will hide me in his shelter in the day of trouble; he will conceal me under the cover of his tent; he will lift me high upon a rock. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 27,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the sake of Christ, then, I am content with weaknesses, insults, hardships, persecutions, and calamities. For when I am weak, then I am strong. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 12,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will give peace in the land, and you shall lie down, and none shall make you afraid. And I will remove harmful beasts from the land, and the sword shall not go through your land. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Leviticus 26,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the peace of God, which surpasses all understanding, will guard your hearts and your minds in Christ Jesus. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>4. Sonntag der Passionszeit – Lätare (Freuet euch mit Jerusalem! Jesaja 66,10)</Sonntag><Losungstext>but there is a God in heaven who reveals mysteries, and he has made known to King Nebuchadnezzar what will be in the latter days. Your dream and the visions of your head as you lay in bed are these: </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 2,28</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>in whom are hidden all the treasures of wisdom and knowledge. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 2,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“You are the Lord, you alone. You have made heaven, the heaven of heavens, with all their host, the earth and all that is on it, the seas and all that is in them; and you preserve all of them; and the host of heaven worships you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Nehemiah 9,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Yet he did not leave himself without witness, for he did good by giving you rains from heaven and fruitful seasons, satisfying your hearts with food and gladness.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 14,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord is righteous in all his ways and kind in all his works. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 145,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And so, from the day we heard, we have not ceased to pray for you, asking that you may be filled with the knowledge of his will in all spiritual wisdom and understanding, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You turn things upside down! Shall the potter be regarded as the clay, that the thing made should say of its maker, “He did not make me”; or the thing formed say of him who formed it, “He has no understanding”? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 29,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Likewise, you who are younger, be subject to the elders. Clothe yourselves, all of you, with humility toward one another, for “God opposes the proud but gives grace to the humble.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 5,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I confess my iniquity; I am sorry for my sin. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 38,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For godly grief produces a repentance that leads to salvation without regret, whereas worldly grief produces death. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 7,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The heart is deceitful above all things, and desperately sick; who can understand it? “I the Lord search the heart and test the mind, to give every man according to his ways, according to the fruit of his deeds.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 17,9.10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>By this we shall know that we are of the truth and reassure our heart before him; for whenever our heart condemns us, God is greater than our heart, and he knows everything. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 John 3,19.20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>but the Lord takes pleasure in those who fear him, in those who hope in his steadfast love. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 147,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For whoever does the will of God, he is my brother and sister and mother.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 3,35</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>5. Sonntag der Passionszeit – Judika (Schaffe mir Recht, Gott! Psalm 43,1)</Sonntag><Losungstext>When my spirit faints within me, you know my way! In the path where I walk they have hidden a trap for me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 142,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, the Father of mercies and God of all comfort, who comforts us in all our affliction, so that we may be able to comfort those who are in any affliction, with the comfort with which we ourselves are comforted by God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,3.4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“You shall say to them, Thus says the Lord: When men fall, do they not rise again? If one turns away, does he not return? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 8,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>All that the Father gives me will come to me, and whoever comes to me I will never cast out. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 6,37</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-03-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“And those who are far off shall come and help to build the temple of the Lord. And you shall know that the Lord of hosts has sent me to you. And this shall come to pass, if you will diligently obey the voice of the Lord your God.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 6,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>In him you also are being built together into a dwelling place for God by the Spirit. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,22</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will rejoice in Jerusalem and be glad in my people; no more shall be heard in it the sound of weeping and the cry of distress. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 65,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So also you have sorrow now, but I will see you again, and your hearts will rejoice, and no one will take your joy from you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 16,22</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>O God, from my youth you have taught me, and I still proclaim your wondrous deeds. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 71,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>he took him up in his arms and blessed God and said, “Lord, now you are letting your servant depart in peace, according to your word; for my eyes have seen your salvation </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,28.29.30</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Blessed are the people who know the festal shout, who walk, O Lord, in the light of your face, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 89,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for at one time you were darkness, but now you are light in the Lord. Walk as children of light (for the fruit of light is found in all that is good and right and true), </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,8.9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Why should the nations say, “Where is their God?” Our God is in the heavens; he does all that he pleases. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 115,2.3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For his invisible attributes, namely, his eternal power and divine nature, have been clearly perceived, ever since the creation of the world, in the things that have been made. So they are without excuse. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 1,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>6. Sonntag der Passionszeit – Palmsonntag</Sonntag><Losungstext>“Bless God in the great congregation, the Lord, O you who are of Israel’s fountain!” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 68,26</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The next day the large crowd that had come to the feast heard that Jesus was coming to Jerusalem. So they took branches of palm trees and went out to meet him, crying out, “Hosanna! Blessed is he who comes in the name of the Lord, even the King of Israel!” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 12,12.13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Were I to write for him my laws by the ten thousands, they would be regarded as a strange thing. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Hosea 8,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Then Pilate said to him, “So you are a king?” Jesus answered, “You say that I am a king. For this purpose I was born and for this purpose I have come into the world—to bear witness to the truth. Everyone who is of the truth listens to my voice.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 18,37</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord has taken away the judgments against you; he has cleared away your enemies. The King of Israel, the Lord, is in your midst; you shall never again fear evil. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zephaniah 3,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He said to them, “Why are you so afraid? Have you still no faith?” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 4,40</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Restore to me the joy of your salvation, and uphold me with a willing spirit. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 51,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Truly, truly, I say to you, you will weep and lament, but the world will rejoice. You will be sorrowful, but your sorrow will turn into joy. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 16,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag>Gründonnerstag</Sonntag><Losungstext>The inhabitants of one city shall go to another, saying, ‘Let us go at once to entreat the favor of the Lord and to seek the Lord of hosts; I myself am going.’ </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 8,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And when they had sung a hymn, they went out to the Mount of Olives. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 14,26</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag>Karfreitag</Sonntag><Losungstext>Praise the Lord! Blessed is the man who fears the Lord, who greatly delights in his commandments! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 112,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He himself bore our sins in his body on the tree, that we might die to sin and live to righteousness. By his wounds you have been healed. For you were straying like sheep, but have now returned to the Shepherd and Overseer of your souls. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,24.25</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Though our iniquities testify against us, act, O Lord, for your name’s sake; for our backslidings are many; we have sinned against you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 14,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He himself bore our sins in his body on the tree, that we might die to sin and live to righteousness. By his wounds you have been healed. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Osterfest</Sonntag><Losungstext>For behold, darkness shall cover the earth, and thick darkness the peoples; but the Lord will arise upon you, and his glory will be seen upon you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 60,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And very early on the first day of the week, when the sun had risen, they went to the tomb. And they were saying to one another, “Who will roll away the stone for us from the entrance of the tomb?” And looking up, they saw that the stone had been rolled back—it was very large. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 16,2.3.4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag>Ostermontag</Sonntag><Losungstext>And when Jacob saw them he said, “This is God’s camp!” So he called the name of that place Mahanaim. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 32,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But the angel said to the women, “Do not be afraid, for I know that you seek Jesus who was crucified. Then go quickly and tell his disciples that he has risen from the dead, and behold, he is going before you to Galilee; there you will see him. See, I have told you.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 28,5.7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>My righteousness draws near, my salvation has gone out, and my arms will judge the peoples; the coastlands hope for me, and for my arm they wait. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 51,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ! According to his great mercy, he has caused us to be born again to a living hope through the resurrection of Jesus Christ from the dead, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 1,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For the Lord your God has blessed you in all the work of your hands. He knows your going through this great wilderness. These forty years the Lord your God has been with you. You have lacked nothing.”’ </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 2,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>but as servants of God we commend ourselves in every way: by great endurance, in afflictions, hardships, calamities, as sorrowful, yet always rejoicing; as poor, yet making many rich; as having nothing, yet possessing everything. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 6,4.10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Woe to those who are wise in their own eyes, and shrewd in their own sight! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 5,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now we have received not the spirit of the world, but the Spirit who is from God, that we might understand the things freely given us by God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 2,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Be to me a rock of refuge, to which I may continually come; you have given the command to save me, for you are my rock and my fortress. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 71,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The Lord will rescue me from every evil deed and bring me safely into his heavenly kingdom. To him be the glory forever and ever. Amen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 4,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Even the stork in the heavens knows her times, and the turtledove, swallow, and crane keep the time of their coming, but my people know not the rules of the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 8,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>who gave himself for us to redeem us from all lawlessness and to purify for himself a people for his own possession who are zealous for good works. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Titus 2,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>1. Sonntag nach Ostern – Quasimodogeniti (Wie die neugeborenen Kindlein. 1.Petrus 2,2)</Sonntag><Losungstext>“He found him in a desert land, and in the howling waste of the wilderness; he encircled him, he cared for him, he kept him as the apple of his eye. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 32,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Fear not, little flock, for it is your Father’s good pleasure to give you the kingdom. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 12,32</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For I have chosen him, that he may command his children and his household after him to keep the way of the Lord by doing righteousness and justice, so that the Lord may bring to Abraham what he has promised him.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 18,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But now that you have been set free from sin and have become slaves of God, the fruit you get leads to sanctification and its end, eternal life. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 6,22</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the king commanded, and those men who had maliciously accused Daniel were brought and cast into the den of lions—they, their children, and their wives. And before they reached the bottom of the den, the lions overpowered them and broke all their bones in pieces. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 6,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Be watchful, stand firm in the faith, act like men, be strong. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 16,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“When I passed by you again and saw you, behold, you were at the age for love, and I spread the corner of my garment over you and covered your nakedness; I made my vow to you and entered into a covenant with you, declares the Lord God, and you became mine. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 16,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for in Christ Jesus you are all sons of God, through faith. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Galatians 3,26</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Remember these things, O Jacob, and Israel, for you are my servant; I formed you; you are my servant; O Israel, you will not be forgotten by me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 44,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore do not throw away your confidence, which has a great reward. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 10,35</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Do not spurn us, for your name’s sake; do not dishonor your glorious throne; remember and do not break your covenant with us. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 14,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>God is faithful, by whom you were called into the fellowship of his Son, Jesus Christ our Lord. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 1,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord your God will make you abundantly prosperous in all the work of your hand, in the fruit of your womb and in the fruit of your cattle and in the fruit of your ground. For the Lord will again take delight in prospering you, as he took delight in your fathers, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 30,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>If you keep my commandments, you will abide in my love, just as I have kept my Father’s commandments and abide in his love. These things I have spoken to you, that my joy may be in you, and that your joy may be full. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 15,10.11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>2. Sonntag nach Ostern – Miserikordias Domini (Die Erde ist voll der Güte des HERRN. Psalm 33,5)</Sonntag><Losungstext>For you cast me into the deep, into the heart of the seas, and the flood surrounded me; all your waves and your billows passed over me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jonah 2,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Then came one of the rulers of the synagogue, Jairus by name, and seeing him, he fell at his feet and implored him earnestly, saying, “My little daughter is at the point of death. Come and lay your hands on her, so that she may be made well and live.” And he went with him. And a great crowd followed him and thronged about him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 5,22.23.24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And they heard the sound of the Lord God walking in the garden in the cool of the day, and the man and his wife hid themselves from the presence of the Lord God among the trees of the garden. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 3,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For you did not receive the spirit of slavery to fall back into fear, but you have received the Spirit of adoption as sons, by whom we cry, “Abba! Father!” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Now set your mind and heart to seek the Lord your God. Arise and build the sanctuary of the Lord God, so that the ark of the covenant of the Lord and the holy vessels of God may be brought into a house built for the name of the Lord.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 22,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do you not know that in a race all the runners run, but only one receives the prize? So run that you may obtain it. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 9,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>God called the dry land Earth, and the waters that were gathered together he called Seas. And God saw that it was good. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Eclesiastes 9,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not be slothful in zeal, be fervent in spirit, serve the Lord. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-04-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>A Psalm of Asaph. Truly God is good to Israel, to those who are pure in heart. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 73,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Beloved, if our heart does not condemn us, we have confidence before God; and whatever we ask we receive from him, because we keep his commandments and do what pleases him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 John 3,21.22</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the Lord said to Moses, “Is the Lord’s hand shortened? Now you shall see whether my word will come true for you or not.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Numbers 11,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And why are you anxious about clothing? Consider the lilies of the field, how they grow: they neither toil nor spin, yet I tell you, even Solomon in all his glory was not arrayed like one of these. Therefore do not be anxious, saying, ‘What shall we eat?’ or ‘What shall we drink?’ or ‘What shall we wear?’ </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,28.29.31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Cast me not away from your presence, and take not your Holy Spirit from me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 51,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>We always thank God, the Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, when we pray for you, He has delivered us from the domain of darkness and transferred us to the kingdom of his beloved Son, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,3.13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>3. Sonntag nach Ostern – Jubilate (Jauchzet Gott, alle Lande! Psalm 66,1)</Sonntag><Losungstext>Then Abner called to Joab, “Shall the sword devour forever? Do you not know that the end will be bitter? How long will it be before you tell your people to turn from the pursuit of their brothers?” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Samuel 2,26</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But if the unbelieving partner separates, let it be so. In such cases the brother or sister is not enslaved. God has called you to peace. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 7,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>and gathered in from the lands, from the east and from the west, from the north and from the south. Let them thank the Lord for his steadfast love, for his wondrous works to the children of man! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 107,3.8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the servant said, ‘Sir, what you commanded has been done, and still there is room.’ And the master said to the servant, ‘Go out to the highways and hedges and compel people to come in, that my house may be filled. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 14,22.23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>who alone stretched out the heavens and trampled the waves of the sea; who made the Bear and Orion, the Pleiades and the chambers of the south; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 9,8.9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He is the image of the invisible God, the firstborn of all creation. For by him all things were created, in heaven and on earth, visible and invisible, whether thrones or dominions or rulers or authorities—all things were created through him and for him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,15.16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And I will lead the blind in a way that they do not know, in paths that they have not known I will guide them. I will turn the darkness before them into light, the rough places into level ground. These are the things I do, and I do not forsake them. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 42,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>because of the tender mercy of our God, whereby the sunrise shall visit us from on high to give light to those who sit in darkness and in the shadow of death, to guide our feet into the way of peace.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,78.79</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>They refused to obey and were not mindful of the wonders that you performed among them, but they stiffened their neck and appointed a leader to return to their slavery in Egypt. But you are a God ready to forgive, gracious and merciful, slow to anger and abounding in steadfast love, and did not forsake them. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Nehemiah 9,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>if we are faithless, he remains faithful— for he cannot deny himself. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Let your mercy come to me, that I may live; for your law is my delight. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 119,77</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now Simon’s mother-in-law lay ill with a fever, and immediately they told him about her. And he came and took her by the hand and lifted her up, and the fever left her, and she began to serve them. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 1,30.31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For the Lord your God has blessed you in all the work of your hands. He knows your going through this great wilderness. These forty years the Lord your God has been with you. You have lacked nothing.”’ </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 2,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Moreover, it is required of stewards that they be found faithful. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 4,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>4. Sonntag nach Ostern – Kantate (Singet dem HERRN ein neues Lied! Psalm 98,1)</Sonntag><Losungstext>Now when these signs meet you, do what your hand finds to do, for God is with you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 10,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Think over what I say, for the Lord will give you understanding in everything. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>To the choirmaster. A Maskil of the Sons of Korah. O God, we have heard with our ears, our fathers have told us, what deeds you performed in their days, in the days of old: </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 44,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And she had a sister called Mary, who sat at the Lord’s feet and listened to his teaching. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 10,39</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>At Gibeon the Lord appeared to Solomon in a dream by night, and God said, “Ask what I shall give you.” Give your servant therefore an understanding mind to govern your people, that I may discern between good and evil, for who is able to govern this your great people?” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Kings 3,5.9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And it is my prayer that your love may abound more and more, with knowledge and all discernment, so that you may approve what is excellent, and so be pure and blameless for the day of Christ, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 1,9.10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>then hear in heaven your dwelling place and forgive and act and render to each whose heart you know, according to all his ways (for you, you only, know the hearts of all the children of mankind), </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Kings 8,39</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now may our Lord Jesus Christ himself, and God our Father, who loved us and gave us eternal comfort and good hope through grace, comfort your hearts and establish them in every good work and word. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 2,16.17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Will it be well with you when he searches you out? Or can you deceive him, as one deceives a man? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 13,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Examine yourselves, to see whether you are in the faith. Test yourselves. Or do you not realize this about yourselves, that Jesus Christ is in you?—unless indeed you fail to meet the test! </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 13,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then we cried to the Lord, the God of our fathers, and the Lord heard our voice and saw our affliction, our toil, and our oppression. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 26,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And will not God give justice to his elect, who cry to him day and night? Will he delay long over them? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 18,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Lift up your eyes to the heavens, and look at the earth beneath; for the heavens vanish like smoke, the earth will wear out like a garment, and they who dwell in it will die in like manner; but my salvation will be forever, and my righteousness will never be dismayed. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 51,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Heaven and earth will pass away, but my words will not pass away. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 21,33</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>5. Sonntag nach Ostern – Rogate (Betet!)</Sonntag><Losungstext>that he may incline our hearts to him, to walk in all his ways and to keep his commandments, his statutes, and his rules, which he commanded our fathers. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Kings 8,58</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore, as you received Christ Jesus the Lord, so walk in him, rooted and built up in him and established in the faith, just as you were taught, abounding in thanksgiving. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 2,6.7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You gave your good Spirit to instruct them and did not withhold your manna from their mouth and gave them water for their thirst. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Nehemiah 9,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But the Helper, the Holy Spirit, whom the Father will send in my name, he will teach you all things and bring to your remembrance all that I have said to you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 14,26</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Say to them, As I live, declares the Lord God, I have no pleasure in the death of the wicked, but that the wicked turn from his way and live; turn back, turn back from your evil ways, for why will you die, O house of Israel? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 33,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And Zacchaeus stood and said to the Lord, “Behold, Lord, the half of my goods I give to the poor. And if I have defrauded anyone of anything, I restore it fourfold.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 19,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>A righteous man knows the rights of the poor; a wicked man does not understand such knowledge. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 29,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For God is not unjust so as to overlook your work and the love that you have shown for his name in serving the saints, as you still do. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 6,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag>Christi Himmelfahrt</Sonntag><Losungstext>O you who love the Lord, hate evil! He preserves the lives of his saints; he delivers them from the hand of the wicked. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 97,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Rather, speaking the truth in love, we are to grow up in every way into him who is the head, into Christ, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 4,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Is Ephraim my dear son? Is he my darling child? For as often as I speak against him, I do remember him still. Therefore my heart yearns for him; I will surely have mercy on him, declares the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he arose and came to his father. But while he was still a long way off, his father saw him and felt compassion, and ran and embraced him and kissed him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 15,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“See, I am setting before you today a blessing and a curse: the blessing, if you obey the commandments of the Lord your God, which I command you today, and the curse, if you do not obey the commandments of the Lord your God, but turn aside from the way that I am commanding you today, to go after other gods that you have not known. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 11,26.27.28</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>knowing that from the Lord you will receive the inheritance as your reward. You are serving the Lord Christ. For the wrongdoer will be paid back for the wrong he has done, and there is no partiality. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 3,24.25</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>6. Sonntag nach Ostern – Exaudi (HERR, höre meine Stimme! Psalm 27,7)</Sonntag><Losungstext>But with you there is forgiveness, that you may be feared. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 130,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>bearing with one another and, if one has a complaint against another, forgiving each other; as the Lord has forgiven you, so you also must forgive. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 3,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>O Lord, in the morning you hear my voice; in the morning I prepare a sacrifice for you and watch. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 5,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>praying at all times in the Spirit, with all prayer and supplication. To that end, keep alert with all perseverance, making supplication for all the saints, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 6,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord looks down from heaven on the children of man, to see if there are any who understand, who seek after God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 14,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not be conformed to this world, but be transformed by the renewal of your mind, that by testing you may discern what is the will of God, what is good and acceptable and perfect. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord will fulfill his purpose for me; your steadfast love, O Lord, endures forever. Do not forsake the work of your hands. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 138,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And I am sure of this, that he who began a good work in you will bring it to completion at the day of Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 1,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Turn to me and be gracious to me, for I am lonely and afflicted. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 25,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The sick man answered him, “Sir, I have no one to put me into the pool when the water is stirred up, and while I am going another steps down before me.” Jesus said to him, “Get up, take up your bed, and walk.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 5,7.8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then my tongue shall tell of your righteousness and of your praise all the day long. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 35,28</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And they worshiped him and returned to Jerusalem with great joy, and were continually in the temple blessing God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 24,52.53</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But Balaam answered and said to the servants of Balak, “Though Balak were to give me his house full of silver and gold, I could not go beyond the command of the Lord my God to do less or more. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Numbers 22,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For we are not, like so many, peddlers of God’s word, but as men of sincerity, as commissioned by God, in the sight of God we speak in Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 2,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-05-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Pfingstfest</Sonntag><Losungstext>Woe to those who join house to house, who add field to field, until there is no more room, and you are made to dwell alone in the midst of the land. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 5,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For in one Spirit we were all baptized into one body—Jews or Greeks, slaves or free—and all were made to drink of one Spirit. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 12,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag>Pfingstmontag</Sonntag><Losungstext>Fear not, nor be afraid; have I not told you from of old and declared it? And you are my witnesses! Is there a God besides me? There is no Rock; I know not any.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 44,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>What I tell you in the dark, say in the light, and what you hear whispered, proclaim on the housetops. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 10,27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And Hannah prayed and said, “My heart exults in the Lord; my horn is exalted in the Lord. My mouth derides my enemies, because I rejoice in your salvation. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 2,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Though you have not seen him, you love him. Though you do not now see him, you believe in him and rejoice with joy that is inexpressible and filled with glory, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 1,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The eyes of the Lord are toward the righteous and his ears toward their cry. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 34,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Ask, and it will be given to you; seek, and you will find; knock, and it will be opened to you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 7,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then David said to the Philistine, “You come to me with a sword and with a spear and with a javelin, but I come to you in the name of the Lord of hosts, the God of the armies of Israel, whom you have defied. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 17,45</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Stand therefore, having fastened on the belt of truth, and having put on the breastplate of righteousness, and, as shoes for your feet, having put on the readiness given by the gospel of peace. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 6,14.15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>My tears have been my food day and night, while they say to me all the day long, “Where is your God?” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 42,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But he said to me, “My grace is sufficient for you, for my power is made perfect in weakness.” Therefore I will boast all the more gladly of my weaknesses, so that the power of Christ may rest upon me. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 12,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>How great are his signs, how mighty his wonders! His kingdom is an everlasting kingdom, and his dominion endures from generation to generation. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 4,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore let us be grateful for receiving a kingdom that cannot be shaken, and thus let us offer to God acceptable worship, with reverence and awe, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 12,28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Trinitatis (Dreieinigkeit)</Sonntag><Losungstext>before the Lord, for he comes to judge the earth. He will judge the world with righteousness, and the peoples with equity. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 98,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And this gospel of the kingdom will be proclaimed throughout the whole world as a testimony to all nations, and then the end will come. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 24,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Speak tenderly to Jerusalem, and cry to her that her warfare is ended, that her iniquity is pardoned, that she has received from the Lord’s hand double for all her sins. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 40,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>that the creation itself will be set free from its bondage to corruption and obtain the freedom of the glory of the children of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“You shall not steal. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 20,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let no one seek his own good, but the good of his neighbor. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 10,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The jar of flour was not spent, neither did the jug of oil become empty, according to the word of the Lord that he spoke by Elijah. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Kings 17,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And taking the five loaves and the two fish, he looked up to heaven and said a blessing and broke the loaves and gave them to the disciples to set before the people. And he divided the two fish among them all. And they all ate and were satisfied. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 6,41.42</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>We have escaped like a bird from the snare of the fowlers; the snare is broken, and we have escaped! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 124,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And behold, an angel of the Lord stood next to him, and a light shone in the cell. He struck Peter on the side and woke him, saying, “Get up quickly.” And the chains fell off his hands. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 12,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But you, O Lord, know me; you see me, and test my heart toward you. Pull them out like sheep for the slaughter, and set them apart for the day of slaughter. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 12,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>As the Father has loved me, so have I loved you. Abide in my love. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 15,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“And I will pour out on the house of David and the inhabitants of Jerusalem a spirit of grace and pleas for mercy, so that, when they look on me, on him whom they have pierced, they shall mourn for him, as one mourns for an only child, and weep bitterly over him, as one weeps over a firstborn. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 12,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Likewise the Spirit helps us in our weakness. For we do not know what to pray for as we ought, but the Spirit himself intercedes for us with groanings too deep for words. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,26</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>1. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>You have given him dominion over the works of your hands; you have put all things under his feet, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 8,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore be imitators of God, as beloved children. And walk in love, as Christ loved us and gave himself up for us, a fragrant offering and sacrifice to God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,1.2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Your dead shall live; their bodies shall rise. You who dwell in the dust, awake and sing for joy! For your dew is a dew of light, and the earth will give birth to the dead. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 26,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>knowing that he who raised the Lord Jesus will raise us also with Jesus and bring us with you into his presence. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 4,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Have you not brought this upon yourself by forsaking the Lord your God, when he led you in the way? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 2,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So Jesus said to the Jews who had believed him, “If you abide in my word, you are truly my disciples, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 8,31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Serve the Lord with gladness! Come into his presence with singing! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 100,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>giving thanks to the Father, who has qualified you to share in the inheritance of the saints in light. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Noah did this; he did all that God commanded him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 6,22</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now faith is the assurance of things hoped for, the conviction of things not seen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 11,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will instruct you and teach you in the way you should go; I will counsel you with my eye upon you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 32,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore do not be foolish, but understand what the will of the Lord is. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Full of splendor and majesty is his work, and his righteousness endures forever. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 111,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But God’s firm foundation stands, bearing this seal: “The Lord knows those who are his,” and, “Let everyone who names the name of the Lord depart from iniquity.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>2. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>A Psalm. A Song for the Sabbath. It is good to give thanks to the Lord, to sing praises to your name, O Most High; to declare your steadfast love in the morning, and your faithfulness by night, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 92,1.2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>May the God of endurance and encouragement grant you to live in such harmony with one another, in accord with Christ Jesus, that together you may with one voice glorify the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 15,5.6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You crown the year with your bounty; your wagon tracks overflow with abundance. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 65,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Every good gift and every perfect gift is from above, coming down from the Father of lights, with whom there is no variation or shadow due to change. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 1,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He sends out his command to the earth; his word runs swiftly. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 147,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for which I am suffering, bound with chains as a criminal. But the word of God is not bound! </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag>Johannistag</Sonntag><Losungstext>For as the earth brings forth its sprouts, and as a garden causes what is sown in it to sprout up, so the Lord God will cause righteousness and praise to sprout up before all the nations. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 61,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And a harvest of righteousness is sown in peace by those who make peace. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 3,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You shall suck the milk of nations; you shall nurse at the breast of kings; and you shall know that I, the Lord, am your Savior and your Redeemer, the Mighty One of Jacob. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 60,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Who shall separate us from the love of Christ? Shall tribulation, or distress, or persecution, or famine, or nakedness, or danger, or sword? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,35</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Blessed are they who observe justice, who do righteousness at all times! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 106,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the world is passing away along with its desires, but whoever does the will of God abides forever. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 John 2,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Remember your congregation, which you have purchased of old, which you have redeemed to be the tribe of your heritage! Remember Mount Zion, where you have dwelt. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 74,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For you know the grace of our Lord Jesus Christ, that though he was rich, yet for your sake he became poor, so that you by his poverty might become rich. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 8,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>3. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>I have set the Lord always before me; because he is at my right hand, I shall not be shaken. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 16,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Jesus said to him, “No one who puts his hand to the plow and looks back is fit for the kingdom of God.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 9,62</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then the king was exceedingly glad, and commanded that Daniel be taken up out of the den. So Daniel was taken up out of the den, and no kind of harm was found on him, because he had trusted in his God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 6,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>persecuted, but not forsaken; struck down, but not destroyed; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 4,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-06-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You have said, “Seek my face.” My heart says to you, “Your face, Lord, do I seek.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 27,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>do not be anxious about anything, but in everything by prayer and supplication with thanksgiving let your requests be made known to God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Can a man hide himself in secret places so that I cannot see him? declares the Lord. Do I not fill heaven and earth? declares the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 23,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But if anyone loves God, he is known by God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 8,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>To the choirmaster: according to The Gittith. A Psalm of David. O Lord, our Lord, how majestic is your name in all the earth! You have set your glory above the heavens. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 8,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for he who is mighty has done great things for me, and holy is his name. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,49</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Yodh: Your hands have made and fashioned me; give me understanding that I may learn your commandments. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 119,73</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And this is his commandment, that we believe in the name of his Son Jesus Christ and love one another, just as he has commanded us. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 John 3,23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I will turn to you and make you fruitful and multiply you and will confirm my covenant with you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Leviticus 26,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For all the promises of God find their Yes in him. That is why it is through him that we utter our Amen to God for his glory. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>4. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>“Be glad, O children of Zion, and rejoice in the Lord your God, for he has given the early rain for your vindication; he has poured down for you abundant rain, the early and the latter rain, as before. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joel 2,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>in whom we have boldness and access with confidence through our faith in him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 3,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>as far as the east is from the west, so far does he remove our transgressions from us. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 103,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now the law came in to increase the trespass, but where sin increased, grace abounded all the more, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I had said in my alarm, “I am cut off from your sight.” But you heard the voice of my pleas for mercy when I cried to you for help. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 31,22</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And they came to Jericho. And as he was leaving Jericho with his disciples and a great crowd, Bartimaeus, a blind beggar, the son of Timaeus, was sitting by the roadside. And when he heard that it was Jesus of Nazareth, he began to cry out and say, “Jesus, Son of David, have mercy on me!” And many rebuked him, telling him to be silent. But he cried out all the more, “Son of David, have mercy on me!” And Jesus stopped and said, “Call him.” And they called the blind man, saying to him, “Take heart. Get up; he is calling you.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 10,46.47.48.49</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>therefore, behold, I will again do wonderful things with this people, with wonder upon wonder; and the wisdom of their wise men shall perish, and the discernment of their discerning men shall be hidden.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 29,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And on the Sabbath he began to teach in the synagogue, and many who heard him were astonished, saying, “Where did this man get these things? What is the wisdom given to him? How are such mighty works done by his hands? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 6,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Because you have made the Lord your dwelling place— the Most High, who is my refuge— </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 91,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Since we have such a hope, we are very bold, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 3,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>One generation shall commend your works to another, and shall declare your mighty acts. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 145,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For it is all for your sake, so that as grace extends to more and more people it may increase thanksgiving, to the glory of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 4,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>May the Lord give strength to his people! May the Lord bless his people with peace! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 29,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now when they saw the boldness of Peter and John, and perceived that they were uneducated, common men, they were astonished. And they recognized that they had been with Jesus. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 4,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>5. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>To you, O Lord, belongs righteousness, but to us open shame, as at this day, to the men of Judah, to the inhabitants of Jerusalem, and to all Israel, those who are near and those who are far away, in all the lands to which you have driven them, because of the treachery that they have committed against you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 9,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For by grace you have been saved through faith. And this is not your own doing; it is the gift of God, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Sow for yourselves righteousness; reap steadfast love; break up your fallow ground, for it is the time to seek the Lord, that he may come and rain righteousness upon you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Hosea 10,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and to put on the new self, created after the likeness of God in true righteousness and holiness. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 4,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>the voice of mirth and the voice of gladness, the voice of the bridegroom and the voice of the bride, the voices of those who sing, as they bring thank offerings to the house of the Lord: “‘Give thanks to the Lord of hosts, for the Lord is good, for his steadfast love endures forever!’ For I will restore the fortunes of the land as at first, says the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 33,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And Jesus said to them, “Can the wedding guests fast while the bridegroom is with them? As long as they have the bridegroom with them, they cannot fast. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 2,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Many are the plans in the mind of a man, but it is the purpose of the Lord that will stand. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 19,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>The end of all things is at hand; therefore be self-controlled and sober-minded for the sake of your prayers. Above all, keep loving one another earnestly, since love covers a multitude of sins. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 4,7.8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Come, everyone who thirsts, come to the waters; and he who has no money, come, buy and eat! Come, buy wine and milk without money and without price. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 55,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>but whoever drinks of the water that I will give him will never be thirsty again. The water that I will give him will become in him a spring of water welling up to eternal life.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 4,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For the Lord your God is God of gods and Lord of lords, the great, the mighty, and the awesome God, who is not partial and takes no bribe. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 10,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Blessed are the pure in heart, for they shall see God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Also henceforth I am he; there is none who can deliver from my hand; I work, and who can turn it back?” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 43,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For we must all appear before the judgment seat of Christ, so that each one may receive what is due for what he has done in the body, whether good or evil. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 5,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>6. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>what is man that you are mindful of him, and the son of man that you care for him? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 8,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For we are his workmanship, created in Christ Jesus for good works, which God prepared beforehand, that we should walk in them. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 2,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Listen to me, you stubborn of heart, you who are far from righteousness: I bring near my righteousness; it is not far off, and my salvation will not delay; I will put salvation in Zion, for Israel my glory.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 46,12.13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the grace of God has appeared, bringing salvation for all people, training us to renounce ungodliness and worldly passions, and to live self-controlled, upright, and godly lives in the present age, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Titus 2,11.12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>To the choirmaster: according to Muth-labben. A Psalm of David. I will give thanks to the Lord with my whole heart; I will recount all of your wonderful deeds. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 9,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>give thanks in all circumstances; for this is the will of God in Christ Jesus for you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>who does great things beyond searching out, and marvelous things beyond number. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 9,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said, “The kingdom of God is as if a man should scatter seed on the ground. He sleeps and rises night and day, and the seed sprouts and grows; he knows not how. The earth produces by itself, first the blade, then the ear, then the full grain in the ear. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 4,26.27.28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“You are my witnesses,” declares the Lord, “and my servant whom I have chosen, that you may know and believe me and understand that I am he. Before me no god was formed, nor shall there be any after me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 43,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said to them, “Go into all the world and proclaim the gospel to the whole creation. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 16,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>We have become like those over whom you have never ruled, like those who are not called by your name. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 63,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And lead us not into temptation, but deliver us from evil. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Whoever is steadfast in righteousness will live, but he who pursues evil will die. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 11,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Blessed are those who hunger and thirst for righteousness, for they shall be satisfied. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 5,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>7. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Whoever oppresses a poor man insults his Maker, but he who is generous to the needy honors him. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 14,31</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the King will answer them, ‘Truly, I say to you, as you did it to one of the least of these my brothers, you did it to me.’ </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 25,40</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For the Lord gives wisdom; from his mouth come knowledge and understanding; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 2,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>If any of you lacks wisdom, let him ask God, who gives generously to all without reproach, and it will be given him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 1,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then Samuel took a stone and set it up between Mizpah and Shen and called its name Ebenezer; for he said, “Till now the Lord has helped us.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 7,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>We are afflicted in every way, but not crushed; perplexed, but not driven to despair; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 4,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And he said, “Naked I came from my mother’s womb, and naked shall I return. The Lord gave, and the Lord has taken away; blessed be the name of the Lord.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 1,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for we brought nothing into the world, and we cannot take anything out of the world. But if we have food and clothing, with these we will be content. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 6,7.8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Be silent before the Lord God! For the day of the Lord is near; the Lord has prepared a sacrifice and consecrated his guests. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zephaniah 1,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said, “He who has ears to hear, let him hear.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 4,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-07-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“You shall not spread a false report. You shall not join hands with a wicked man to be a malicious witness. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 23,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do your best to present yourself to God as one approved, a worker who has no need to be ashamed, rightly handling the word of truth. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“For I know their works and their thoughts, and the time is coming to gather all nations and tongues. And they shall come and shall see my glory, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 66,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For there is no distinction between Jew and Greek; for the same Lord is Lord of all, bestowing his riches on all who call on him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 10,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>8. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Remember the days of old; consider the years of many generations; ask your father, and he will show you, your elders, and they will tell you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 32,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Follow the pattern of the sound words that you have heard from me, in the faith and love that are in Christ Jesus. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 1,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Toward the scorners he is scornful, but to the humble he gives favor. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 3,34</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do nothing from selfish ambition or conceit, but in humility count others more significant than yourselves. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>My foot stands on level ground; in the great assembly I will bless the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 26,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>What then, brothers? When you come together, each one has a hymn, a lesson, a revelation, a tongue, or an interpretation. Let all things be done for building up. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 14,26</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For a majority of the people, many of them from Ephraim, Manasseh, Issachar, and Zebulun, had not cleansed themselves, yet they ate the Passover otherwise than as prescribed. For Hezekiah had prayed for them, saying, “May the good Lord pardon everyone who sets his heart to seek God, the Lord, the God of his fathers, even though not according to the sanctuary’s rules of cleanness.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 30,18.19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And behold, there was a man named Zacchaeus. He was a chief tax collector and was rich. And he was seeking to see who Jesus was, but on account of the crowd he could not, because he was small in stature. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 19,2.3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He does not deal with us according to our sins, nor repay us according to our iniquities. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 103,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But we believe that we will be saved through the grace of the Lord Jesus, just as they will.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 15,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Cry out again, Thus says the Lord of hosts: My cities shall again overflow with prosperity, and the Lord will again comfort Zion and again choose Jerusalem.’” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 1,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He delivered us from such a deadly peril, and he will deliver us. On him we have set our hope that he will deliver us again. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>My eyes are ever toward the Lord, for he will pluck my feet out of the net. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 25,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Finally, brothers, pray for us, that the word of the Lord may speed ahead and be honored, as happened among you, and that we may be delivered from wicked and evil men. For not all have faith. But the Lord is faithful. He will establish you and guard you against the evil one. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 3,1.2.3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>9. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>They asked, and he brought quail, and gave them bread from heaven in abundance. He opened the rock, and water gushed out; it flowed through the desert like a river. For he remembered his holy promise, and Abraham, his servant. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 105,40.41.42</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Blessed be the God and Father of our Lord Jesus Christ, who has blessed us in Christ with every spiritual blessing in the heavenly places, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 1,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Gideon said to them, “I will not rule over you, and my son will not rule over you; the Lord will rule over you.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Judges 8,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For it is not the one who commends himself who is approved, but the one whom the Lord commends. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 10,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But the righteous shall be glad; they shall exult before God; they shall be jubilant with joy! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 68,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Rejoice in the Lord always; again I will say, rejoice. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Let your eyes be open to the plea of your servant and to the plea of your people Israel, giving ear to them whenever they call to you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Kings 8,52</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>If you ask me anything in my name, I will do it. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 14,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But he was pierced for our transgressions; he was crushed for our iniquities; upon him was the chastisement that brought us peace, and with his wounds we are healed. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 53,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He did not say this of his own accord, but being high priest that year he prophesied that Jesus would die for the nation, and not for the nation only, but also to gather into one the children of God who are scattered abroad. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 11,51.52</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Whom have I in heaven but you? And there is nothing on earth that I desire besides you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 73,25</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So Jesus said to the twelve, “Do you want to go away as well?” Simon Peter answered him, “Lord, to whom shall we go? You have the words of eternal life, and we have believed, and have come to know, that you are the Holy One of God.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 6,67.68.69</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>do not oppress the widow, the fatherless, the sojourner, or the poor, and let none of you devise evil against another in your heart.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 7,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>God chose what is low and despised in the world, even things that are not, to bring to nothing things that are, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 1,28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>10. Sonntag nach Trinitatis (Israelsonntag)</Sonntag><Losungstext>It is he who remembered us in our low estate, for his steadfast love endures forever; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 136,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Remember those who are in prison, as though in prison with them, and those who are mistreated, since you also are in the body. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Thus says the Lord of hosts: In those days ten men from the nations of every tongue shall take hold of the robe of a Jew, saying, ‘Let us go with you, for we have heard that God is with you.’” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 8,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And day by day, attending the temple together and breaking bread in their homes, they received their food with glad and generous hearts, praising God and having favor with all the people. And the Lord added to their number day by day those who were being saved. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 2,46.47</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For the Lord is good; his steadfast love endures forever, and his faithfulness to all generations. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 100,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But when the goodness and loving kindness of God our Savior appeared, he saved us, not because of works done by us in righteousness, but according to his own mercy, by the washing of regeneration and renewal of the Holy Spirit, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Titus 3,4.5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Now therefore, if I have found favor in your sight, please show me now your ways, that I may know you in order to find favor in your sight. Consider too that this nation is your people.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 33,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>To this he called you through our gospel, so that you may obtain the glory of our Lord Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 2,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Hatred stirs up strife, but love covers all offenses. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 10,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>By this all people will know that you are my disciples, if you have love for one another.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 13,35</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You are wearied with your many counsels; let them stand forth and save you, those who divide the heavens, who gaze at the stars, who at the new moons make known what shall come upon you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 47,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>At that time the disciples came to Jesus, saying, “Who is the greatest in the kingdom of heaven?” And calling to him a child, he put him in the midst of them and said, “Truly, I say to you, unless you turn and become like children, you will never enter the kingdom of heaven. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 18,1.2.3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The king answered and said to Daniel, “Truly, your God is God of gods and Lord of kings, and a revealer of mysteries, for you have been able to reveal this mystery.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 2,47</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>so that at the name of Jesus every knee should bow, in heaven and on earth and under the earth, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 2,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>11. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Trust in him at all times, O people; pour out your heart before him; God is a refuge for us. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 62,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And this is the confidence that we have toward him, that if we ask anything according to his will he hears us. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 John 5,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You prepare a table before me in the presence of my enemies; you anoint my head with oil; my cup overflows. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 23,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And while he was at Bethany in the house of Simon the leper, as he was reclining at table, a woman came with an alabaster flask of ointment of pure nard, very costly, and she broke the flask and poured it over his head. There were some who said to themselves indignantly, “Why was the ointment wasted like that? But Jesus said, “Leave her alone. Why do you trouble her? She has done a beautiful thing to me. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 14,3.4.6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And Hannah prayed and said, “My heart exults in the Lord; my horn is exalted in the Lord. My mouth derides my enemies, because I rejoice in your salvation. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 2,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And Mary said, “My soul magnifies the Lord, and my spirit rejoices in God my Savior, for he has looked on the humble estate of his servant. For behold, from now on all generations will call me blessed; </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,46.47.48</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You have not bought me sweet cane with money, or satisfied me with the fat of your sacrifices. But you have burdened me with your sins; you have wearied me with your iniquities. “I, I am he who blots out your transgressions for my own sake, and I will not remember your sins. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 43,24.25</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And you, who once were alienated and hostile in mind, doing evil deeds, he has now reconciled in his body of flesh by his death, in order to present you holy and blameless and above reproach before him, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,21.22</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>for it is the Lord our God who brought us and our fathers up from the land of Egypt, out of the house of slavery, and who did those great signs in our sight and preserved us in all the way that we went, and among all the peoples through whom we passed. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joshua 24,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>teaching them to observe all that I have commanded you. And behold, I am with you always, to the end of the age.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 28,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>A Psalm of David, when he was in the wilderness of Judah. O God, you are my God; earnestly I seek you; my soul thirsts for you; my flesh faints for you, as in a dry and weary land where there is no water. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 63,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>On the last day of the feast, the great day, Jesus stood up and cried out, “If anyone thirsts, let him come to me and drink. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 7,37</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>In those days Hezekiah became sick and was at the point of death, and he prayed to the Lord, and he answered him and gave him a sign. But Hezekiah did not make return according to the benefit done to him, for his heart was proud. Therefore wrath came upon him and Judah and Jerusalem. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 32,24.25</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Then one of them, when he saw that he was healed, turned back, praising God with a loud voice; and he fell on his face at Jesus’ feet, giving him thanks. Now he was a Samaritan. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 17,15.16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>12. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>And the effect of righteousness will be peace, and the result of righteousness, quietness and trust forever. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 32,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the kingdom of God is not a matter of eating and drinking but of righteousness and peace and joy in the Holy Spirit. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 14,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-08-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Know that the Lord, he is God! It is he who made us, and we are his; we are his people, and the sheep of his pasture. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 100,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>that they should seek God, and perhaps feel their way toward him and find him. Yet he is actually not far from each one of us, for “‘In him we live and move and have our being’; as even some of your own poets have said, “‘For we are indeed his offspring.’ </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 17,27.28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>In that day the root of Jesse, who shall stand as a signal for the peoples—of him shall the nations inquire, and his resting place shall be glorious. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 11,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And when he came up out of the water, immediately he saw the heavens being torn open and the Spirit descending on him like a dove. And a voice came from heaven, “You are my beloved Son; with you I am well pleased.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 1,10.11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Praise him, sun and moon, praise him, all you shining stars! Let them praise the name of the Lord! For he commanded and they were created. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 148,3.5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Worthy are you, our Lord and God, to receive glory and honor and power, for you created all things, and by your will they existed and were created.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 4,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Anxiety in a man’s heart weighs him down, but a good word makes him glad. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 12,25</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Be kind to one another, tenderhearted, forgiving one another, as God in Christ forgave you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 4,32</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord bless you and keep you; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Numbers 6,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For from his fullness we have all received, grace upon grace. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 1,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For you have been a stronghold to the poor, a stronghold to the needy in his distress, a shelter from the storm and a shade from the heat; for the breath of the ruthless is like a storm against a wall, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 25,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“And to the angel of the church in Smyrna write: ‘The words of the first and the last, who died and came to life. “I know your tribulation and your poverty (but you are rich) and the slander of those who say that they are Jews and are not, but are a synagogue of Satan. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 2,8.9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>13. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>The Lord will keep you from all evil; he will keep your life. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 121,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now may the God of peace himself sanctify you completely, and may your whole spirit and soul and body be kept blameless at the coming of our Lord Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 5,23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>great in counsel and mighty in deed, whose eyes are open to all the ways of the children of man, rewarding each one according to his ways and according to the fruit of his deeds. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 32,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For to this end we toil and strive, because we have our hope set on the living God, who is the Savior of all people, especially of those who believe. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 4,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And you shall know that I am the Lord, when I deal with you for my name’s sake, not according to your evil ways, nor according to your corrupt deeds, O house of Israel, declares the Lord God.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 20,44</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But love your enemies, and do good, and lend, expecting nothing in return, and your reward will be great, and you will be sons of the Most High, for he is kind to the ungrateful and the evil. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 6,35</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You are wearied with your many counsels; let them stand forth and save you, those who divide the heavens, who gaze at the stars, who at the new moons make known what shall come upon you. Behold, they are like stubble; the fire consumes them; they cannot deliver themselves from the power of the flame. No coal for warming oneself is this, no fire to sit before! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 47,13.14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not be led away by diverse and strange teachings, for it is good for the heart to be strengthened by grace, not by foods, which have not benefited those devoted to them. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I have set my bow in the cloud, and it shall be a sign of the covenant between me and the earth. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 9,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>so that by two unchangeable things, in which it is impossible for God to lie, we who have fled for refuge might have strong encouragement to hold fast to the hope set before us. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 6,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Hear my prayer, O Lord, and give ear to my cry; hold not your peace at my tears! For I am a sojourner with you, a guest, like all my fathers. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 39,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But she came and knelt before him, saying, “Lord, help me.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 15,25</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>A Psalm of David. The earth is the Lord’s and the fullness thereof, the world and those who dwell therein, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 24,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Look carefully then how you walk, not as unwise but as wise, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>14. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>‘Ah, Lord God! It is you who have made the heavens and the earth by your great power and by your outstretched arm! Nothing is too hard for you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 32,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And Jesus came and said to them, “All authority in heaven and on earth has been given to me. Go therefore and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and of the Son and of the Holy Spirit, teaching them to observe all that I have commanded you. And behold, I am with you always, to the end of the age.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 28,18.19.20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>you shall winnow them, and the wind shall carry them away, and the tempest shall scatter them. And you shall rejoice in the Lord; in the Holy One of Israel you shall glory. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 41,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>More than that, we also rejoice in God through our Lord Jesus Christ, through whom we have now received reconciliation. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 5,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>So Abram went, as the Lord had told him, and Lot went with him. Abram was seventy-five years old when he departed from Haran. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 12,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Know then that it is those of faith who are the sons of Abraham. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Galatians 3,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Honor the Lord with your wealth and with the firstfruits of all your produce; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 3,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But love your enemies, and do good, and lend, expecting nothing in return, and your reward will be great, and you will be sons of the Most High, for he is kind to the ungrateful and the evil. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 6,35</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For I, the Lord your God, hold your right hand; it is I who say to you, “Fear not, I am the one who helps you.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 41,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But when he saw the wind, he was afraid, and beginning to sink he cried out, “Lord, save me.” Jesus immediately reached out his hand and took hold of him, saying to him, “O you of little faith, why did you doubt?” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 14,30.31</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For I the Lord love justice; I hate robbery and wrong; I will faithfully give them their recompense, and I will make an everlasting covenant with them. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 61,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>that no one transgress and wrong his brother in this matter, because the Lord is an avenger in all these things, as we told you beforehand and solemnly warned you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Thessalonians 4,6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He is wise in heart and mighty in strength —who has hardened himself against him, and succeeded?— </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 9,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Live in harmony with one another. Do not be haughty, but associate with the lowly. Never be wise in your own sight. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 12,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>15. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>“Honor your father and your mother, that your days may be long in the land that the Lord your God is giving you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 20,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore welcome one another as Christ has welcomed you, for the glory of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 15,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You have caused my companions to shun me; you have made me a horror to them. I am shut in so that I cannot escape; my eye grows dim through sorrow. Every day I call upon you, O Lord; I spread out my hands to you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 88,8.9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I do not ask that you take them out of the world, but that you keep them from the evil one. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 17,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>How long must I take counsel in my soul and have sorrow in my heart all the day? How long shall my enemy be exalted over me? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 13,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I have said these things to you, that in me you may have peace. In the world you will have tribulation. But take heart; I have overcome the world.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 16,33</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He will swallow up death forever; and the Lord God will wipe away tears from all faces, and the reproach of his people he will take away from all the earth, for the Lord has spoken. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 25,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For while we are still in this tent, we groan, being burdened—not that we would be unclothed, but that we would be further clothed, so that what is mortal may be swallowed up by life. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 5,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“For from the least to the greatest of them, everyone is greedy for unjust gain; and from prophet to priest, everyone deals falsely. They have healed the wound of my people lightly, saying, ‘Peace, peace,’ when there is no peace. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 6,13.14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for each tree is known by its own fruit. For figs are not gathered from thornbushes, nor are grapes picked from a bramble bush. The good person out of the good treasure of his heart produces good, and the evil person out of his evil treasure produces evil, for out of the abundance of the heart his mouth speaks. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 6,44.45</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Great peace have those who love your law; nothing can make them stumble. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 119,165</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let the word of Christ dwell in you richly, teaching and admonishing one another in all wisdom, singing psalms and hymns and spiritual songs, with thankfulness in your hearts to God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 3,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For I am with you to save you, declares the Lord; I will make a full end of all the nations among whom I scattered you, but of you I will not make a full end. I will discipline you in just measure, and I will by no means leave you unpunished. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 30,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>At my first defense no one came to stand by me, but all deserted me. May it not be charged against them! But the Lord stood by me and strengthened me, so that through me the message might be fully proclaimed and all the Gentiles might hear it. So I was rescued from the lion’s mouth. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 4,16.17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>16. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>The Lord has made known his salvation; he has revealed his righteousness in the sight of the nations. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 98,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And when they arrived and gathered the church together, they declared all that God had done with them, and how he had opened a door of faith to the Gentiles. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 14,27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>In the beginning, God created the heavens and the earth. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Eclesiastes 12,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Philip found Nathanael and said to him, “We have found him of whom Moses in the Law and also the prophets wrote, Jesus of Nazareth, the son of Joseph.” Nathanael said to him, “Can anything good come out of Nazareth?” Philip said to him, “Come and see.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 1,45.46</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag>Michaelistag</Sonntag><Losungstext>“Thus says the Lord of hosts: The fast of the fourth month and the fast of the fifth and the fast of the seventh and the fast of the tenth shall be to the house of Judah seasons of joy and gladness and cheerful feasts. Therefore love truth and peace. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 8,19</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and you will know the truth, and the truth will set you free.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 8,32</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-09-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I believed, even when I spoke: “I am greatly afflicted”; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 116,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Blessed is the man who remains steadfast under trial, for when he has stood the test he will receive the crown of life, which God has promised to those who love him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 1,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>because your heart was tender and you humbled yourself before God when you heard his words against this place and its inhabitants, and you have humbled yourself before me and have torn your clothes and wept before me, I also have heard you, declares the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>2 Chronicles 34,27</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For I am the least of the apostles, unworthy to be called an apostle, because I persecuted the church of God. But by the grace of God I am what I am, and his grace toward me was not in vain. On the contrary, I worked harder than any of them, though it was not I, but the grace of God that is with me. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 15,9.10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I have seen his ways, but I will heal him; I will lead him and restore comfort to him and his mourners, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 57,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And when Jesus heard it, he said to them, “Those who are well have no need of a physician, but those who are sick. I came not to call the righteous, but sinners.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 2,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But there will be no gloom for her who was in anguish. In the former time he brought into contempt the land of Zebulun and the land of Naphtali, but in the latter time he has made glorious the way of the sea, the land beyond the Jordan, Galilee of the nations. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 9,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But you are a chosen race, a royal priesthood, a holy nation, a people for his own possession, that you may proclaim the excellencies of him who called you out of darkness into his marvelous light. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 2,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Erntedankfest</Sonntag><Losungstext>Trust in the Lord with all your heart, and do not lean on your own understanding. In all your ways acknowledge him, and he will make straight your paths. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 3,5.6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore, preparing your minds for action, and being sober-minded, set your hope fully on the grace that will be brought to you at the revelation of Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 1,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Moreover, he said to me, “Son of man, all my words that I shall speak to you receive in your heart, and hear with your ears. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 3,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore we must pay much closer attention to what we have heard, lest we drift away from it. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 2,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And I will not hide my face anymore from them, when I pour out my Spirit upon the house of Israel, declares the Lord God.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 39,29</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now there are varieties of gifts, but the same Spirit; and there are varieties of service, but the same Lord; and there are varieties of activities, but it is the same God who empowers them all in everyone. To each is given the manifestation of the Spirit for the common good. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 12,4.5.6.7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Have I any pleasure in the death of the wicked, declares the Lord God, and not rather that he should turn from his way and live? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Ezekiel 18,23</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>I have come into the world as light, so that whoever believes in me may not remain in darkness. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 12,46</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then Joshua said to the people, “You are witnesses against yourselves that you have chosen the Lord, to serve him.” And they said, “We are witnesses.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joshua 24,22</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let no one disqualify you, insisting on asceticism and worship of angels, going on in detail about visions, puffed up without reason by his sensuous mind, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 2,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But I said, “I have labored in vain; I have spent my strength for nothing and vanity; yet surely my right is with the Lord, and my recompense with my God.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 49,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore, my beloved brothers, be steadfast, immovable, always abounding in the work of the Lord, knowing that in the Lord your labor is not in vain. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 15,58</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For he spoke, and it came to be; he commanded, and it stood firm. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 33,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he awoke and rebuked the wind and said to the sea, “Peace! Be still!” And the wind ceased, and there was a great calm. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 4,39</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>18. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>The hearing ear and the seeing eye, the Lord has made them both. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 20,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But blessed are your eyes, for they see, and your ears, for they hear. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 13,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I say to the Lord, “You are my Lord; I have no good apart from you.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 16,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And this is eternal life, that they know you, the only true God, and Jesus Christ whom you have sent. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 17,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Then David said to Solomon his son, “Be strong and courageous and do it. Do not be afraid and do not be dismayed, for the Lord God, even my God, is with you. He will not leave you or forsake you, until all the work for the service of the house of the Lord is finished. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 28,20</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>This is how one should regard us, as servants of Christ and stewards of the mysteries of God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 4,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And there was evening and there was morning, the third day. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Eclesiastes 12,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So Peter opened his mouth and said: “Truly I understand that God shows no partiality, but in every nation anyone who fears him and does what is right is acceptable to him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 10,34.35</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>saying, ‘Turn now, every one of you, from his evil way and evil deeds, and dwell upon the land that the Lord has given to you and your fathers from of old and forever. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 25,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For I delight in the law of God, in my inner being, but I see in my members another law waging war against the law of my mind and making me captive to the law of sin that dwells in my members. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 7,22.23</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Behold, he who keeps Israel will neither slumber nor sleep. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 121,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>who will sustain you to the end, guiltless in the day of our Lord Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 1,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“And now, Israel, what does the Lord your God require of you, but to fear the Lord your God, to walk in all his ways, to love him, to serve the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 10,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But be doers of the word, and not hearers only, deceiving yourselves. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 1,22</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>19. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>And Samuel said, “Has the Lord as great delight in burnt offerings and sacrifices, as in obeying the voice of the Lord? Behold, to obey is better than sacrifice, and to listen than the fat of rams. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Samuel 15,22</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For your obedience is known to all, so that I rejoice over you, but I want you to be wise as to what is good and innocent as to what is evil. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 16,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>who executes justice for the oppressed, who gives food to the hungry. The Lord sets the prisoners free; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 146,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So if the Son sets you free, you will be free indeed. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 8,36</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And God said, “Let there be lights in the expanse of the heavens to separate the day from the night. And let them be for signs and for seasons, and for days and years, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Eclesiastes 7,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And we know that for those who love God all things work together for good, for those who are called according to his purpose. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And he lay down and slept under a broom tree. And behold, an angel touched him and said to him, “Arise and eat.” And he arose and ate and drank, and went in the strength of that food forty days and forty nights to Horeb, the mount of God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Kings 19,5.8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But we have this treasure in jars of clay, to show that the surpassing power belongs to God and not to us. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 4,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Behold, you have made my days a few handbreadths, and my lifetime is as nothing before you. Surely all mankind stands as a mere breath! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 39,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>and which now has been manifested through the appearing of our Savior Christ Jesus, who abolished death and brought life and immortality to light through the gospel, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 1,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Incline your ear, and come to me; hear, that your soul may live; and I will make with you an everlasting covenant, my steadfast, sure love for David. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 55,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now may the God of peace who brought again from the dead our Lord Jesus, the great shepherd of the sheep, by the blood of the eternal covenant, equip you with everything good that you may do his will, working in us that which is pleasing in his sight, through Jesus Christ, to whom be glory forever and ever. Amen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,20.21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the Lord stirred up the spirit of Zerubbabel the son of Shealtiel, governor of Judah, and the spirit of Joshua the son of Jehozadak, the high priest, and the spirit of all the remnant of the people. And they came and worked on the house of the Lord of hosts, their God, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Haggai 1,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not neglect the gift you have, which was given you by prophecy when the council of elders laid their hands on you. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 4,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>20. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>Then Amos answered and said to Amaziah, “I was no prophet, nor a prophet’s son, but I was a herdsman and a dresser of sycamore figs. But the Lord took me from following the flock, and the Lord said to me, ‘Go, prophesy to my people Israel.’ </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Amos 7,14.15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Passing alongside the Sea of Galilee, he saw Simon and Andrew the brother of Simon casting a net into the sea, for they were fishermen. And Jesus said to them, “Follow me, and I will make you become fishers of men.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 1,16.17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“I, I am he who comforts you; who are you that you are afraid of man who dies, of the son of man who is made like grass, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 51,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Little children, you are from God and have overcome them, for he who is in you is greater than he who is in the world. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 John 4,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Truly I know that it is so: But how can a man be in the right before God? If one wished to contend with him, one could not answer him once in a thousand times. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Job 9,2.3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the scribe said to him, “You are right, Teacher. You have truly said that he is one, and there is no other besides him. And to love him with all the heart and with all the understanding and with all the strength, and to love one’s neighbor as oneself, is much more than all whole burnt offerings and sacrifices.” And when Jesus saw that he answered wisely, he said to him, “You are not far from the kingdom of God.” And after that no one dared to ask him any more questions. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 12,32.33.34</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For who is God, but the Lord? And who is a rock, except our God?— </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 18,31</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For no one can lay a foundation other than that which is laid, which is Jesus Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Corinthians 3,11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You shall not add to the word that I command you, nor take from it, that you may keep the commandments of the Lord your God that I command you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 4,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Beloved, I am writing you no new commandment, but an old commandment that you had from the beginning. The old commandment is the word that you have heard. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 John 2,7</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Six days you shall work, but on the seventh day you shall rest. In plowing time and in harvest you shall rest. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Exodus 34,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Keep a close watch on yourself and on the teaching. Persist in this, for by so doing you will save both yourself and your hearers. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 4,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-10-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag>Reformationstag</Sonntag><Losungstext>But I will sing of your strength; I will sing aloud of your steadfast love in the morning. For you have been to me a fortress and a refuge in the day of my distress. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 59,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And rising very early in the morning, while it was still dark, he departed and went out to a desolate place, and there he prayed. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 1,35</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>21. Sonntag nach Trinitatis</Sonntag><Losungstext>For it is you who light my lamp; the Lord my God lightens my darkness. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 18,28</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And Jesus said to him, “What do you want me to do for you?” And the blind man said to him, “Rabbi, let me recover my sight.” And Jesus said to him, “Go your way; your faith has made you well.” And immediately he recovered his sight and followed him on the way. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 10,51.52</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>They have all turned aside; together they have become corrupt; there is none who does good, not even one. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 14,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>the righteousness of God through faith in Jesus Christ for all who believe. For there is no distinction: for all have sinned and fall short of the glory of God, and are justified by his grace as a gift, through the redemption that is in Christ Jesus, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 3,22.23.24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“Rejoice with Jerusalem, and be glad for her, all you who love her; rejoice with her in joy, all you who mourn over her; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 66,10</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And coming up at that very hour she began to give thanks to God and to speak of him to all who were waiting for the redemption of Jerusalem. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,38</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Sing aloud, O daughter of Zion; shout, O Israel! Rejoice and exult with all your heart, O daughter of Jerusalem! The Lord has taken away the judgments against you; he has cleared away your enemies. The King of Israel, the Lord, is in your midst; you shall never again fear evil. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zephaniah 3,14.15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He is the propitiation for our sins, and not for ours only but also for the sins of the whole world. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 John 2,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Not one word of all the good promises that the Lord had made to the house of Israel had failed; all came to pass. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joshua 21,45</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now you, brothers, like Isaac, are children of promise. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Galatians 4,28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>that people may know, from the rising of the sun and from the west, that there is none besides me; I am the Lord, and there is no other. I form light and create darkness; I make well-being and create calamity; I am the Lord, who does all these things. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 45,6.7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>May the Lord direct your hearts to the love of God and to the steadfastness of Christ. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Thessalonians 3,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Those who pay regard to vain idols forsake their hope of steadfast love. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jonah 2,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>so that you may not be sluggish, but imitators of those who through faith and patience inherit the promises. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 6,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Drittletzter Sonntag des Kirchenjahres</Sonntag><Losungstext>He is not greater in this house than I am, nor has he kept back anything from me except you, because you are his wife. How then can I do this great wickedness and sin against God?” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 39,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>You then, my child, be strengthened by the grace that is in Christ Jesus, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,1</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I was ready to be sought by those who did not ask for me; I was ready to be found by those who did not seek me. I said, “Here I am, here I am,” to a nation that was not called by my name. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 65,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For we hold that one is justified by faith apart from works of the law. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 3,28</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Turn to me and be gracious to me; give your strength to your servant, and save the son of your maidservant. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 86,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And my God will supply every need of yours according to his riches in glory in Christ Jesus. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Philippians 4,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Better is a little with the fear of the Lord than great treasure and trouble with it. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Proverbs 15,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For what does it profit a man to gain the whole world and forfeit his soul? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 8,36</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But we your people, the sheep of your pasture, will give thanks to you forever; from generation to generation we will recount your praise. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 79,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Through him then let us continually offer up a sacrifice of praise to God, that is, the fruit of lips that acknowledge his name. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For I will pour water on the thirsty land, and streams on the dry ground; I will pour my Spirit upon your offspring, and my blessing on your descendants. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 44,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For the promise is for you and for your children and for all who are far off, everyone whom the Lord our God calls to himself.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 2,39</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>How great are your works, O Lord! Your thoughts are very deep! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 92,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>which he will display at the proper time—he who is the blessed and only Sovereign, the King of kings and Lord of lords, who alone has immortality, who dwells in unapproachable light, whom no one has ever seen or can see. To him be honor and eternal dominion. Amen. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 6,15.16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Vorletzter Sonntag des Kirchenjahres</Sonntag><Losungstext>He has told you, O man, what is good; and what does the Lord require of you but to do justice, and to love kindness, and to walk humbly with your God? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Micah 6,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So flee youthful passions and pursue righteousness, faith, love, and peace, along with those who call on the Lord from a pure heart. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 2,22</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You shall not take vengeance or bear a grudge against the sons of your own people, but you shall love your neighbor as yourself: I am the Lord. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Leviticus 19,18</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Let brotherly love continue. Do not neglect to show hospitality to strangers, for thereby some have entertained angels unawares. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,1.2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“For my name’s sake I defer my anger; for the sake of my praise I restrain it for you, that I may not cut you off. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 48,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>who saved us and called us to a holy calling, not because of our works but because of his own purpose and grace, which he gave us in Christ Jesus before the ages began, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Timothy 1,9</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag>Buss- und Bettag</Sonntag><Losungstext>O Lord our God, other lords besides you have ruled over us, but your name alone we bring to remembrance. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 26,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But Peter and the apostles answered, “We must obey God rather than men. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Acts 5,29</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Oh, taste and see that the Lord is good! Blessed is the man who takes refuge in him! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 34,8</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And at the time for the banquet he sent his servant to say to those who had been invited, ‘Come, for everything is now ready.’ </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 14,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He changes times and seasons; he removes kings and sets up kings; he gives wisdom to the wise and knowledge to those who have understanding; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 2,21</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And they sing the song of Moses, the servant of God, and the song of the Lamb, saying, “Great and amazing are your deeds, O Lord God the Almighty! Just and true are your ways, O King of the nations! Who will not fear, O Lord, and glorify your name? For you alone are holy. All nations will come and worship you, for your righteous acts have been revealed.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 15,3.4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Because your steadfast love is better than life, my lips will praise you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 63,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>So we have come to know and to believe the love that God has for us. God is love, and whoever abides in love abides in God, and God abides in him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 John 4,16</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>Letzter Sonntag des Kirchenjahres – Ewigkeitssonntag</Sonntag><Losungstext>I, I am the Lord, and besides me there is no savior. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 43,11</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>one Lord, one faith, one baptism, one God and Father of all, who is over all and through all and in all. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 4,5.6</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For thus says the One who is high and lifted up, who inhabits eternity, whose name is Holy: “I dwell in the high and holy place, and also with him who is of a contrite and lowly spirit, to revive the spirit of the lowly, and to revive the heart of the contrite. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 57,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>When he went ashore he saw a great crowd, and he had compassion on them, because they were like sheep without a shepherd. And he began to teach them many things. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 6,34</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He has remembered his steadfast love and faithfulness to the house of Israel. All the ends of the earth have seen the salvation of our God. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 98,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And he said to them, “Is a lamp brought in to be put under a basket, or under a bed, and not on a stand? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 4,21</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>who drink wine in bowls and anoint themselves with the finest oils, but are not grieved over the ruin of Joseph! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Amos 6,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>As for the rich in this present age, charge them not to be haughty, nor to set their hopes on the uncertainty of riches, but on God, who richly provides us with everything to enjoy. They are to do good, to be rich in good works, to be generous and ready to share, thus storing up treasure for themselves as a good foundation for the future, so that they may take hold of that which is truly life. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Timothy 6,17.18.19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And now we thank you, our God, and praise your glorious name. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Chronicles 29,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>giving thanks always and for everything to God the Father in the name of our Lord Jesus Christ, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 5,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>O Lord, all my longing is before you; my sighing is not hidden from you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 38,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>for you know that the testing of your faith produces steadfastness. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 1,3</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>As one whom his mother comforts, so I will comfort you; you shall be comforted in Jerusalem. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 66,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“I will not leave you as orphans; I will come to you. Yet a little while and the world will see me no more, but you will see me. Because I live, you also will live. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 14,18.19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>1. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag><Losungstext>May the Lord give you increase, you and your children! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 115,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And his mercy is for those who fear him from generation to generation. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,50</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-11-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the Lord will inherit Judah as his portion in the holy land, and will again choose Jerusalem.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Zechariah 2,12</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Who shall bring any charge against God’s elect? It is God who justifies. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,33</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-0100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Sojourn in this land, and I will be with you and will bless you, for to you and to your offspring I will give all these lands, and I will establish the oath that I swore to Abraham your father. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Genesis 26,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And if you call on him as Father who judges impartially according to each one’s deeds, conduct yourselves with fear throughout the time of your exile, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 Peter 1,17</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-0200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>To the choirmaster. Of David. In the Lord I take refuge; how can you say to my soul, “Flee like a bird to your mountain, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 11,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Peace I leave with you; my peace I give to you. Not as the world gives do I give to you. Let not your hearts be troubled, neither let them be afraid. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 14,27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-0300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Every man shall give as he is able, according to the blessing of the Lord your God that he has given you. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 16,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>For if the readiness is there, it is acceptable according to what a person has, not according to what he does not have. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 8,12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-0400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>It is in vain that you rise up early and go late to rest, eating the bread of anxious toil; for he gives to his beloved sleep. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 127,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Do not be like them, for your Father knows what you need before you ask him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-0500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Father of the fatherless and protector of widows is God in his holy habitation. God settles the solitary in a home; he leads out the prisoners to prosperity, but the rebellious dwell in a parched land. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 68,5.6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>That evening at sundown they brought to him all who were sick or oppressed by demons. And the whole city was gathered together at the door. And he healed many who were sick with various diseases, and cast out many demons. And he would not permit the demons to speak, because they knew him. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 1,32.33.34</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-0600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>2. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag><Losungstext>It has seemed good to me to show the signs and wonders that the Most High God has done for me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 4,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>the life was made manifest, and we have seen it, and testify to it and proclaim to you the eternal life, which was with the Father and was made manifest to us— </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 John 1,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-0700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And those who are wise shall shine like the brightness of the sky above; and those who turn many to righteousness, like the stars forever and ever. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 12,3</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Therefore, we are ambassadors for Christ, God making his appeal through us. We implore you on behalf of Christ, be reconciled to God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 5,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-0800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Blow a trumpet in Zion; sound an alarm on my holy mountain! Let all the inhabitants of the land tremble, for the day of the Lord is coming; it is near, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Joel 2,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>But according to his promise we are waiting for new heavens and a new earth in which righteousness dwells. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Peter 3,13</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-0900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>For the Lord your God is bringing you into a good land, a land of brooks of water, of fountains and springs, flowing out in the valleys and hills, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Deuteronomy 8,7</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He who did not spare his own Son but gave him up for us all, how will he not also with him graciously give us all things? </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Romans 8,32</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-1000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the glory of the Lord shall be revealed, and all flesh shall see it together, for the mouth of the Lord has spoken.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 40,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the Word became flesh and dwelt among us, and we have seen his glory, glory as of the only Son from the Father, full of grace and truth. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 1,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-1100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>He delivers and rescues; he works signs and wonders in heaven and on earth, he who has saved Daniel from the power of the lions.” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Daniel 6,27</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Jesus Christ is the same yesterday and today and forever. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Hebrews 13,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-1200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>As for me, I said, “O Lord, be gracious to me; heal me, for I have sinned against you!” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 41,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the prayer of faith will save the one who is sick, and the Lord will raise him up. And if he has committed sins, he will be forgiven. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>James 5,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-1300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>3. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag><Losungstext>There is none like you, O Lord; you are great, and your name is great in might. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 10,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And we have seen and testify that the Father has sent his Son to be the Savior of the world. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 John 4,14</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-1400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>My soul yearns for you in the night; my spirit within me earnestly seeks you. For when your judgments are in the earth, the inhabitants of the world learn righteousness. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 26,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He who supplies seed to the sower and bread for food will supply and multiply your seed for sowing and increase the harvest of your righteousness. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 9,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-1500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>you have kept with your servant David my father what you declared to him. You spoke with your mouth, and with your hand have fulfilled it this day. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>1 Kings 8,24</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Blessed be the Lord God of Israel, for he has visited and redeemed his people and has raised up a horn of salvation for us in the house of his servant David, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 1,68.69</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-1600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>You are the God who works wonders; you have made known your might among the peoples. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 77,14</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>the mystery hidden for ages and generations but now revealed to his saints. To them God chose to make known how great among the Gentiles are the riches of the glory of this mystery, which is Christ in you, the hope of glory. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Colossians 1,26.27</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-1700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>There is hope for your future, declares the Lord, and your children shall come back to their own country. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 31,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Behold, I stand at the door and knock. If anyone hears my voice and opens the door, I will come in to him and eat with him, and he with me. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 3,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-1800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Hear the word of the Lord, O children of Israel, for the Lord has a controversy with the inhabitants of the land. There is no faithfulness or steadfast love, and no knowledge of God in the land; </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Hosea 4,1</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“Repent, for the kingdom of heaven is at hand.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 3,2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-1900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>Your eyes saw my unformed substance; in your book were written, every one of them, the days that were formed for me, when as yet there was none of them. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 139,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Nevertheless, do not rejoice in this, that the spirits are subject to you, but rejoice that your names are written in heaven.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 10,20</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-2000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>4. Sonntag im Advent</Sonntag><Losungstext>But may all who seek you rejoice and be glad in you; may those who love your salvation say continually, “Great is the Lord!” </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 40,16</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>he predestined us for adoption to himself as sons through Jesus Christ, according to the purpose of his will, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Ephesians 1,5</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-2100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>And the Lord said: “Because this people draw near with their mouth and honor me with their lips, while their hearts are far from me, and their fear of me is a commandment taught by men, </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 29,13</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Little children, let us not love in word or talk but in deed and in truth. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>1 John 3,18</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-2200:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>but you are the same, and your years have no end. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 102,27</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>“I am the Alpha and the Omega,” says the Lord God, “who is and who was and who is to come, the Almighty.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Revelation 1,8</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-2300:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>I lay down and slept; I woke again, for the Lord sustained me. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 3,5</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Truly, I say to you, whoever does not receive the kingdom of God like a child shall not enter it.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Mark 10,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-2400:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag>Heiliger Abend</Sonntag><Losungstext>My soul thirsts for God, for the living God. When shall I come and appear before God? </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 42,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Now after Jesus was born in Bethlehem of Judea in the days of Herod the king, behold, wise men from the east came to Jerusalem, saying, “Where is he who has been born king of the Jews? For we saw his star when it rose and have come to worship him.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 2,1.2</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-2500:00:00</Datum><Wtag>6</Wtag><Sonntag>Weihnachtsfest</Sonntag><Losungstext>Blessed are the people to whom such blessings fall! Blessed are the people whose God is the Lord! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 144,15</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And the angel said to them, “Fear not, for behold, I bring you good news of great joy that will be for all the people. For unto you is born this day in the city of David a Savior, who is Christ the Lord. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,10.11</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-2600:00:00</Datum><Wtag>7</Wtag><Sonntag>2. Weihnachtstag</Sonntag><Losungstext>Behold, I will bring to it health and healing, and I will heal them and reveal to them abundance of prosperity and security. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Jeremiah 33,6</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>When the angels went away from them into heaven, the shepherds said to one another, “Let us go over to Bethlehem and see this thing that has happened, which the Lord has made known to us.” </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Luke 2,15</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-2700:00:00</Datum><Wtag>1</Wtag><Sonntag>1. Sonntag nach Weihnachten</Sonntag><Losungstext>Blessed is the man who makes the Lord his trust, who does not turn to the proud, to those who go astray after a lie! </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 40,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>And we have the prophetic word more fully confirmed, to which you will do well to pay attention as to a lamp shining in a dark place, until the day dawns and the morning star rises in your hearts, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Peter 1,19</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-2800:00:00</Datum><Wtag>2</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>The Lord God has given me the tongue of those who are taught, that I may know how to sustain with a word him who is weary. Morning by morning he awakens; he awakens my ear to hear as those who are taught. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 50,4</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>who comforts us in all our affliction, so that we may be able to comfort those who are in any affliction, with the comfort with which we ourselves are comforted by God. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>2 Corinthians 1,4</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-2900:00:00</Datum><Wtag>3</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>But for you who fear my name, the sun of righteousness shall rise with healing in its wings. You shall go out leaping like calves from the stall. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Malachi 4,2</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>He came to his own, and his own people did not receive him. But to all who did receive him, who believed in his name, he gave the right to become children of God, </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 1,11.12</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-3000:00:00</Datum><Wtag>4</Wtag><Sonntag/><Losungstext>“For behold, I create new heavens and a new earth, and the former things shall not be remembered or come into mind. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Isaiah 65,17</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Your kingdom come, your will be done, on earth as it is in heaven. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>Matthew 6,10</Lehrtextvers></Losungen><Losungen><Datum>2020-12-3100:00:00</Datum><Wtag>5</Wtag><Sonntag>Altjahresabend</Sonntag><Losungstext>The Lord has heard my plea; the Lord accepts my prayer. </Losungstext><Losungsvers>Psalms 6,9</Losungsvers><Lehrtext>Until now you have asked nothing in my name. Ask, and you will receive, that your joy may be full. </Lehrtext><Lehrtextvers>John 16,24</Lehrtextvers></Losungen></FreeXml>